<?xml version="1.0"?>
<ArrayOfCountry xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Country>
    <Id>1</Id>
    <UniqueId>aab7340d-d349-4be8-958e-8d3c4a0d04d9</UniqueId>
    <CountryPageUniqueId>ed2de5be-ecee-46b0-9356-41ef6ba4c26d</CountryPageUniqueId>
    <CountryName>Australia</CountryName>
    <Text>Our Australian operations in Sydney and Perth are fully integrated into Allen &amp;amp; Overy's global network. The offices offer a full suite of corporate and finance (debt and equity) services. Our team includes partners and lawyers who are proficient in numerous languages including Mandarin, Japanese, Indonesian, German, French and Spanish. 
Allen &amp;amp; Overy Australia offers the best of both worlds: the expertise and resources of a global elite law practice coupled with a leading group of senior domestic practitioners. With ease, we are able to provide our clients with innovative and cost effective legal solutions around the clock.
Since our arrival, Allen &amp;amp; Overy has quickly established a track record of executing both complex, unique and strategic cross-border and domestic transactions. 
As a global elite practice, Allen &amp;amp; Overy is at the cutting edge of international legal and commercial insights. Our teams are often advising on market developments and 'firsts' around the world. In addition to this first-hand experience, we have established a 'Global Intelligence Unit' to track trends and emerging legal and commercial issues and analyse what they mean for our clients.
We are committed to offering our clients in the Australian market the expertise of our international knowledge platform and impressive global office network.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>ac8e0e83-ca74-4368-a13b-c3ac21608c19</TermStoreId>
  </Country>
  <Country>
    <Id>2</Id>
    <UniqueId>21725ff9-c315-42de-8b65-5cf86aeb3d8d</UniqueId>
    <CountryPageUniqueId>a75fca7f-d958-414f-8d49-e3dce1bf7868</CountryPageUniqueId>
    <CountryName>Belgium</CountryName>
    <Text>Having been in the market for more than 30 years, our Belgian clients appreciate our natural understanding of their industry and background. International clients come to us for our knowledge of the 'ins and outs' of doing business in Belgium. 
The majority of our work is complex, large scale, urgent and international in nature. Unlike the majority of law firms in Belgium we provide clients with a full service covering: corporate, M&amp;amp;A, finance, litigation, commercial contracts, employment and benefits, intellectual property, IT, outsourcing, real estate, tax, environment, EU and competition and public law, and are consistently ranked first tier across most of these areas. This means our clients receive relevant, commercial advice with all perspectives integrated, without the need to piece together a jigsaw puzzle of input from different law firms.
Clients benefit from our seamless integration across legal practice areas and into Allen &amp;amp; Overy's international network, ensuring the sharing of knowledge, information, technology systems, processes and skills.
Recognition for our work
Allen &amp;amp; Overy's Belgian Tax practice received the Belgium Tax Firm of the Year award at the International Tax Review European Awards 2013
 Allen &amp;amp; Overy named &amp;quot;Benelux Law Firm of the Year&amp;quot; at international M&amp;amp;A awards for the fifth time (FT and Mergermarket 2012)
&amp;quot;Allen &amp;amp; Overy comes recommended for its depth of practice, vast expertise and excellent insights at both a national and international level.&amp;quot; Chambers Europe 2011 (Belgium)
&amp;quot;The overall level of legal services at Allen &amp;amp; Overy LLP is 'excellent'.&amp;quot; Legal 500 2011 (Belgium)
Find out more about Allen &amp;amp; Overy's global expertise. 
Our offices 
Antwerp
Brussels</Text>
    <TermStoreId>4594549a-cedc-4930-b0e8-7872b7e53883</TermStoreId>
  </Country>
  <Country>
    <Id>3</Id>
    <UniqueId>8face95d-4dbe-431b-a1bc-71814680b53b</UniqueId>
    <CountryPageUniqueId>0c53d9e8-9cd8-4319-aad0-4ed88992b414</CountryPageUniqueId>
    <CountryName>Brazil</CountryName>
    <Text>Our São Paulo office reflects Allen &amp;amp; Overy's long-term investment in Brazil and the broader Latin American region.  
Our local presence is a natural outgrowth of our decades of participation in Brazil and Latin America-related transactions from our offices around the world.
Our dedicated São Paulo team combines our strength in corporate finance with cultural familiarity and language skills to provide clients with highly effective service on Brazilian and Latin American transactions. Our experience in market-leading transactions, together with our long-standing working relationships with the country’s best local law firms, give us and our clients excellent access to current legal developments and local market intelligence.
With a large number of transactions in Brazil involving cross-border elements, our São Paulo office is also supported by additional Portuguese speaking project finance, capital markets, trade finance, general banking and corporate lawyers located in our New York, London and Tokyo offices. Although we (and all other international firms with offices in Brazil) are not permitted by the Brazilian bar to practice Brazilian law, we understand the Brazilian market, legal environment and risks, and are well seasoned in advising foreign investors in doing deals and transacting in Brazil.
Find out more about Allen &amp;amp; Overy's global expertise.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>ef55ec23-c356-4149-9f75-74ba8e923afc</TermStoreId>
  </Country>
  <Country>
    <Id>4</Id>
    <UniqueId>687bc117-41e7-4619-832c-ff1e96a535b3</UniqueId>
    <CountryPageUniqueId>5e207c58-4949-42bf-bc79-42d58e999042</CountryPageUniqueId>
    <CountryName>China and Hong Kong</CountryName>
    <Text>We have one of the most experienced China law practices in the region with the ability to advise on Hong Kong, UK and U.S. law. We have been in China for over 20 years and were one of the first international law firms to obtain official approval from the People's Republic of China (PRC) Ministry of Justice to register an office in Beijing in 1993. 
Our full service practices in Beijing, Hong Kong and Shanghai, cover cross-border, multidisciplinary deals such as anti-trust, dispute resolution, distribution arrangements, financing, foreign direct investment, intellectual property, international capital markets, licensing, mergers and acquisitions, outbound investment, project finance, real estate, regulatory services, technology and telecommunications transactions.
We have around 180 lawyers and consultants in the region and we continue to look for opportunities for further growth, always considering where our clients may want to turn to us for international and local advice. This is why, during 2010, we opened offices in Sydney and Perth in Australia and entered into an exclusive association with Ginting &amp;amp; Reksodiputro in Indonesia. A large number of our lawyers are native speakers of, or proficient in, Mandarin and Cantonese. 
We have good working relationships with a number of major local law firms in the PRC and as such are able to provide a seamless and full range of legal services to our clients.
Find out more about Allen &amp;amp; Overy's global expertise.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>d6a164f6-c10e-4fc9-a910-8a910405cedf</TermStoreId>
  </Country>
  <Country>
    <Id>5</Id>
    <UniqueId>b3abd515-f5f0-4873-a5ac-d41d5b33c9ed</UniqueId>
    <CountryPageUniqueId>3a8bcba0-9e4b-4e89-b825-5fa5c4ec26c7</CountryPageUniqueId>
    <CountryName>Czech Republic</CountryName>
    <Text>Our strength is our lawyers’ combined international experience and in-depth knowledge of the Czech legal and regulatory environment.
Most of our lawyers are Czech and many of them have completed postgraduate studies in the U.S., the UK and Germany, and have spent time working in our international offices, in particular London. To reinforce this breadth and depth of experience, all of our lawyers, including our three partners, take part in regional and international training with colleagues from across the Allen &amp;amp; Overy global network.
The integration of the Prague office into the international network of Allen &amp;amp; Overy offices ensures a comprehensive sharing of knowledge, processes, skills and information technology systems.
Our clients enjoy the advantage of working with a truly global firm which seamlessly combines both local and international expertise.
Recognition for our work 
Allen &amp;amp; Overy is the ‘top firm in Prague’ for banking, finance and capital markets work, and is ‘excellent on all counts’. The Legal 500 2012 
Allen &amp;amp; Overy has a very strong offering in corporate and M&amp;amp;A work, with notable expertise in energy and private equity deals. The firm is a leading regional player, working closely with its offices across CEE. &amp;quot;Sources say: ‘A very professional and highly responsive team that really knows its stuff’.&amp;quot; Chambers Europe 2012
Legal Adviser of the Year in Central and Eastern Europe. The Financial Times and The Mergermarket Group European M&amp;amp;A Awards 2010
 
Find out more about Allen &amp;amp; Overy's global expertise.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>37da1ffa-0be0-4f6c-a8dd-db8e99830989</TermStoreId>
  </Country>
  <Country>
    <Id>6</Id>
    <UniqueId>d1f5bd8b-465e-4496-896a-4e76667fac7a</UniqueId>
    <CountryPageUniqueId>3169c030-f526-41c8-a7b3-13e59c08545a</CountryPageUniqueId>
    <CountryName>France</CountryName>
    <Text>Founded in 1989 and fully established since 1998, Allen &amp;amp; Overy Paris today boasts more than 150 lawyers including 37 partners.
Our continuing growth is based on the talent and proven experience of our staff combined with our technical expertise and pragmatic approach to each case, which is the result of in-depth knowledge of our clients market and business sector. 
As well as being global advisors in business and finance law, we have become a strategic and preferred partner to our clients. We support them in day-to-day matters and contribute to the high points of their development, be they large businesses in France or abroad, innovative or developing companies, banking and financial institutions, stock market businesses, or public institutions.
It is our vocation to understand, advise, and support our clients wherever they operate.
Find out more about Allen &amp;amp; Overy's global expertise.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>2d2c6ba4-0862-4ec9-844c-b8b37b1822b4</TermStoreId>
  </Country>
  <Country>
    <Id>7</Id>
    <UniqueId>c7aeb174-cff6-4242-a6d2-4c16ae740775</UniqueId>
    <CountryPageUniqueId />
    <CountryName>Germany</CountryName>
    <Text />
    <TermStoreId>224ffec0-8344-4706-9660-3d9cc4441001</TermStoreId>
  </Country>
  <Country>
    <Id>8</Id>
    <UniqueId>85ddd266-e232-4644-8289-5fe6fcb0ff29</UniqueId>
    <CountryPageUniqueId>6705d167-9bee-4f79-8ecc-760e93acffce</CountryPageUniqueId>
    <CountryName>Greece</CountryName>
    <Text>To support our practice in Greece, we have opened a small representative office in Athens. The Athens office is not a full service office. It does not practise Greek law and there is a very limited presence of Allen &amp;amp; Overy lawyers on the ground.
It has been set up only to support visiting teams of Allen &amp;amp; Overy lawyers working on Greek transactions when in Athens; clients who require advice and assistance in connection with matters involving Greece or Greek counterparties should therefore continue to address themselves to their usual Allen &amp;amp; Overy contact or to partner Yannis Manuelides who is based in London and is in charge of the overall Greek practice at Allen &amp;amp; Overy.
Find out more about Allen &amp;amp; Overy's global expertise.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>1607b066-57fc-4496-abf8-f845d49febc2</TermStoreId>
  </Country>
  <Country>
    <Id>9</Id>
    <UniqueId>dee9fe74-acba-4ec7-9ff5-71c7d95e97c5</UniqueId>
    <CountryPageUniqueId>090fd244-6bfc-445f-be8e-2664cd4d5081</CountryPageUniqueId>
    <CountryName>Hungary</CountryName>
    <Text>Since 1993, Morley Allen &amp;amp; Overy Iroda has established itself as one of the premier practices in Hungary, with a formidable group of experienced lawyers particularly suited to corporate and finance work. 
Many of our lawyers have completed post-graduate studies in Hungary, as well as the US, UK and the Netherlands.
Our office in Budapest consists of 25 lawyers including two resident partners. With 15 support staff we are well prepared to collaborate on cross-border projects and co-operate with local counsel from other leading legal practices or Allen &amp;amp; Overy offices in other jurisdictions. 
As part of the Central and East European practice, we can also call on the expertise of Allen &amp;amp; Overy lawyers in the Czech Republic, Poland , Romania, Slovakia and Russia. The CEE region is a key market for us and, unlike many other law firms, we remain committed to maintaining a long-term presence in Hungary.
Find out more about Allen &amp;amp; Overy's global expertise.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>7746f39f-d63a-441b-b26a-4941e99a78c0</TermStoreId>
  </Country>
  <Country>
    <Id>10</Id>
    <UniqueId>430ada7e-9919-40e2-bca5-d21cc5c3ee63</UniqueId>
    <CountryPageUniqueId />
    <CountryName>India</CountryName>
    <Text />
    <TermStoreId>d70636c6-fe95-43a6-bd4d-ba4f87c5f659</TermStoreId>
  </Country>
  <Country>
    <Id>11</Id>
    <UniqueId>0d5a5278-bc38-4989-83a8-174427d0960b</UniqueId>
    <CountryPageUniqueId>16a98437-74c2-448c-abdf-343c6dd29dfb</CountryPageUniqueId>
    <CountryName>Indonesia</CountryName>
    <Text>Indonesia is one of the most important emerging markets in Asia and Allen &amp;amp; Overy have been active there for many years, representing financial institutions, corporates and the Republic of Indonesia on a wide range of transactions. 
In 2010, we strengthened our Indonesian offering by entering into an exclusive association agreement with Ginting &amp;amp; Reksodiputro (G&amp;amp;R), based in Jakarta. G&amp;amp;R is a top tier Indonesia law practice and their lawyers provide first class Indonesian legal advice and are well established leaders in the local market. 
We are delighted to work with Daniel Ginting, Harun Reksodiputro and their team, who offer an exceptional service.  This coupled with our own Indonesian expertise means we now provide a high quality 'one stop shop' on Indonesian transactions – an ability to give outstanding local and international advice as well as an integrated full service. This is what clients have come to expect from Allen &amp;amp; Overy across the world.
The main strengths of our practice in Indonesia include: 
banking and finance
projects
corporate
capital markets
Find out more about Allen &amp;amp; Overy's global expertise.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>0e9447ed-64cb-496e-a302-5cda4ac99210</TermStoreId>
  </Country>
  <Country>
    <Id>12</Id>
    <UniqueId>4de7907e-3d2c-4117-9da0-b86636d4819a</UniqueId>
    <CountryPageUniqueId>fba94fc5-313b-4afa-b1d7-4677eb5ca3eb</CountryPageUniqueId>
    <CountryName>Italy</CountryName>
    <Text>Over 20 years, Allen &amp;amp; Overy has evolved as one of Italy’s premier legal practices. Based in Milan and Rome, our lawyers have an in-depth knowledge of the local market and can draw on the resources and skills of an integrated worldwide network. 
We offer domestic and cross-border legal services to the world’s leading corporations and financial institutions. Our clients have quick and easy access to the full range of our expertise in the areas of administrative law, antitrust, banking, corporate/M&amp;amp;A, debt and equity capital markets, employment, energy, infrastructure, litigation and arbitration, intellectual property, project finance, real estate, restructuring and tax. 
Our lawyers in Italy, many of whom are qualified to practise in multiple jurisdictions (including England and New York), work closely with our international network of offices. In this way we are able to offer our clients the support and advice needed to succeed in the changing national and global markets. 
Find out more about Allen &amp;amp; Overy's global expertise.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>aaa07865-3e85-4cec-bc29-506f1c692954</TermStoreId>
  </Country>
  <Country>
    <Id>13</Id>
    <UniqueId>f13ae7da-336b-4829-bcea-3631b2bbaef1</UniqueId>
    <CountryPageUniqueId>f246db16-d72a-46c0-b7b9-5ae4813059dd</CountryPageUniqueId>
    <CountryName>Japan</CountryName>
    <Text>Since entering Japan in 1988, we have earned a reputation for providing innovative and high quality advice, steering complex transactions to a successful conclusion.
Our office covers the full gamut of corporate work, including mergers and acquisitions, investments and joint ventures. Our projects and banking practice is recognized as one of the leading practices in the country. We are active across all sectors and have particular experience in the oil &amp;amp; gas, power, infrastructure, petrochemicals, life sciences, food &amp;amp; beverage and real estate sectors.
Our team offers both international and Japanese law capability. We are often the first port of call for domestic and foreign companies on both in-bound transactions and out-bound strategic transactions involving Japanese entities.
Through our long history in Tokyo, we are praised for our understanding of the cultural and other non-legal aspects of doing business in Japan. Coupled with our extensive network of offices around the world, this proves to be a powerful combination.
Find out more about Allen &amp;amp; Overy's global expertise.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>5cea2f16-579c-4fe8-8fdb-9f0dffb8b4fa</TermStoreId>
  </Country>
  <Country>
    <Id>14</Id>
    <UniqueId>0615b527-4d81-4d16-902f-f73d2b6b7da7</UniqueId>
    <CountryPageUniqueId>412788e8-9eb9-465d-9272-b707e029b6b5</CountryPageUniqueId>
    <CountryName>Luxembourg</CountryName>
    <Text>We deal with all types of domestic and cross-border transactions, from local matters to pivotal international transactions. Our lawyers advise banks, asset managers, private equity houses, insurance and reinsurance companies, blue chip companies, Luxembourg-based companies, governmental authorities and public entities, and we are the chosen legal partner for many organisations with international or European headquarters in Luxembourg.
The combination of our international network and sound local knowledge enables us to provide our clients with a consistent and first rate service. That means giving them intelligent advice in banking, capital markets, competition, corporate, intellectual property, insurance law, investment and pension funds, labour law, real estate and tax. Beyond technical expertise, our clients appreciate our commercially astute approach and the way we find practical solutions to their problems, including access to pioneering know-how services.
For contentious matters, our litigation lawyers represent clients before all Luxembourg courts, the Court of Justice of the European Union and the Benelux Court of Justice.
Due to the growing interest in Luxembourg legal structures from clients outside Luxembourg and to the intensification and globalisation of inbound and outbound - to and from Luxembourg - business and investment relations, we have established dedicated Luxembourg desks in different parts of the world.
Recognition for our work
Luxembourg Law Firm of the Year, IFLR Europe Awards 2007, 2009 and 2010
Luxembourg Tax Firm of the Year, ITR European Tax Awards 2010 &amp;amp; 2011
Law Firm of the Year for Benelux, FT Mergermarket Awards 2007, 2008, 2009, 2010, 2012 &amp;amp; 2013
Intellectual Property Law Firm of the Year in Luxembourg, Corporate Intl Magazine 2010 Legal Award</Text>
    <TermStoreId>cee77378-d2ea-4cf2-ac02-1dd48401b1d9</TermStoreId>
  </Country>
  <Country>
    <Id>15</Id>
    <UniqueId>097fdb0d-7513-41b0-9e71-55f3725ad86d</UniqueId>
    <CountryPageUniqueId>98d5c39f-501e-470f-97bc-45b7d179411b</CountryPageUniqueId>
    <CountryName>Morocco</CountryName>
    <Text>Our Casablanca office is staffed by a team of over 30 fee earners, combining leading local lawyers with regional and internationals specialists. This combination of in-depth local understanding and market leading international expertise makes our offering a truly unique one.
Our team has an extensive track record of advising clients on high profile, strategic transactions in Africa and have established close working relationships with regulators, government departments, investors and leading corporates across the region. 
Morocco is rapidly establishing itself as a key hub for international companies and investors looking to build a presence in Africa. Our Casablanca office works closely with our global Africa interest group and top-tier Middle East practice providing a complete solution for the full spectrum of MENA legal requirements. 
We pride ourselves on combining international commercial experience with local knowledge and quality people. Our team is well known for their innovative approach to client service and track record of providing seamless integrated advice on cutting-edge deals throughout the region. 
Find out more about Allen &amp;amp; Overy's global expertise.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>9bc3e0e6-8c13-4eaa-ba60-3d4061ba65bf</TermStoreId>
  </Country>
  <Country>
    <Id>16</Id>
    <UniqueId>0999a527-bb1f-488e-8e32-39fdc93f1ebf</UniqueId>
    <CountryPageUniqueId>e79cc851-4f4c-4630-a705-9850d61d4708</CountryPageUniqueId>
    <CountryName>Netherlands</CountryName>
    <Text>We think and work with our clients. Our lawyers are recognised for their commercial understanding and for daring to take a stand and provide clear recommendations; a rare phenomenon in legal practice.
Allen &amp;amp; Overy's Amsterdam office, is known for its individual experts and their ability to join forces, across practice areas and borders, to get deals done and to find solutions in highly complex cases.
We believe that clients today are looking for a legal adviser who is also a long-term business partner. In today’s world, legal risk management is an integral part of running a business, going well beyond transactions and disputes. We use our knowledge and experience to help our clients mitigate risks and navigate the pitfalls, on deal and off deal.
Our global span of 43 offices with 5,153 staff and 525 partners covers established and emerging economies in the West and East. What we share is deep-seated local knowledge and networks, a spirit of collaboration and the drive to exceed client expectations.
Our office in Amsterdam includes over 430 staff and 40 partners and offers legal advice to clients in almost every sector, including large and mid-sized companies, financial institutions and government organisations. Our clients benefit from our global reach and scalability. We are universally recognised market leaders in corporate transactions, banking &amp;amp; capital markets, governance &amp;amp; regulatory and disputes.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>031d8f93-2113-474e-9855-66e3e672928e</TermStoreId>
  </Country>
  <Country>
    <Id>17</Id>
    <UniqueId>51daac74-b274-48f6-9685-827b924821d4</UniqueId>
    <CountryPageUniqueId>77391bdf-0418-48c3-895c-c0cec18f3da2</CountryPageUniqueId>
    <CountryName>Poland</CountryName>
    <Text>Allen &amp;amp; Overy was one of the first international legal practices to open an office in Poland in 1991. Since then, we've developed into a leading practice in all core groups with an outstanding reputation for our role in a number of large-scale landmark transactions. 
We seek to combine extensive international experience of managing corporate and financial transactions with both expertise in new and complex legal areas, and excellent local law advice provided by top-class Polish and foreign lawyers.
We have developed a team of lawyers with specialisations covering Allen &amp;amp; Overy’s core practice areas. This enables us to staff major transactions locally, with the facility to involve experts from other Allen &amp;amp; Overy offices if required. Our lawyers cooperate across practice groups to offer clients integrated and business-oriented solutions.
Recognition for our work
 “The Polish branch of this magic circle firm maintains its exceptional reputation in the market” Chambers Europe 2013
 “It is a driving force for other firms in the Polish market.&amp;quot; Chambers Europe 2013
 &amp;quot;The lawyers are extremely reliable and trustworthy; I enjoy working with them. They are creative and don't just give 'yes' or 'no' answers, they give comprehensive alternatives.” Chambers Europe 2013
Allen &amp;amp; Overy, A. Pędzich sp. k.’s ‘excellent’ team is valued for its ‘good level of specific legal knowledge’. Legal 500 2013
Allen &amp;amp; Overy, A. Pedzich sp. k.’s team is ‘well organised’ and ‘experienced, with strong pro-business qualities and knowledge’ Legal 500 2013


Find out more about Allen &amp;amp; Overy's global expertise.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>9f29f956-844e-4336-a140-859e8353ba0a</TermStoreId>
  </Country>
  <Country>
    <Id>18</Id>
    <UniqueId>aceab5b7-070f-4e8f-882b-d4ca116c3541</UniqueId>
    <CountryPageUniqueId>a06bb319-13ed-4aa3-8b51-f35498d81220</CountryPageUniqueId>
    <CountryName>Qatar</CountryName>
    <Text>Allen &amp;amp; Overy has been active in the Qatari market since the 1970s. Over this time, Qatar has increased in importance, both as an integral part of the Gulf Cooperation Council markets, and as a launch pad for investment in other parts of the world. 
We opened our office in Doha in February 2010, having obtained a licence to practice from the Qatar Financial Centre. The decision to open an office in Qatar followed requests from a number of our Qatar-based institutional clients and a growing interest in Qatar from clients from across our international network.
Our Doha office focuses on all aspects of commercial law. The office advises on corporate law, including domestic and regional M&amp;amp;A, joint ventures, outward investments by Qatari clients, inward investment by international clients and commercial arrangements (such as agency arrangements) for international clients conducting business within Qatar.
Because of the way Qatar's foreign investor laws are structured, we have particular expertise in advising on joint ventures to conduct business in Qatar between international clients and Qatar-based entities. We advise on all aspects of finance, including bank finance for local and international banks, debt capital markets for issuers and managers and all aspects of Islamic financing (including Sukuks). Other areas of expertise include domestic and international real estate, Qatari regulatory advice and collective investment schemes.  
Find out more about Allen &amp;amp; Overy's global expertise.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>e1cae941-cb6a-4294-9dcc-b3640b73946c</TermStoreId>
  </Country>
  <Country>
    <Id>19</Id>
    <UniqueId>a19edeeb-93d8-416c-897a-bfa3a19138dd</UniqueId>
    <CountryPageUniqueId>295b4777-4bfa-4a26-8ce7-4d7949e83888</CountryPageUniqueId>
    <CountryName>Romania</CountryName>
    <Text>Radu Tărăcilă Pădurari Retevoescu SCA (RTPR) and Allen &amp;amp; Overy have been working together in Romania for several years.
Our association combines the expertise, resources and reputation of an international legal practice with top-flight Romanian lawyers who have excellent knowledge of local market conditions.
RTPR has four partners, 30 associate lawyers and trainees and more than 12 support staff in Bucharest, as well as the support from Allen &amp;amp; Overy of an international team of lawyers specialising in mergers and acquisitions, finance, capital markets and projects. Together we handle the most sophisticated, demanding and high-profile transactions on the Romanian market.
We offer our clients a strong team which delivers a first-class service, providing pragmatic and commercially-orientated advice. We have the resources to respond quickly, effectively and efficiently to our clients’ needs.
Find out more about Allen &amp;amp; Overy's global expertise.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>8aa3e513-f21c-451f-9966-199589980098</TermStoreId>
  </Country>
  <Country>
    <Id>20</Id>
    <UniqueId>2efeaab4-8138-474a-b283-13486539fc8d</UniqueId>
    <CountryPageUniqueId>709c9233-9aa3-431b-9015-08e66c8de2a3</CountryPageUniqueId>
    <CountryName>Russia</CountryName>
    <Text>Allen &amp;amp; Overy Legal Services provides a comprehensive service to clients wishing to do business in the Russian Federation, combining international experience with local expertise.
We have nearly 40 years’ experience advising on transactions concerning the former Soviet Union and have been active in Russia and the CIS since 1991.
Allen &amp;amp; Overy’s Moscow office, which opened in 1993, is the headquarters of the global Russia practice group, which comprises some 150 lawyers (both Russian and internationally qualified) based in Moscow, London, New York, Continental Europe and Asia Pacific.
We have also established a dedicated Luxembourg-Russia desk, which is focussing on growing client demand for investment into and out of Russia.
The depth of our practice enables our lawyers to understand the approach various parties take to the legal and commercial issues common in finance and corporate deals, and the quality and reach of the work we undertake ensure that our lawyers have continuous access to the most creative solutions the marketplace has to offer. 
Find out more about Allen &amp;amp; Overy's global expertise.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>d8bb1f82-95be-4add-8b49-1f6e7710653f</TermStoreId>
  </Country>
  <Country>
    <Id>21</Id>
    <UniqueId>751a47a4-d88b-4f09-8e46-f4a6e95a93a0</UniqueId>
    <CountryPageUniqueId>c9627f1b-f16c-450b-92e5-5150742aac84</CountryPageUniqueId>
    <CountryName>Saudi Arabia</CountryName>
    <Text>Allen &amp;amp; Overy advises its clients on matters relating to the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia through an association with Zeyad S. Khoshaim Law Firm. 
The associated Riyadh office includes a team of veteran Saudi and internationally qualified lawyers who advise on a wide range of practice areas, including debt and equity capital markets, local and cross-border M&amp;amp;A, corporate, projects, banking, and Islamic finance transactions.
The Riyadh team is led by three partners: Zeyad Khoshaim, who is a Saudi Arabian and New York qualified lawyer; Julian Johansen, a UK qualified lawyer who is fully fluent in Arabic; and Johannes Bruski, a corporate lawyer with over twenty years of experience.
Together, the team has an unparalleled understanding of the Saudi Arabian commercial landscape, legal framework, and cultural issues. The team routinely handles all aspects of sophisticated transactions and works seamlessly with A&amp;amp;O’s offices around the world, providing first class, efficient, and integrated legal services.
Recent news
Zeyad S. Khoshaim Law Firm in Association with Allen &amp;amp; Overy has advised AlBilad Investment Company, Alinma Investment Company, Deutsche Securities Saudi Arabia LLC, and Riyadh Capital on the issuance of a SAR7.5bn Saudi Arabian public sukuk (Sadara sukuk).
Along with the Sadara sukuk, we have also advised National Medical Care Company on its USD100million IPO on the Saudi Stock Exchange (Tadawul).
We have advised Saudi Electricity Company, as borrower, in relation to a SAR4.1bn facility to finance the purchase of power generation units from General Electric. This was Saudi Electricity Company’s first ECA-backed facility and the lenders included U.S. Export-Import Bank and Canada’s Export Development Credit
Recognition for our work
&amp;quot;My first choice in Saudi Arabia.” – Chambers Global 2013, Saudi Arabia
“The depth of the senior people there is very helpful.” – Chambers Global 2013, Saudi Arabia
“This firm goes from strength to strength, rising to the top of the rankings after another successful year.”– Chambers Global 2013, Saudi Arabia
“Sources say: ‘Outstanding lawyers there’.” – Chambers Global 2013, Saudi Arabia
Find out more about Allen &amp;amp; Overy's global expertise.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>1db33158-0d86-4fb3-90f3-815cee7d5fcb</TermStoreId>
  </Country>
  <Country>
    <Id>22</Id>
    <UniqueId>1658ed0b-1992-4b30-9722-53151237c6dc</UniqueId>
    <CountryPageUniqueId>7c945fd9-0fb2-47fb-86cc-95abeb6ab532</CountryPageUniqueId>
    <CountryName>Singapore</CountryName>
    <Text>Singapore is a hub for South East Asia and our Singapore office is an intrinsic part of Allen &amp;amp; Overy's Asia Pacific network. We offer clients first class advice on Singapore, English and U.S. law.
Our philosophy is to maintain a high level of personal contact with clients and to ensure those clients have access to our resources and skills at all times. We manage transactions proactively, act both as legal advisers and project coordinators and believe in the effective worldwide management of know-how.
Find out more about Allen &amp;amp; Overy's global expertise.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>088477ae-c777-4b4c-9eb1-ed1c32beccf0</TermStoreId>
  </Country>
  <Country>
    <Id>23</Id>
    <UniqueId>25f2f3b9-c9fb-4f78-af3e-ca9f7b3e98b5</UniqueId>
    <CountryPageUniqueId>13137f05-6c85-4290-9b0b-722295740e3e</CountryPageUniqueId>
    <CountryName>Slovakia</CountryName>
    <Text>Operating from a dedicated office in Bratislava, we are an established leader in the Slovak legal market and a practice of choice. 
Our reputation in the country is built on the blend of global and local knowledge we offer, combined with high-quality services and commitment. 
Known for our international expertise and detailed knowledge of the local legal and business environment, we act for a wide range of Slovak and multinational clients and play a leading role in complex transactions.
Among others, we advise both local and international financial institutions as well as energy, telecoms and media companies in the Slovak Republic.
Our dedicated team of lawyers has a particular expertise in the areas of corporate and M&amp;amp;A, banking and finance, regulatory and compliance, employment, antitrust/competition, restructuring and dispute resolution law.
We value the stable relationships we enjoy with clients in the Slovak market and aim to help them achieve their business goals through the highest standards of legal services and advice.
Recognition for our work
“An excellent team. It is proactive, thinks outside the box and understands clients' needs.&amp;quot;Chambers Europe 2013
&amp;quot;They have the personality for each type of situation. They're very versatile and very smart in Slovakia.&amp;quot; IFLR1000 2012
&amp;quot;Allen &amp;amp; Overy is 'at the top of its game'.&amp;quot; Chambers Europe 2011
Find out more about Allen &amp;amp; Overy's global expertise.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>e644d031-57b7-46e0-aebf-f131de048a0c</TermStoreId>
  </Country>
  <Country>
    <Id>24</Id>
    <UniqueId>aed0169e-e784-4f4e-8b99-3343277151fb</UniqueId>
    <CountryPageUniqueId>64d534f0-4abf-457a-acf3-4edc28a30c71</CountryPageUniqueId>
    <CountryName>Spain</CountryName>
    <Text>Allen &amp;amp; Overy opened the Madrid office in 1991, at a time when the sophistication of the Spanish market, which reflected a simultaneous growth in the country's economy, required a quality focus, with national excellence and international reach.
During the last 20 years we have grown and currently over 100 people are part of the Allen &amp;amp; Overy Madrid team. Our office is led by nine top-tier partners, each of whom has an exceptional track record of success and achievement across a range of industry sectors and who are supported by a dedicated team of experienced lawyers. We are one of the most reputable legal practices in the Spanish market and our work is recognised by the main legal directories. 
Our clients are our priority and they include important Spanish companies and international corporations with interests in Spain, financial institutions and public entities.
Our team of lawyers works together with our client teams, understands their business strategies and knows the kind of market trends that offer the best solution at any time and guarantee the success of any transaction in which we are involved.
Find out more about Allen &amp;amp; Overy's global expertise.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>d48249ff-c3c2-4902-9775-f94dd86b26c1</TermStoreId>
  </Country>
  <Country>
    <Id>25</Id>
    <UniqueId>08a2a55a-5d5b-41aa-98b5-2ba80c4ed3cd</UniqueId>
    <CountryPageUniqueId>a58ca470-abe0-4927-9feb-f63684192460</CountryPageUniqueId>
    <CountryName>Thailand</CountryName>
    <Text>Our Bangkok office has five partners, four counsels and over 20 associates who together advise large domestic and multinational corporates, banks and other financial institutions on international and Thai law.
Central to our strength in Thailand is a strong regional network with offices in Singapore, Jakarta, Hong Kong, Beijing, Shanghai, Tokyo, Sydney and Perth.
We have a strong corporate and M&amp;amp;A practice acting for many multinationals and many of Thailand's listed companies, whom we have also advised on listing and debt and equity offerings. We also have a strong banking practice, with a special focus on project finance, having played a role in most of the recent projects in Thailand in the power and industrial sectors. 
 
Our domestic and international capital markets group has worked on many of the international offerings, securitisations and structured products in Thailand in the past few years. Our capabilities in these sectors are complemented by our litigation practice. With a mixture of Thai and non-Thai partners, we appreciate the requirements of international clients and also of the domestic environment.
Recognition for our work
Thailand Capital Markets Firm of the Year 2010, Asian Counsel
Thailand Alternative Investment Funds Firm of the Year 2010, Asian Counsel
Find out more about Allen &amp;amp; Overy's global expertise.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>924af178-816d-434a-bd01-d9ec3e960a64</TermStoreId>
  </Country>
  <Country>
    <Id>26</Id>
    <UniqueId>85ffdbd5-5713-4d1a-86bc-79a36dfd40bd</UniqueId>
    <CountryPageUniqueId>587db6d3-a0a9-4be6-a1c2-51b3d3323e71</CountryPageUniqueId>
    <CountryName>United Arab Emirates</CountryName>
    <Text>We have had a strong presence in the United Arab Emirates since 1978 and have offices in both of the country's major business centres – Dubai and Abu Dhabi.
The United Arab Emirates is a significant part of our network. Our lawyers offer international expertise gained on high-profile, multi-jurisdictional transactions with deep local roots, the result of many years’ experience in the local Middle East markets where they operate. They advise on some of the most innovative and complex transactions in the region, many of which are market firsts. Over the years we have also built strong relationships with local law firms, key government agencies and regulatory bodies. Thanks to this combination we are now recognised as the preferred legal adviser to some of the most successful organisations operating in the United Arab Emirates, including those expanding overseas and international clients investing in the region. 
Whether we are handling corporate, banking, project finance, capital markets, funds and real estate transactions or dispute resolution matters, we use the best of our technical and international expertise and local knowledge to find practical ways to help our clients achieve their business objectives.
Our first Middle East office opened in Dubai in 1978 and it has grown into a major force in the region. Our team of resident partners and associate lawyers, including Arabic speakers, have experience in working on some of the largest, most complex and unique transactions in the region for a variety of high-profile clients. In terms of track record, breadth of resources and consistent quality across the range of disciplines, there are few firms in Dubai capable of matching this overall service.
Our Abu Dhabi office opened in 2007 and today has a highly experienced team including a number of leading Abu Dhabi practitioners who brought with them extensive expertise and understanding of local practices, clients and transactions. We advise numerous local government entities on a wide variety of matters, including drafting.
Recognition for our work
“Allen &amp;amp; Overy has been doing deals in the region for much longer than many firms and, in addition to being well entrenched, is most efficient in terms of keeping costs down.” Legal 500 2011 (UAE)
“Sources say, ‘A&amp;amp;O offers a smooth, assured Rolls-Royce service. They’ve seen it all before and are incredibly practised and skilful. Highly recommended’.” Chambers Global 2011 (UAE)
“This firm offers the best of both worlds for clients seeking a keen understanding of local law coupled with highly regarded international transactions.” Chambers Global 2011 (UAE)
Find out more about Allen &amp;amp; Overy's global expertise. 
Our offices
Dubai
Abu Dhabi</Text>
    <TermStoreId>3b98eef1-95b2-4b68-8b6e-d73a98e4f4ce</TermStoreId>
  </Country>
  <Country>
    <Id>27</Id>
    <UniqueId>b8a6906b-265d-40de-8ba4-836cc74528c8</UniqueId>
    <CountryPageUniqueId>e427e5fe-fa2c-427c-9c3d-26d9db091b95</CountryPageUniqueId>
    <CountryName>United Kingdom</CountryName>
    <Text>We regularly work on complex cross-border transactions, ground breaking new legal solutions and products, and help Allen &amp;amp; Overy's clients resolve their most difficult disputes.
Our 2500 staff in London are based at One Bishops Square. Allen &amp;amp; Overy's Belfast office, initially comprising a Support Services Centre, opened in July 2011.
Find out more about Allen &amp;amp; Overy's global expertise.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>5683f492-1ae0-4a3f-b445-48d73cbc3afc</TermStoreId>
  </Country>
  <Country>
    <Id>28</Id>
    <UniqueId>67408e98-6416-446e-b38b-7096f01f9ee7</UniqueId>
    <CountryPageUniqueId>e86cf683-52ff-4421-a69d-06ff058d4630</CountryPageUniqueId>
    <CountryName>United States</CountryName>
    <Text>Our New York and Washington, D.C. offices are the core of the global U.S. practice with more than 175 of our U.S. qualified lawyers based there.
Our attorneys handle the most sophisticated and complex domestic and cross-border transactions and cases for our U.S. and non-U.S. clients. We provide a wide range of comprehensive legal services to the world's leading financial institutions, global corporations, funds and multilateral agencies. 
As more than 65% of our work involves more than two countries, our U.S. practice is fully integrated with our offices in Europe, Asia, South America, Australia and Africa to provide our international and domestic clients with seamless solutions and a global reach that is unmatched by any other U.S. firm.Our attorneys include some of the country's leading practitioners that have been recommended by peers and clients in legal and industry publications.
Recognition for our work from the 2011 and 2012 Chambers USA Guide
&amp;quot;They are amazing. With them on our side, we are always confident that a transaction will work because they know what they are doing.&amp;quot; 
&amp;quot;They have a broad global reach, and so whenever there are pieces that are outside of the US I know I have my one go-to person here who can leverage relationships across the globe.&amp;quot; 
&amp;quot;This experienced litigation team handles a wide range of general commercial and securities litigation, as well as white-collar crime and government investigations work. The group has been particularly busy in major financial services litigation. With litigation practices in the UK, Europe, the Middle East and Asia, the firm's strong global footprint enables it to handle complex national and international cases.&amp;quot; 
&amp;quot;The internationally renowned firm has established a significant presence in the US projects market. The firm is particularly well known for its work in the PPP arena, providing counsel to lenders and sponsors, as well as infrastructure funds and government authorities.&amp;quot; 
&amp;quot;This firm stands out in the derivatives and structured products sector for its strong international platform and network of resources. The group maintains close ties to ISDA, and remains a go-to group for key financial institutions&amp;quot;
&amp;quot;It's one of the preeminent real estate groups in New York.&amp;quot; 
&amp;quot;The group provides regulatory advice to the US operations of some of the most recognized financial institutions in the world, including RBS, UBS and BNP Paribas. It also serves as one of the primary outside counsel for SIFMA in relation to the SEC's new pay-to-play rules.&amp;quot;
&amp;quot;It is a really skilled group; the premier firm in the country on any placement agent regulation.&amp;quot; 
&amp;quot;The team's most important quality is its tenacity to stay relevant to our business. The lawyers go the extra mile to understand our business.&amp;quot; 
Find out more about Allen &amp;amp; Overy's global expertise.
Our offices
New York
Washington, D.C.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>5eb0c9d7-808a-474e-9590-c91974c1766a</TermStoreId>
  </Country>
  <Country>
    <Id>29</Id>
    <UniqueId>303286cd-7219-43fd-ad5c-6c7d0325882a</UniqueId>
    <CountryPageUniqueId>4e5b1de5-bc6c-486b-918d-cc5ea87979a3</CountryPageUniqueId>
    <CountryName>Turkey</CountryName>
    <Text>We provide English law advice to international and local corporates, banks, financial institutions, bondholders and government bodies on project finance, capital markets, general lending and M&amp;amp;A work. 
Our Istanbul office is managed by Charles Lindsay who is supported by senior associate Karen Lee and associate Seyda Duman. 
Through our exclusive association with local law firm Gedik &amp;amp; Eraksoy, we also provide our domestic and international clients with Turkish law advice across the full range of transactions. 
A summary of our experience is as follows:
Project financing - We advise sponsors, governments, construction companies and lenders on projects and project financings (including Islamic and conventional financings) across multiple sectors including oil and gas, power, renewables, infrastructure and telecoms.
General lending - Our coverage spans the spectrum of debt products, including a number of hybrid finance options such as bank/bond structures, Islamic structures, high yield, LBOs, margin loans, bridge and forward-start/refinancing facilities.
Capital markets - Our expertise covers the broad spectrum of DCM products, including standalone bonds and debt programmes, Islamic structures, subordinated debt and hybrid capital, Islamic structures, equity linked instruments, liability management, private placements and warrants.
M&amp;amp;A - We advise on mergers and acquisitions (public and private company M&amp;amp;A, joint ventures, private equity investments, public takeovers), corporate finance and equity capital markets work (IPOs and listing on local and international stock exchanges, capital raisings and listed company work), shareholder disputes, employment, intellectual property and commercial agreements.
If you would like to receive further information regarding Allen &amp;amp; Overy Danışmanlık Hizmetleri Avukatlık Ortaklığı, please email Hale Arifagaoglu, hale.arifagaoglu@allenovery.com.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>73c2005a-026d-4eed-a4ff-5edb75b66c85</TermStoreId>
  </Country>
  <Country>
    <Id>30</Id>
    <UniqueId>37f0f704-150e-43f3-a552-85ead09112a8</UniqueId>
    <CountryPageUniqueId>73ec5afa-5de4-4a7e-ab7a-2d7cd43ba6c3</CountryPageUniqueId>
    <CountryName>Vietnam</CountryName>
    <Text>Allen &amp;amp; Overy has established an impressive track record in Vietnam, advising on many of the largest and most important transactions in this market since the mid-1990s. 
Our Hanoi and Ho Chi Minh City offices are a core element of the firm’s growth strategy in Asia. Our work here covers the spectrum of practice areas key to cross-border business. We pride ourselves on the support we are able to provide to clients both on the ground locally in Vietnam, and regionally, particularly in the high growth markets within ASEAN. 
We have a first-class team of international and Vietnamese lawyers to help clients achieve their commercial and strategic goals in Vietnam. Our team’s combined international experience and local expertise allows us to advise on all domestic and cross-border transactions. This one-stop-shop offering is one of the key reasons some of the world’s most prominent corporations have sought our help on their transactions in Vietnam. 
Regionally, we are the only fully integrated international firm with ASEAN covered. Beyond Vietnam, we have a sizeable presence in Singapore, Thailand and Indonesia* as well as dedicated resources focused on Myanmar, Malaysia, the Philippines, Laos, Cambodia and Brunei. 
The strength and breadth of our offering in ASEAN and Asia Pacific differentiates us from other firms, and our global network ensures that our clients enjoy an integrated service across all jurisdictions in which they do business. 
* In Indonesia, we have an exclusive association with local firm Ginting &amp;amp; Reksodiputro</Text>
    <TermStoreId>34578c2f-4ac0-4820-8255-50d22a6625da</TermStoreId>
  </Country>
  <Country>
    <Id>31</Id>
    <UniqueId>3c9467a0-380f-4e69-bd59-ddcf04fc8cff</UniqueId>
    <CountryPageUniqueId />
    <CountryName>Myanmar</CountryName>
    <Text />
    <TermStoreId>a26acdb7-cdb1-4fb9-beae-3ed4fe6a54e1</TermStoreId>
  </Country>
</ArrayOfCountry>