<?xml version="1.0"?>
<ArrayOfPractice xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema">
  <Practice>
    <Id>206</Id>
    <UniqueId>f186fd86-dd75-4fda-a54e-6e660012f4dc</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Abuse of Dominance</PracticeName>
    <Text>Fines of hundreds of millions of dollars or euros are no longer an exception.
Whereas companies could previously focus their attention on U.S. and EU investigations, we are now seeing competition authorities from other important jurisdictions such as Japan, Brazil, Canada, India, South Korea, and others, stepping up their efforts in penalising anticompetitive behaviour. 
We regularly advise clients on complex abuse of dominance and monopolisation issues, drawing on an extraordinary wealth of experience across our international network of offices. Our lawyers act in behavioural cases for both incumbents and complainants. 
 
Our team includes many of the leading practitioners in the field as well as former enforcers and former judicial assistants at the European Court of Justice. This enables us to understand and approach our clients' antitrust issues from every angle and allows us to continue to work on cutting-edge issues at the forefront of antitrust policy. 
 
Our lawyers have played key roles in developing current U.S. and EU enforcement policies and procedures and bring this experience to bear in advising clients on the right strategies and approach across jurisdictions.
Recognition for our work
&amp;quot;This firm has a highly regarded pan-European practice.&amp;quot; Chambers and Partners Europe 2012
 
&amp;quot;The firm exceeded my expectations, it is outstanding in terms of both skill and client care.&amp;quot; Chambers and Partners Italy 2012
 
&amp;quot;We feel that we are in safe hands with these lawyers: they offer a perfect combination of technical expertise, thorough understanding of client needs and commitment.&amp;quot; Chambers and Partners Spain 2012</Text>
    <TermStoreId>01bd9a84-7c08-4fbf-9895-bec345449639</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>97290c58-1db1-45aa-89a2-48d7d0f765a0</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>207</Id>
    <UniqueId>20da89a0-4312-4519-9447-609eab0cb96e</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Administrative Contracts</PracticeName>
    <Text>As such, we are asked to advise on some of the most complex, often first-of-their kind, public sector deals.
We act for public authorities, companies, banks, public-funded entities and utilities and offer advice on all types of public contracts, ranging from public procurement (public works, services, supplies), large transactions such as concessions (including toll roads, water distribution, waste management, telecoms) to public-private partnerships (PPP) (prisons, hospitals, stadiums, roads, rail, canal, renewable energies, etc).
Our practice is well known for its litigation capabilities in this area. We advise on all types of disputes, whether occurring before the contract enters into force (challenge of tender procedures) or relating to the performance of the contract. We work closely with our clients to develop the most effective strategy taking into account our client's objectives and budgetary constraints.
Our team includes specialist lawyers located in [X] jurisdictions. We are used to working together in cross-jurisdictional matters and our seamless service is considered to be one of our greatest strengths. We also share the latest knowledge, so we are able to offer innovative solutions when required.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>ddc543ae-782f-4085-b49f-bee2c313c574</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>e5f42143-a550-4fe5-84a5-6b5ada4229fb</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>208</Id>
    <UniqueId>e3e82623-a51f-411b-b14f-99ebae56cc7c</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Anti-Bribery and Corruption</PracticeName>
    <Text>Our team includes former prosecutors in the U.S., a former chief prosecutor in Europe and has worked on the most significant case to date in the UK. Thanks to our past governmental and recent defence experience, our lawyers are known and respected by leading prosecutors and regulators in the U.S., UK and around Europe. We are one of a few practices which have partners with in-depth experience of managing corruption investigations across Europe, the U.S., the Middle East and Asia.
We routinely act on complex, multi-jurisdictional corruption matters. Our international reach gives us expertise in local law in multiple jurisdictions, and the offices throughout our network work closely together. This is important because corruption investigations are usually cross-border and because different legal systems and cultures have different regulatory regimes and so do not treat issues such as privacy, data protection, employee protection and privilege in the same way. Consequently, our lawyers are able to provide clients with rounded and insightful advice that addresses local issues as well as the risks to a global business arising from cross-border investigations. We can credibly present this analysis to regulators across jurisdictions (including the UK and the U.S.) to protect our clients’ positions.  
We have a track record of handling significant, high-profile bribery and corruption issues for blue-chip multinationals: we have represented large multinational corporations on the full range of corruption issues, from assisting with policies and procedures, to risk management, to handling global investigations and defence. We also regularly conduct due diligence into, and advise on strategies to deal with, foreign agents or intermediaries and mergers and acquisitions/joint venture targets.  
We can call upon a network of trusted local counsel with whom we have built good working relationships: our experience of working on corruption matters with lawyers in jurisdictions where we do not have an office means that we are well placed to recommend local counsel with specialist corruption expertise. Where we need to work in conjunction with local counsel to manage a cross-border investigation or issue, our established working relationships mean that we form integrated teams and are used to managing multiple parties to deliver a high-quality service efficiently.
Recent examples of our work
Our recent and current casework in this area includes representing:
BAE Systems Plc – defence of the public investigation by the UK SFO of the company’s involvement with the Al Yamamah defence contract with Saudi Arabia and its procurement of contracts in multiple jurisdictions around the world, culminating in final settlement at the end of 2010 
a global financial institution – three separate internal investigations of potential corruption issues involving Europe, Asia and Latin America
a UK-based industrialist and his companies – defence in an investigation by the U.S. DOJ, the UK SFO and authorities in other countries, regarding potential corruption; the three-year-long investigation has involved fact gathering on three continents and in five countries
a UK FTSE 100 Plc with global operations – U.S. DOJ corruption investigation of its worldwide sales operations; dealt with DOJ settlement and with UK authorities and advised on corruption issues arising in the Middle East, Asia and Europe (over 40 jurisdictions)</Text>
    <TermStoreId>83842768-aef2-4f6e-9f26-07845155f080</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId />
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>209</Id>
    <UniqueId>9dbed0fd-123a-4e47-9f2c-f6cf38b9de56</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Antitrust Investigations and Disputes</PracticeName>
    <Text>Our antitrust litigation team combines technical expertise with strategic advice to pursue or defend claims on behalf of our clients before national courts across Europe, the EU courts, U.S. courts or elsewhere around the globe.
We advise on all types of disputes and represent companies under investigation by European and U.S. and national competition authorities in cases concerning breaches of competition law. We coordinate national or multi-jurisdictional litigation strategies and responses, often being called in at the pre-litigation stage. In the U.S. we represent corporations and senior executives in criminal and regulatory antitrust investigations initiated by federal and state authorities.
We also help companies develop sound risk management strategies and compliance policies, and conduct in-depth audits, along with crisis management, litigation risk and exposure assessments.
Our team includes many of the leading practitioners in the field, including a former director of criminal enforcement at the Antitrust Division of the U.S. Department of Justice, highly experienced lawyers and litigators, some of whom are former judicial assistants at the ECJ and professors of law at prominent universities. We have played a key role in developing the European Commission's leniency protocols and its approach to access to documents and witness interviews.
Across our European network we have a very active antitrust litigation practice leading private enforcement cases before the commercial courts and cases before the relevant national competition authority, the EU Commission and regulatory bodies. 
Private damages actions 
Findings of cartel, abuse of dominance/monopolisation are frequently followed by private (class) actions seeking damages. Private actions are a mainstay of the competitive landscape in the U.S. and increasingly so in Europe, requiring clients to wield both the sword and shield to protect their rightful place in the market. We are frequently asked to advise on identifying the courts and tribunals in which actions may be brought and assess our clients' exposure to such actions, while considering how best to challenge such claims, to obtain interim relief or to avoid litigation, including through alternative dispute resolution mechanisms. We are currently acting on a number of follow-on antitrust damages cases as well as cases at the intersection of antitrust and IP litigation.
Private actions between international companies increasingly take place in multiple jurisdictions at the same time. In such complex cases, a global strategy is required to enhance efficiency and consistency and also to reduce the costs involved. We offer our clients a significant and competitive advantage in this area by combining the efficiency of our global presence with the perspective of local experience and expertise.
We can assist companies in making litigation risk and exposure assessments and in determining their litigation strategy. By bringing together a team of antitrust, litigation, securities and other experts from across our global practice, we are perfectly equipped to handle each type of private action. 
Commercial antitrust disputes 
Antitrust issues are regularly invoked in negotiations and litigation between rival companies or between companies and their suppliers. Competitors, suppliers or customers may try to use antitrust law to nullify a contract, or alternatively to defend an alleged breach of contract. In recent years we have also seen an increasing number of major cases on licensing and IP (particularly relating to patents) in which antitrust issues play a pivotal role. 
We can use our combined expertise in antitrust and litigation to assist companies seeking to use antitrust issues as either a weapon or a defence in commercial disputes. 
Judicial review 
We have significant experience coordinating challenges to decisions by regulatory authorities at both EU and national level. Our team of antitrust litigation experts have acted in high-profile cases in recent years and are experienced in pleading before the ECJ, General Court in Luxembourg and national courts, including the High Court in England. Our team includes former référendaires at both EU and national courts.
In particular, our team has significant experience in representing clients (whether merging parties or third-party challengers) regarding merger decisions made by both the European Commission and the UK competition authorities. We have also represented companies on half of all the cases challenging merger decisions before the UK Competition Appeal Tribunal, including Lloyds/HBOS and BSkyB/ITV.
Recognition for our work
&amp;quot;The group is noted for its experience in appearing before the Competition Appeal Tribunal (CAT) and in representing clients in a range of litigious matters&amp;quot;Chambers and Partners UK 2013
&amp;quot;The group is acclaimed for the breadth of its experience and it includes experts in merger control, litigation and behavioural matters&amp;quot; Chambers and Partners UK 2013 
&amp;quot;It handles a large volume of litigation and has expertise in a number of sectors&amp;quot;Chambers and Partners France 2012 
&amp;quot;This firm has a truly global presence in litigation, with particular strengths in Europe and the Middle East, as well as a considerable presence in China and the USA&amp;quot; Chambers and Partners 2012
&amp;quot;This team is universally praised for its consistently high-quality work&amp;quot; Chambers and Partners Poland 2012</Text>
    <TermStoreId>3be89296-333d-4c06-961b-1f7c3ca3db6b</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>7a7028a8-8ba1-4a5f-a0dc-95c1b4785668</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>210</Id>
    <UniqueId>c21b52e6-96eb-4604-ac66-f9e8f50732fa</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Antitrust/Competition</PracticeName>
    <Text>In this environment, many of the world's leading companies are turning to Allen &amp;amp; Overy as their preferred competition counsel. 
We have been involved in some of the most high-profile and ground breaking cases in antitrust enforcement in recent years. With over 100 antitrust specialists based in 19 offices serving the three main global regions – Asia Pacific, Europe and the Americas – Allen &amp;amp; Overy is the first choice for major corporates seeking advice on their global antitrust policies, litigation and regulatory strategies. 
We cover all areas of antitrust and competition law enforcement and litigation: antitrust and IP; antitrust disputes including private damages, commercial disputes and judicial reviews; cartels; compliance and counselling; merger control; public procurement and competitive tendering; sector regulation, abuse of dominance/monopolisation and market investigations; and state aid. 
Award-winning
Highly regarded by the legal directories, our antitrust and competition team is ranked in the top ten of the GCR Global Elite. Our award-winning team consists of many of the leading practitioners in the field. This includes a former director of criminal enforcement at the Antitrust Division of the U.S. Department of Justice (DOJ), former judicial assistants at the European Court of Justice (ECJ), professors of law at prominent universities and the president of the International Bar Association.
This wide network enables us to understand our clients' needs and approach their antitrust issues from every angle and allows us to continue to work on cutting-edge issues at the forefront of antitrust policy.
Regulatory experts
The global economy is being heavily re-regulated by states and regional organisations, and competition law is at the core of this trend.
Our clients rely on us as specialists in regulatory policy to organise coalitions of legal, economic and academic experts to protect their business strategies, products and intellectual property rights. We invest significant time and energy in understanding each sector's specific complexities and defending our clients' unique interests.
Our lawyers are described by Chambers and Partners as part of &amp;quot;a new generation that has the ability to understand clients' businesses and sectors&amp;quot;.
What makes us different?
We combine all the following within one global team: 
The resources to handle multi-forum cases involving parallel, simultaneous government investigations and multiple civil actions worldwide
Global efficiency with local knowledge and expertise
A team of former senior government officials and academics with experience of working at the cutting edge of antitrust law
One of the few international firms with an IP and technology practice of the quality necessary to be able to represent clients in licensing and IP infringement matters
Sector regulatory specialists in IT, telecommunications, energy, media, financial services, life sciences, infrastructure and transport, and retail and consumer goods
Integrated team of antitrust litigation experts
Recognition for our work
GCR &amp;quot;Elite&amp;quot; law firm 2013
Winner – GCR Merger Control Matter of the Year 2012 
Winner – GCR Matter of the Year 2012
Winner – GCR Matter of the Year 2011
&amp;quot;This firm benefits from an impressive network of expertise in competition law, with notable global sector coverage extending across the IT, energy and automotive industries, amongst others. It is well regarded in China, Australia and across Europe, and continues to develop its practice in the USA.&amp;quot; Chambers and Partners Global 2013
&amp;quot;This firm's European coverage is extremely impressive, with experienced practices in the key economies of Western Europe as well as a strong practice in Central and Eastern Europe.&amp;quot;Chambers and Partners Europe 2013
&amp;quot;A key to Allen &amp;amp; Overy's success is its formidable network&amp;quot;IFLR EU Competition 2012 
&amp;quot;Allen &amp;amp; Overy's acclaimed worldwide strength in competition law&amp;quot;Chambers and Partners UK 2012
&amp;quot;Its ability to draw upon the expertise of the firm's global network of European and American antitrust practitioners is also considered a real competitive edge&amp;quot;Chambers and Partners China 2012</Text>
    <TermStoreId>97290c58-1db1-45aa-89a2-48d7d0f765a0</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId />
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>211</Id>
    <UniqueId>2b29ed57-5421-4c8b-b84d-e1a6eebe82db</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Asset Finance</PracticeName>
    <Text>But we also have extensive experience at other levels and across all sectors of the asset finance industry. Whatever we’re handling, our lawyers have the breadth and depth of experience to help our clients find the most commercially beneficial way to structure a deal. 
We advise on both domestic and cross-border asset financings including all types of debt, lease (both tax- and non-tax-based, including UK tax leasing, Spanish operating tax leases, Japanese operating leases) export credit and capital markets driven products, securitisations, receivables financings, vendor programmes and retail finance. Our lawyers help clients to buy and sell leasing companies and portfolios of assets, and structure regional and global leasing business networks. They also advise on aircraft repossessions and have  extensive experience on airline and ship restructurings and insolvencies. 
We act for banks, financiers, airlines, lessors, manufacturers, captive finance companies, operators, borrowers, lessees, export credit agencies, and governmental and international organisations. 
With a range of experts throughout our worldwide network, we’re able to cover all types of vessel and offshore installation from LNG carriers and drilling rigs to VLCCs and luxury yachts. Similarly, we advise on the full range of aircraft financing including all types of pre- and post-delivery financings, ECA backed financing, operating leases, sale and purchase of new and used aircraft and structured financing, and give advice on general aviation matters such as regulatory and maintenance. Our expertise in domestic and cross-border asset financings covers everything from rail, manufacturing plants, water treatment facilities and pipelines to vehicle fleets, mining equipment, films, satellites and computer hardware/software.
We have a track record for advising clients on transactions that become market firsts and award winners, helping us to cement our position at the forefront of the market. 
Recognition for our work
“An enormous volume of deals in aviation and other assets. A brand name popular with financial institutions.” Chambers Global 2011
“Clients benefit from the firm's global presence, which enables the team to collaborate with colleagues in multiple jurisdictions on complex international and cross-border transactions.” Chambers UK 2012
“Their strength is their ‘no mountain too high’ approach. If I say I need something yesterday, it will be there.” Chambers UK 2010</Text>
    <TermStoreId>957ad9f8-3dac-4cb7-9100-69b3001f257d</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>7891e92d-9a8b-4dfa-8b4f-f45d51f09808</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>212</Id>
    <UniqueId>38ac71cd-a42a-4723-b9e9-83b4e0f25fc2</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Asset Management</PracticeName>
    <Text>The industry is going through a period of change as a result of the increasing overlap between the alternative investment sector and the traditional retail long-only sector, the evolution of investment strategies, regulatory change and the opportunities arising from the changes taking place in the banking sector.  We are ideally placed to assist clients in positioning their businesses and tailoring their investments to take advantage of these new trends. 
We have particular capabilities in relation to infrastructure, debt, real estate, private equity, hedge, structured regulated (including ETFs) and sovereign wealth funds.  
The team assists both asset managers and major institutional investors on:
setting up new investment funds and managed account structures, including tax matters, fund structuring, drafting offering materials and constitutional documentation, joint venture arrangements, negotiating with investors and handling closings.
advising on investment management agreements, appointing custodians and broker-dealers, establishing securities lending programmes, prime brokerage agreements and setting up fund platforms.
all regulatory matters.  The international nature of the team makes us very well placed to advise on the cross-border impact of regulations affecting the industry, from the Dodd-Frank Act and Investment Adviser regulations in the U.S. to the Alternative Investment Fund Manager's Directive, EMIR and Solvency II in the EU.  Our asset management team is part of our wider regulatory team and so provides regulatory advice on a seamless basis.
secondary transfers (often on a portfolio basis) of interests in funds. 
Notably, the group also advises a broad range of institutional investors on their investments in funds and their appointment of asset managers. We are therefore very much in tune with market standards across a range of asset management products. This also provides a benefit to our asset manager clients, since this market knowledge makes us more efficient in structuring funds, negotiating side letters and closing investors into a fund.
The team works closely with lawyers in other practice areas to advise on: 
M&amp;amp;A transactions for asset managers or providers of services to asset managers;
financings and hedging for funds;
LLP agreements for asset managers;
asset management related disputes (e.g. misselling claims); and
employment, remuneration and data protection matters.
Working with Allen &amp;amp; Overy's well developed sector teams in areas such as real estate, private equity and infrastructure we are also able to offer asset managers full life-cycle support in dealing with the assets you chose to invest in.
Recognition for our work
&amp;quot;Allen &amp;amp; Overy LLP’s ‘very experienced and responsive’ team works across the higher end of private equity, real estate, infrastructure, hedge and listed funds, and certain UCITS.&amp;quot; Legal 500, 2011
&amp;quot;Allen &amp;amp; Overy LLP has ‘good depth, a sufficiently large team and the ability to bring in specialists in the US, the UK and across the EU’.&amp;quot; Legal 500, 2012
&amp;quot;This firm provides a full suite of services to asset managers and institutional investor clients, such as advice relating to fund establishment, regulatory matters, structuring fund vehicles, investment management and undertakings for collective investment transferable securities (UCITS).&amp;quot; Chambers &amp;amp; Partners, 2013</Text>
    <TermStoreId>abd5af70-fbf2-466d-af86-435b5f97fe82</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId />
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>213</Id>
    <UniqueId>34cb14c6-d31a-4126-b0fd-c77ff8a606f8</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Aviation Disputes</PracticeName>
    <Text>We act for lessors such as Boeing, GECAS, Trident (BAE’s aircraft leasing arm), Pembroke, Allco Finance and Pegasus in the repossession of aircraft in the UK, Europe, Asia and the U.S. 
We also advise them on repossession strategies, including self-help remedies, court orders, cross-border enforcement strategies and arbitration.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>e108a1ac-252a-449c-9004-e536bdebb382</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>7a7028a8-8ba1-4a5f-a0dc-95c1b4785668</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>214</Id>
    <UniqueId>2cc48364-d5ca-4ed1-8a9b-64a3752321a3</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Banking and Finance</PracticeName>
    <Text>With such a deep team and global reach, international and industry-leading ‘first-of-a-kind’ transactions are our hallmark. We have been instrumental in nearly all the major developments in the modern financial markets.
The past few years have been the most challenging in the history of the international financial markets and have required fresh thinking as the markets adjust to continually changing economic, political and regulatory conditions. Renowned for our intellectual rigour, our banking and finance lawyers draw on deep product expertise and regularly work alongside our regulatory, litigation, restructuring and other specialists – particularly important in light of recent market conditions – to develop innovative solutions for our clients, often incorporating complex financing techniques that lead the industry.
That is why over 800 corporate and financial institution participants in the financial markets entrust us with the full range of their domestic and cross-border transactions.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>7891e92d-9a8b-4dfa-8b4f-f45d51f09808</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId />
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>215</Id>
    <UniqueId>9bd4e772-b8ea-46ef-96c4-4f62f1bbf630</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Banking, Finance and Securities Disputes</PracticeName>
    <Text>We also provide first rate business and product and transaction knowledge which is aligned with our pre-eminent global Finance practice. 
As advisers to the world’s leading international financial institutions, we support clients in their litigation and dispute resolution needs, from major investigations and high-profile disputes, to reputational risk management issues. Our clients are the world's leading investment banks, asset managers, hedge funds, private banks and retail banks.
Our global network and experience – along with our extensive knowledge that comes from having unrivalled banking, capital markets and derivatives practices in the world’s main financial hubs – sets us apart from others in the industry. Because our dedicated Banking, Finance and Securities Disputes team works closely with our transactional specialists, we are able to quickly spot business trends that might lead to risk for our clients. We can then organise rapid and robust strategies to enforce rights, recover money or assets, or defend financial and reputational claims.
 
Many of our cases involve working with colleagues across different jurisdictions. For example in 2011 around two-thirds of our finance litigation cases involved lawyers from two or more of our offices – demonstrating the cross-border collaboration between our litigators around the world. As a result, we are able to manage disputes and coordinate proceedings brought in more than one jurisdiction and across varied legal cultures. 
Recent examples of our work
Our recent and current casework in this area includes representing:
Richard Fuld in connection with congressional testimony, testimony before the Financial Crisis Inquiry Commission, criminal, regulatory and bankruptcy examiner investigations, FINRA proceedings and multiple civil securities and ERISA actions.
Dexia/Depfa in proceedings brought in the English courts to recover sums owing from an Italian public authority under interest rate swaps which involved successfully opposing a jurisdiction challenge. These matters are also the subject of Italian proceedings in the Administrative Court. In addition, we are acting for both European and U.S. banks in respect of a number of other claims against public bodies in respect of challenges to the validity of ISDA trades.
Four major banks in defending claims brought by the trustee in the bankruptcy of Bernard L. Madoff Investment Securities LLC and the liquidators of some of the feeder funds.
Recognition for our work
Ranked 1st tier in the Dispute Resolution category. &amp;quot;This firm has a truly global presence in litigation, with particular strengths in Europe and the Middle East, as well as a considerable presence in China and the USA. Its international stature is illustrated by the key financial crisis-related cases that it features on.&amp;quot; Chambers &amp;amp; Partners Global 2011 
Ranked 1st tier in the Banking Litigation category. “Banking and finance powerhouse Allen &amp;amp; Overy LLP fields a ‘technically excellent’ banking, finance and regulatory litigation team that is ‘very thorough and responsive’. Thanks to the firm’s global network, the group packs a serious international punch, and excels in complex cross-border financial disputes.”  Legal 500 UK 2010</Text>
    <TermStoreId>1f402dbf-34af-4430-b952-6106e350b409</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>7a7028a8-8ba1-4a5f-a0dc-95c1b4785668</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>216</Id>
    <UniqueId>67433873-3e30-4a69-853f-3da3800585c1</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Capital Markets</PracticeName>
    <Text>Our capital markets practice covers the full range of capital markets products and incorporates specialists in debt and equity capital markets, derivatives and structured finance, securitisation, corporate trust and agency and high yield.
Few practices can match our award-winning, top tier position across the full range of capital market products. With such a deep bench of specialists and global reach, international and industry-leading ‘first-of-a-kind’ transactions are our hallmark. We have been instrumental in nearly all the major developments in the capital markets, starting with the first ever eurobond issue in the 1960s.
Integrated into our capital markets practice is a group of U.S. corporate finance lawyers who specialise in U.S. securities law advice, enabling us to advise on U.S. law aspects of transactions anywhere in the world. In addition, a number of our lawyers play leading roles in our cross-practice Islamic Finance group.
The past few years have been the most challenging in the history of international financial markets and have required fresh thinking as the markets adjust to the continually changing economic, political and regulatory conditions. Renowned for our intellectual rigour, our capital markets lawyers draw on deep product expertise and regularly work alongside our regulatory, banking and finance, litigation, restructuring and other specialist teams to develop innovative solutions for our clients, often incorporating precedent-setting financing techniques that lead the industry.
That is why over 800 corporate and financial institution participants in the financial markets entrust us with the full range of their domestic and cross-border transactions.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>dddbe240-d29a-43f7-922f-1dc914fc0e53</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId />
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>217</Id>
    <UniqueId>5bc1d809-206f-4d9a-9151-2bf83b629556</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Cartels and other Anticompetitive Agreements</PracticeName>
    <Text>The stakes for companies subject to cartels and other anticompetitive agreements continue to increase. In a number of jurisdictions cartel activity is a criminal offence and there is also a burgeoning movement to criminalise cartel activity in places where previously it was seen as wholly or principally a civil matter. We are seeing increasingly aggressive cartel enforcement everywhere in the world. 
Whereas companies could previously focus their attention on U.S. and EU investigations, we are now seeing competition authorities from other important jurisdictions such as Japan, Brazil, Canada, India, South Korea and others stepping up their efforts in penalising anticompetitive behaviour. Our lawyers have played key roles in developing current U.S. and EU enforcement policies and procedures and this experience enables us to cover every aspect of complex government investigations and to provide the best immediate response to multi-dimensional enforcement actions. 
We are well placed to deal with the globalisation of antitrust enforcement and its evolution to a penal or quasi-penal regime. Our team includes a former director of criminal enforcement at the Antitrust Division of the U.S. Department of Justice, and, to adequately defend companies before the EU and U.S. courts, especially on procedural grounds, highly experienced lawyers and litigators, some of whom are former judicial assistants at the European Court of Justice and professors of law at prominent universities. 
We have a leading international cartel practice, advising clients on anticompetitive agreements as well as acting in high-profile international and national cartel investigations and subsequent litigation. 
Although the issues in cartel cases are not sector-specific our experience spans almost every sector of the economy and our teams have broken new ground in the use of leniency programmes on a global scale. 
Our work on cartel cases includes:
Conducting audits (including review of documents seized and interviews) on a national and/or multi- jurisdictional basis, pre or post dawn raids, to identify potential competition law issues and measure the risks incurred 
Attending a dawn raid on premises to ensure our client's rights are preserved 
Gathering a rapid response team (multi-jurisdictional or national) to review all documentation 
Challenging dawn raid procedures in court 
Preparing for potential further inspections
Developing defence and communication strategies
Assisting with preliminary consideration as to leniency/settlement
Advising on formal proceedings
Recognition for our work
&amp;quot;The firm is capable of handing complex cartel investigations&amp;quot; Chambers and Partners Europe 2012</Text>
    <TermStoreId>7bd383da-c7b6-4046-a271-ab0e230d70ed</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>97290c58-1db1-45aa-89a2-48d7d0f765a0</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>218</Id>
    <UniqueId>869419de-e434-4515-8761-17dd4aace6df</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Chemicals</PracticeName>
    <Text>Our multi-jurisdictional chemicals practice group has a strong record of advising a number of leading multinational chemicals companies, as well as downstream users of chemicals across different sectors on sensitive issues surrounding the regulatory/liability risks arising from their products and services.
We have worked extensively on Europe’s REACH regime. This has included advice on:
registration obligations in complex supply chains
disclosure of information to regulators and third parties
analysis of trading operations to determine REACH obligations
the authorisation powers (and the inclusion of substances on the candidate list) including related legal challenges
Safety Data Sheets
REACH audits by regulators
supply chain terms
We provide advice on developments under the CLP Regulation and track and advise on the development of equivalent global requirements.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>9b083943-ec72-4ad4-b737-89a90be88f20</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>afb18bd5-bdd7-4cc3-a69b-bcb6997b5a6c</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>219</Id>
    <UniqueId>d5ba315d-79a1-41d5-b3ff-09c7cdc61615</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Class Actions and Group Litigation</PracticeName>
    <Text>Legislative reform has taken place in many European countries, and is being progressed at EU Commission level.
We offer our clients a significant and competitive advantage in this area through our 'global footprint' – we have experience in virtually every significant jurisdiction in handling and resolving class actions. Experience shows that this global footprint can be very effective for our clients as the risk of class actions spreads across Europe and elsewhere.
Our team consists of litigation, securities, competition and other experts from across our global practice. Leading our team is specialist Patricia M Hynes, who, as an ex-leader of the plaintiffs' class action bar, offers a unique insight into class action cases. In addition, we have one of the leading litigation teams in the Netherlands, which is rapidly developing into an important forum for (international) collective settlement of mass claims. 
 Recent examples of our work
Successfully concluded defence of Jeffrey Greenberg, the former CEO of MMC, over five years in numerous securities class actions, ERISA class actions and derivative actions in both state and federal courts.
Representation of JPMorgan Chase in several federal and state class actions arising out of the Madoff Ponzi scheme. JPMorgan provided routine banking services to Bernard Madoff Investment Services (BMIS).
Representation of the bankruptcy trustees and policyholders of bankrupt life insurer Vie d'Or in litigation that led to landmark Supreme Court decisions on the rights and powers of representative associations in class actions, and in the ensuing class settlement (one of the first under the 2005 Act on the Collective Settlement of Mass Claims).
Representation of British American Tobacco in a class action brought by the main Italian consumer association and three smokers. The claimants sought compensation for both economic and not economic damages which smokers have allegedly suffered and would still suffer due to the addiction caused by cigarettes.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>f1f720e9-9b41-4592-87e6-035002c3c514</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>7a7028a8-8ba1-4a5f-a0dc-95c1b4785668</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>220</Id>
    <UniqueId>2ea1a4fb-2d11-421b-ac5e-fb985d85c996</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Commercial</PracticeName>
    <Text>We advise on the full range of commercial issues, across all sectors, on a multi-jurisdictional basis.
Our general commercial experience includes advising on all commercial contracts including contracts covering outsourcing conducted through a detailed procurement process, services distribution, software licensing, development, product, marketing, manufacturing, supply, maintenance and support, white labelling, collaboration, joint venture agreements and online terms and conditions.
We also advise on non-contractual commercial issues such as data protection, freedom of information, document retention policies, eCommerce and sales law.
Clients value the calibre of our team, the quality of our legal expertise and our ability to negotiate robust agreements.  Key to our success is the ability to combine the technical skills of our professionals with the business needs of our clients.  We proactively help you to understand and deal with issues that arise in a commercial manner that fits in with your business objectives.
Clients benefit from:
Specialist expertise – recognised specialists in regulatory, tax, finance, employment, antitrust, public procurement and IP law. This means you will have access to the full skill-set necessary to achieve your commercial objectives.
Experience with suppliers and customers – we act for both major suppliers and customers so we understand the key requirements of your commercial contracts and your likely concerns.  
Multinational team – our integrated team covers Asia Pacific, Europe, Middle East and U.S. meaning we bring both local knowledge and a global perspective to our work.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>eccb15de-0c31-4efc-81f0-6128450ad09c</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>7e0fa517-f886-49c1-8d30-6474dd585171</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>221</Id>
    <UniqueId>9fbaa515-e703-4161-99aa-2ea85da81683</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Commercial and Contract Disputes</PracticeName>
    <Text>Whether it is a dispute involving a merger and acquisition/sale, commercial contract or business competition, our litigators take a practical, commercial approach. 
After a thorough analysis of the law and facts, we work with our clients to fashion the right approach: is the dispute appropriate for aggressive litigation, in which case we fight to win, or is a more nuanced approach to resolving the dispute called for?
In each situation, our global network means we can deliver accurate, commercial advice quickly, wherever the dispute takes place.  If the dispute covers multiple jurisdictions, our local experts on the ground can quickly form an international team. Our long experience means we know what to expect and how to achieve results.  We never lose sight of the need to tailor our approach to the needs of the client we are representing, whether they are a large corporate undertaking or a smaller enterprise.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>a692dec7-5e2c-43e1-b874-4782d10aff01</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>7a7028a8-8ba1-4a5f-a0dc-95c1b4785668</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>222</Id>
    <UniqueId>75885c34-0110-4e26-a7c5-57cd63c8665f</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Commercial Intellectual Property</PracticeName>
    <Text>We frequently advise on cross-border collaborations, joint ventures and strategic licensing deals and have experience both working for, and negotiating against, counterparties throughout Europe, the United States and Asia. The particular commercial advice we can provide to clients includes the following:
licensing, joint venture and collaboration documentation
sale and other forms of disposal of IP rights including warranty protection
distribution, agency, contract manufacture, supply, sponsorship and other commercial agreements
IP backed asset financing and taking security interests over IP assets including royalty monetisation agreements
IP due diligence and verification including of related agreements
antitrust risks in licensing, joint venture and non-compete arrangements including those related to the settlement of patent disputes
what happens when one party wants to get out of the arrangement and/or one party becomes bankrupt or insolvent
standard form agreements, including providing seminars to business people on how to use standard forms, and issues to watch out for</Text>
    <TermStoreId>39ac337f-2ca1-43e9-a8de-05e1a4d60e7c</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>ead974a2-95a8-4128-afb5-b493481bf45d</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>223</Id>
    <UniqueId>3c786b3f-db3b-48cd-b163-5cba80a32134</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Contaminated Land</PracticeName>
    <Text>We also work with clients on a variety of remediation projects, including advising on contractual arrangements with environmental consultants and remediation contractors.  Our advice concerns liabilities arising from a broad scope of EHS matter such as contaminated land, marine or other waterways pollution and asbestos, across a wide variety of industries, whether as part of a transaction or on a stand alone basis.
We have a strong background in working with clients to manage historical (or legacy) environmental issues, commonly related to contaminated land. We help clients to identify the extent of any retained environmental liabilities and advise on how to mitigate those risks and manage any potential exposures arising from assets, permits and contracts.
The environmental and social responsibility risks in any business are requiring greater attention than ever. Civil liability for environmental damage continues to be a hot topic in Europe and else where.
In this potentially complex area, Allen &amp;amp; Overy’s team has advised on both potential corporate and director liability in respect of environmental and health and safety incidents. Our global coverage makes us particularly well placed to provide multi-jurisdictional advice.
The range of advice that we offer in relation to contaminated land includes:
marine offshore and other waterways pollution
asbestos
remediation projects
historical or legacy environmental issues
mitigation of risk and exposures from assets, operations, permits and contracts
Environmental Liability Directive
tortious environmental liability
health and safety incidents
corporate and director liability for environmental, health and safety matters
aftercare and restoration obligations
remediation obligations arising from decommissioning of permitted facilities</Text>
    <TermStoreId>df94aec6-c4ca-407f-aa66-f5da039f7530</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>afb18bd5-bdd7-4cc3-a69b-bcb6997b5a6c</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>224</Id>
    <UniqueId>e8e343f7-e8a1-489b-9013-077a4d9b4757</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Corporate and M＆A</PracticeName>
    <Text>We advise across the broad spectrum of corporate work including public takeovers, private M&amp;amp;A, ECM, complex joint ventures, disposals and corporate restructurings, as well as general commercial, antitrust and corporate governance issues.
Recognised as a leading adviser on M&amp;amp;A and other corporate transactions  we are able to combine exceptional transactional skills with specialist expertise including antitrust, employment and benefits, environmental, intellectual property and tax. This enables us to handle the numerous issues that can arise in a single corporate transaction. We have an exceptional track record in every sector and particular strengths in highly regulated industries.
Allen &amp;amp; Overy is a truly global adviser and we boast an enviable geographic footprint. Our corporate team spans all of our offices and works seamlessly with a global community of relationship law firms giving us access to a further 118 countries. This platform provides our clients with the confidence that they will receive the highest quality advice in both their domestic markets and as they expand into new territories.
Cross-border work is where we excel and the majority of our transactions have a multi-jurisdictional focus. Strong teamwork and efficient working practices and uniform approaches enable us to manage cross-border deals effectively and seamlessly.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>7e0fa517-f886-49c1-8d30-6474dd585171</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId />
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>225</Id>
    <UniqueId>ff781b85-6e55-4455-bce9-f1ccdfffc878</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Corporate Disputes and Corporate Governance</PracticeName>
    <Text>Much of our work involves corporate disputes such as breach of contract and warranty cases, disputes over the proper construction of agreements, shareholder disputes, disputes over joint ventures, and post-mergers and acquisitions disputes. In addition, we regularly advise on corporate governance related litigation, for example shareholder activism battles, disputes on public take-over bids and squeeze-out procedures. We recognise that prevention is better than cure and regularly advise clients on risk management issues.
We understand that corporations today want lawyers who understand their business and we take the time to do just that, combining sector expertise with a broad geographical reach. We are also aware that a large number of corporate transactions these days trigger litigation and require litigation support in the preparatory and execution phases. We and our clients appreciate that an approach to a particular legal problem needs to be not only the best solution to that specific problem but also one that does not harm other aspects of the client's business.
Our experience enables us to find practical and tailored solutions to the problems of international corporate clients as well as smaller enterprises across all industry sectors.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>3c80ef9f-40de-4161-b7de-0b02ccf3f2d7</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>7a7028a8-8ba1-4a5f-a0dc-95c1b4785668</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>226</Id>
    <UniqueId>de00db00-65fc-4adf-bb73-effbea2fadba</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Corporate Governance and Compliance</PracticeName>
    <Text>Compliance issues are having an increasing impact on corporates globally.
We provide general company and compliance advice to our corporate clients on the legal issues which most regularly impact upon their businesses.  Across all of our offices we help our clients navigate the maze of legislation and best practice codes relevant to corporate governance and corporate responsibility.
Our boardroom practice covers addresses all elements of company law, from advice on board procedures to issues arising in takeover situations, as well as, analysing corporate policies, codes of conduct, and assistance with shareholder engagement. 
Our experts advise on domestic and international corporate issues including corporate law, sector-specific regulations, relevant listing rules, liability and risks for board directors and senior executives.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>c1dfcf43-52b9-45a5-b2a4-f6d192580e9a</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId />
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>227</Id>
    <UniqueId>5cf3d4b7-34fc-4061-9112-f20d2db9b346</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Corporate Occupiers and Leasing</PracticeName>
    <Text>Effectively managing operational real estate is an issue of strategic importance and can provide the foundation for future growth.
With vast experience in acting for both tenants and landlords, we have a real understanding of the issues our clients face in managing real estate and anticipating their future operational requirements. We specialise in acting for financial institutions and corporates on HQ relocations, data centres and office matters, and have advised on some of the most significant deals in the market in recent times.
In particular, we help clients with the negotiation of heads of terms and agreements to lease; the negotiation and agreement of commercial leases and all supporting documentation; exit issues relating to existing premises; and construction issues regarding fit-out by the landlord and/or tenant. Underpinning our advice is a unrelenting focus on ensuring the best possible commercial terms for our clients.
Our lawyers work closely with clients to identify provisions that could pose risks within a chosen strategy. These include financial obligations such as rent review, insurance and repair obligations. Having established whether the risk is reasonable, taking into account the market and other commercial factors, we work to agree the approach and mitigating factors that should be adopted in order to manage the risk. A material disruption to your business from the perspective of a landlord or tenant is likely to impact you economically. Our team’s prior experience of leading similar projects and working with other professional advisers means that our rigorous approach to project management allows your day-to-day operations to continue smoothly.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>015fd297-d550-47c0-b035-d2cf60446c86</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>2cd9e1b8-bcd7-4f4d-b63b-1f28018625b1</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>228</Id>
    <UniqueId>6168893b-8c5e-4df7-9921-b625dd02d0fb</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Corporate Trust and Agency</PracticeName>
    <Text>Integrated with the rest of our International Capital Markets practice, our Corporate Trustee group is ideally positioned as a key partner to the corporate trustee and agency services community and related counterparties in relation to all aspects of capital markets transactions. 
This is enhanced by our ability to provide specialist trustee and agency services advice in many of the key jurisdictions including the UK, Europe (including Germany and Italy), Asia (including Hong Kong, Singapore and Sydney) and the Middle East (through our office in Dubai).
We can advise on the full range of transactions, including:
new issues – including domestic and cross-border MTN programmes, ‘plain vanilla’ standalone corporate bonds, regulatory and hybrid capital issues, equity-linked corporate bonds, covered bonds, securitisations and all other forms of asset backed and structured finance
'after sales' advisory work – including in relation to defaults, restructurings, waivers, modifications and the general exercise of trustee powers and discretions
Due to recent market events, much of our current 'after sales' service is concentrated on downgrades, collateral postings, restructurings, enforcements, defaults, receiverships and related matters – we have extensive experience of the restructuring of debt issues and also accelerating debt issues and enforcing security (including liquidating assets) both at the trustee’s discretion and on direction from its beneficiaries with respect to both English and New York law transactions.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>033a4fb4-2e4e-4276-a1b1-4fb60e95ede5</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>dddbe240-d29a-43f7-922f-1dc914fc0e53</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>229</Id>
    <UniqueId>217d63e8-faa9-4934-a028-ff88e741d49c</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Covered Bonds</PracticeName>
    <Text>Working closely with the authorities, issuers and investment banks on the implementation of domestic legislation across numerous jurisdictions we have a deep appreciation of the issues encountered in the market and have worked on a variety of structures. 
As a result, we have advised on covered bond programmes not only in the core markets in Europe but across the globe both for structured and legislative covered bond transactions. We have a particular track record of advising on the first covered bonds programmes in markets, such as advising on the first covered bond programmes in Australia, Greece, Hungary, Italy, Korea, New Zealand, Switzerland and the UK. We have also acted on the establishment of covered bond programmes in Canada, Finland, France, Germany, the Netherlands, Norway, Spain, Sweden and the U.S. 
We also work with the broadest range of assets for inclusion in covered bond programmes including social housing loans, infrastructure loans, shipping loans commercial mortgages as well as residential mortgage loans.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>12d5d865-788d-4c14-be3f-60e7bb9e3086</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>dddbe240-d29a-43f7-922f-1dc914fc0e53</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>230</Id>
    <UniqueId>14f19ccd-4432-4d20-aa00-039614e4e580</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Data Protection</PracticeName>
    <Text>Across our international network, our data protection practitioners advise on all aspects of compliance with data privacy law.
We carry out cross-border data privacy surveys for clients, both to review their existing processes and procedures and to help set up new ventures.  With significant experience of designing, drafting, reviewing and updating general corporate group and HR policies, we support clients with whistle-blowing; employee telephone, internet and email use; customer data; cross-border data transfers; and data protection consents.  We also advise clients on the implications of freedom of information legislation, how to mitigate risk and the potential to use the legislation for competitive advantage.
Our team draws on specialists from a variety of complementary disciplines including employment and benefits, financial services, intellectual property, outsourcing,  regulatory and regulatory litigation and to deliver a comprehensive approach to our clients' data protection needs.
With strong working relationships with regulators across our network, we have developed a nuanced understanding of the attitude of regulators and to assist clients with risk-based analysis.  This means we provide our clients with a quick and efficient response – regardless of time zone.  Our global presence, together with the extensive experience of our integrated international data protection group, sets us apart from many of our competitors.  We have detailed experience in each jurisdiction, which brings valuable insight to managing the differing legal systems, cultures and regulatory regimes.
We are active participants in the privacy community, including the International Association of Privacy Professionals and regular speakers at industry events as well as contributing to industry publications.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>1e4332a6-4658-4c66-8c9b-3306d0758872</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>7e0fa517-f886-49c1-8d30-6474dd585171</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>231</Id>
    <UniqueId>c0a60543-2230-4e77-850f-e562b76e014b</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Debt Capital Markets</PracticeName>
    <Text>We advise issuers and underwriters on the full spectrum of debt capital market transactions, including standalone bonds and debt programmes, tier 1 and hybrid capital, equity-linked instruments, liability management, private placements, warrants, high yield and Islamic structures.
We have been instrumental in nearly all the major developments in the modern financial markets, starting with the first ever eurobond issue in the 1960s. Of the most recent developments, we have a particular track record in liability management, regulatory capital and capital raisings for financial institutions, debt issues by emerging markets issuers, sovereign debt offerings and we have been involved in numerous landmark transactions since the development of the offshore RMB market. Our excellence is reflected through our top tier position in all major legal directories, Thomson Reuters and Bloomberg debt legal adviser league tables and numerous independent market surveys and awards.
In addition to our DCM team in New York, we provide our clients with one of the deepest and most sophisticated U.S. practices on the ground in EMEA and Asia. Our team advises on the U.S. aspects of all debt capital market transactions, including SEC-registered offerings, Rule 144A and Regulation S offerings, high-yield offerings and convertible bonds. The team is further complemented by experts in U.S. tax, U.S. financial regulation and U.S. bankruptcy/restructuring.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>ca255a32-064a-4151-8486-c56aff4f9348</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>dddbe240-d29a-43f7-922f-1dc914fc0e53</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>232</Id>
    <UniqueId>056dd29a-d9f5-4d45-85e9-9e433a0623ae</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Derivatives and Structured Finance</PracticeName>
    <Text>Our advisory and transactional work covers all the major product types (exchange-traded or centrally cleared, OTC and securities) and all the underlying asset classes (currency, credit, equity, interest rate, commodity, energy, property, weather, fund, inflation).
More generally, we advise most of the financial institutions active in the market on the full range of product wrappers (including structured notes, certificates, warrants and funds) and underlyings (including equities, credit, commodities, FX, funds, indices and proprietary trading strategies). We advise on flow and highly bespoke structured products and are at the forefront of product development and regulatory and tax issues. More recently we have been involved with the developments on OTC clearing, advising on the relevant rules and procedures and on the impact the Dodd-Frank Act and proposed European derivatives legislation could have on clearing procedures.
Our role as European, Hong Kong and U.S. counsel to the International Swaps and Derivatives Association, Inc (ISDA) for many years, as well as our participation in other industry bodies means that we are at the forefront of the latest legal, regulatory and documentary developments and innovations in the marketplace. This ensures that we are up to speed with all relevant ISDA documentation and can deal with any ISDA-related queries or concerns our clients may have quicker and more efficiently than most of our competitors.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>91553ab5-463c-4c6e-9159-b25edf9fa428</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>dddbe240-d29a-43f7-922f-1dc914fc0e53</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>233</Id>
    <UniqueId>9b6fdc64-f920-4487-ad10-e9bcfa52812d</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>EHS Regulatory</PracticeName>
    <Text>Particular areas of strength include air and water pollution, waste management and shipment, land contamination, noise abatement and hazardous substances 
The global slowdown has led to significant corporate restructuring, plant closures and mothballing. Environmental issues are often a key consideration in these decisions given the need to minimise the environmental legacy and eliminate longer term risks.
We advise on health and safety issues in transactions and on a stand-alone basis. This ranges from strategic issues concerning board-level health and safety responsibilities to practical guidance over health and safety issues, relationships with contractors and health and safety-related proceedings.
We also assist on measures to prevent bribery and corruption issues connected to environmental and wider compliance matters.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>8fa9c80e-b51d-4e7d-91e1-ba6519d7e951</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>afb18bd5-bdd7-4cc3-a69b-bcb6997b5a6c</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>234</Id>
    <UniqueId>36836df4-800b-4094-92ed-5b584efc43f9</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Emerging Markets</PracticeName>
    <Text>Across our global network, we have a number of fee earners with a dedicated focus on emerging markets, who work together in a 'coverage model' approach across product lines and sectors. 
We cannot underestimate the importance of 'local' expertise on emerging markets transactions. Allen &amp;amp; Overy is one of a small number of firms that has embraced the ambition of being a truly global practice, with 43 offices spanning Latin America, Central and Eastern Europe, the Commonwealth of Independent States, Middle East, Africa, and Asia Pacific, among others. In particular, we assist clients in BRIC countries through our offices in Brazil, Russia and China.
In the remaining emerging markets jurisdictions where we do not have offices, we have highly developed relationships with a dense international network of relationship firms. This network guarantees consistency in approach, uniformly high standards and ensures that Allen &amp;amp; Overy remains synonymous with advanced legal thinking. Should you wish to, you can benefit from this network through Allen &amp;amp; Overy recommending firms to you in jurisdictions where you do not already instruct local counsel.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>2877744c-6ac0-4df3-96e9-d42e2d873655</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId />
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>235</Id>
    <UniqueId>32e21577-c5a2-4a4d-a7da-500602ef4051</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Employment</PracticeName>
    <Text>Understanding your obligations as an employer and recruiting, retaining and managing the right people, has never been more critical. Our clients come to us to help them manage their risks and provide strategic, board-level advice on crucial employment-related issues, as well as day-to-day support.
Many of our clients are heavily invested in globalisation and continue to expand their international platform. This means that workplace issues have multiple dimensions: at strategic level, at cross-border level and a local dimension on the ground. With over 110 employment lawyers in 23 countries across Europe, the Middle East, Asia Pacific and the U.S., we work in partnership with clients to develop individual, sophisticated and creative solutions to modern workplace issues. 
We advise on the full range of employment and benefits issues, local and global, advisory and transactional, and contentious and non-contentious. This includes advising on issues from working conditions, labour risk prevention, employee relations, HR policies and privacy, to restructuring, relationship breakdowns and dispute resolution. We're decisive. We recognise your commercial needs.
We are at the forefront of industry debate and market practice and supplement our expertise with critical sector knowledge, to find the right solution. Our team also pride themselves on being market-leaders in the use of technology to provide clients with products that deconstruct the complicated legal and regulatory hurdles across the globe, and then reconstruct them into simple and manageable reference toolkits.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>8834849e-be17-4b89-9730-f172bc2cc400</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>112e5e15-9144-48fb-8dd0-5c09eb1e53a3</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>236</Id>
    <UniqueId>c598fc15-a235-40bc-bcdf-46ec097d264d</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Employment and Benefits</PracticeName>
    <Text>Recognised as one of the market's top Employment and Benefits practices, we offer clients a truly integrated approach, with our experienced and highly regarded specialists in employment, incentives and pensions working closely together.
With over 180 lawyers in 26 countries across Europe, the Middle East, Asia Pacific and the U.S., our global practice is one of the best-resourced practices in its field. Our strong and renowned litigation capabilities result in a full service offering.
Our multi-jurisdictional capabilities have been consistently endorsed year-on-year in the legal directories, being top-ranked in the latest editions of Chambers Global as &amp;quot;an exceptional firm&amp;quot;. Many of our local practices also have leading rankings in their jurisdictions and are award winning. 30 of our partners and associates are recognised as leaders in their field across many prominent directories (Chambers Legal 500, PLC, Who's Who, and others).
Our team is renowned for being at the forefront of using innovative tools to assist clients to meet their needs and challenges on HR-related matters. With a client-centric approach  we cover not only standalone advisory and corporate transactional support but also provide clients with a more bespoke approach which includes providing training, regular legal bulletins and a broad range of value added services.
We are committed to the development of best practice within all three areas and devote a considerable amount of time and resources to training our lawyers to ensure our clients receive the best, practical and robust advice.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>112e5e15-9144-48fb-8dd0-5c09eb1e53a3</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId />
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>237</Id>
    <UniqueId>825d3792-4ad1-4c95-b64b-3766a0c7c106</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Employment Disputes</PracticeName>
    <Text>Our team has vast experience of advising clients on contentious issues, assisting clients before all national courts (as well as the European Court of Justice) and employment tribunals in the full range of individual and collective labour conflicts.
In an effort to reduce the financial burden of litigious action, we have noticed a trend in clients opting for alternative methods of dispute resolution and have recently worked on both tribunal-led and independent mediations.
We consider this standalone expertise to be a real strength of our practice where we add tangible value to clients, working with them to limit reputational and financial damage.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>1e39ff04-ee8d-43bf-b3e0-ab6787cfdb31</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>112e5e15-9144-48fb-8dd0-5c09eb1e53a3</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>238</Id>
    <UniqueId>9dc7fef4-e2b3-4e98-9aea-46e421483cf9</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Energy Disputes</PracticeName>
    <Text>The increasing incidence of state intervention, coupled with increased competition for resources and stronger regulation has also contributed to a rise in contentious matters. 
We have advised on many of the most high profile cases in this area, managing effectively and efficiently the many disputes where hundreds of millions of dollars are at stake, with significant volumes of documentation and complex, disputed facts. We have an outstanding record of assisting our clients in avoiding or resolving disputes and regulatory issues through negotiation, mediation, international arbitration, litigation, expert determination and other forms of alternative dispute resolution. 
Recognition for our work
&amp;quot;The firm provides 'full cross-sector support on oil and gas matters'; clients highlight its 'thorough capital markets, M&amp;amp;A and litigation expertise', while its projects and regulatory work 'sets the industry standard'.&amp;quot; Legal 500 2011 (Oil and Gas)
&amp;quot;Despite turbulent market conditions, this elite firm continues to perform strongly in the energy, projects and infrastructure sectors. Sources say: 'Allen &amp;amp; Overy's personal service is what sets it apart.' 'I am impressed by its perfect command of the project, the depth of legal investigations carried out and the quality of the work produced.'&amp;quot; Chambers Global 2011 (Projects and Energy)</Text>
    <TermStoreId>69797063-94a4-4077-84d5-c5b727bb1edb</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>7a7028a8-8ba1-4a5f-a0dc-95c1b4785668</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>239</Id>
    <UniqueId>9359e3ce-27c1-4231-89cf-7eecd52a9b7d</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Engineering, Procurement and Construction (EPC)</PracticeName>
    <Text>The core of its membership is located within the practice's Projects Group from where it provides the construction input in relation to major global projects across energy and infrastructure, such as the Jubail refinery project in Saudi Arabia the Simandou iron ore project and the Nizhnekamsk refinery project in Tatarstan, on PFI Projects such as the Dublin Metro, Mersey Gateway and the Buckinghamshire and Norfolk B waste-to-energy projects.
We have extensive experience in the entire range of construction-related projects, from large scale commercial and residential developments to highly complex multi-plant facilities.  We also have extensive experience in advising on all of the major standard form construction contracts, as well as on the most unique of bespoke construction contracts.  This range of experience permits us to structure contracting strategies which fit our clients' commercial and financial requirements regardless of the complexity of the chosen project or financing structure. 
Construction and engineering projects inevitably involve a number of risks, requiring the allocation of those risks and the negotiation of suitable contractual terms for their management. Our lawyers understand these risks and the methods for allocating and managing them. They also understand the significance of the construction arrangements within the wider project and are skilled in ensuring the appropriate allocation of construction risks to the party or parties best placed to manage those risks, so ensuring that the relevant project is bankable from a construction risk perspective. These skills also make us unique in identifying and quantifying risks for lenders to projects who require an analytical approach to their project risk diligence.  
Recent examples of our work
Jubail Oil Refinery - advised Saudi Aramco Total Refining and Petrochemical Company  (SATORP), in relation to the USD14.2bn greenfield refining and petro-chemical plant in Saudi Arabia. This deal had the largest deal value transaction of 2011 and was the winner of Middle East petro-chemicals deal of the year 2010 – PFI Awards 2011 and Middle East oil and gas deal of the year 2010, Project Finance
The Sur Power project in Oman
The Norfolk B waste to energy power project 
El Boleo Mining Project - advising Baja Mining Corp and Minera y Metalurgica del Boleo S.A. de C.V. on the USD1.04 billion greenfield Boleo mining project in Baja, Mexico. The project assembled diverse sources of debt, including Korea Development Bank in its first overseas natural resources financing, and was one of the largest financings for a Mexican mining project to date. The project also features the largest loan ever from U.S. Ex-Im Bank to a mining project, U.S. Ex-Im Bank’s fifth this year, after a long break from mining projects.

Recognition for our work 
A highlight for the Allen &amp;amp; Overy Construction Group was the publication in September by Sweet &amp;amp; Maxwell of &amp;quot;EPC Contracts and Major Projects (a guide to construction and other project contracts)&amp;quot;. This publication, which was authored by Nigel Pritchard, John Scriven and other members of the Allen &amp;amp; Overy Construction Group reinforces out reputation as the leading firm advising on Engineering, Procurement and Construction (EPC) Contracts.
&amp;quot;Clients appreciate the team's efficient and prompt turnaround of work while maintaining its reputedly high standards. The group's work in EPC projects is an outstanding feature.&amp;quot; - Chambers Global (Construction)</Text>
    <TermStoreId>bf8d42bf-a454-4706-8504-9f4becd66a24</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>9f06ba67-0792-49a7-aae5-b50ac5896363</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>240</Id>
    <UniqueId>65b1fe36-e589-4d8f-be6e-6227309e186d</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Environment</PracticeName>
    <Text>Likewise, developments in the climate change arena are raising new challenges for the business community. Regulatory demands, however, continue to widen in response to increasingly international environmental, human rights and trade concerns and present more and more compliance issues affecting both processes and products, as well as liability issues in business transactions. To steer successfully through this regulatory jungle requires specialist expertise on a global scale.
Allen &amp;amp; Overy’s Global Environmental and Regulatory Law Group includes more than 60 specialist, commercially focused environmental and regulatory law experts across the world advising on all aspects of environmental, product and trade law and liability. As one of the first law firms to develop a globally integrated environmental law practice, Allen &amp;amp; Overy is able to provide both transactional and stand alone advice in all the major areas of environmental and health and safety law at national, regional and international levels. We have long-standing expertise in a wide range of regulatory issues affecting our clients’ supply chains and the movement of our clients’ products around the World. We also regularly advise clients on the management of cross-border due diligence and on contractual negotiations in relation to major international acquisitions, disposals and infrastructure projects.
Our geographic reach, including the transfer of knowledge between different offices and jurisdictions, means that we are able to keep abreast of the latest environmental initiatives and legislative developments occurring around the globe. We closely track environmental policy, climate change and trade policy and regulatory developments and are in regular contact with policy makers and regulators whose work impacts our clients' interests. In addition to expertise in Allen &amp;amp; Overy’s own offices, by virtue of our network of specialist local firms in other jurisdictions, we can also ensure that you get high quality environmental and regulatory advice wherever in the world you need it.
With a mass of new and changing legislation in this area, the boardroom has never had so much reason to pay attention to human rights and other regulatory issues. SEC and new EU reporting requirements (and their global equivalents) on environmental issues, including obligations to report on environmental proceedings, impacts and standards in annual reports and on non-compliance more generally authorities, are just a couple of examples.
Allen &amp;amp; Overy’s environmental and regulatory law experts advise on all types of disclosure requirements and associated problems, such as commercial confidentiality. Whether the issue of disclosure arises in respect of a statutory or permit based obligation, as a result of a request from a regulator, or even under pressure from interested stakeholders, Allen &amp;amp; Overy’s sector specific knowledge helps clients grappling with the legal and commercial implications, particularly in relation to business sensitive matters.
The ability to obtain information from Government and public bodies which may concern your business or the business of others is both a positive and negative development. We can advise on exactly what &amp;quot;freedom of access to information&amp;quot; might mean for you, and how defences, like commercial confidentiality and national security, come into play.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>afb18bd5-bdd7-4cc3-a69b-bcb6997b5a6c</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId />
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>241</Id>
    <UniqueId>85bf33e4-3184-47ea-876f-adc35cac9ae8</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Environmental Disclosure</PracticeName>
    <Text>SEC reporting requirements on environmental issues, new EU transparency requirements and obligations to report on environmental impacts and standards in annual reports, are just a couple of examples. 
Allen &amp;amp; Overy’s environmental and regulatory law experts advise on all types of environmental disclosure requirements and associated problems, such as commercial confidentiality. Whether the issue of disclosure arises in respect of a statutory or permit based obligation, as a result of a request from a regulator or even under pressure from interested stakeholders, Allen &amp;amp; Overy’s sector specific knowledge helps clients grappling with the legal and commercial implications, particularly in relation to business sensitive matters. 
The ability to obtain information from government and public bodies which may concern your business or the business of others is both a positive and negative development. We can advise on exactly what &amp;quot;freedom of access to information&amp;quot; might mean for you, and how defences, like commercial confidentiality and national security, come into play</Text>
    <TermStoreId>025aec67-2ce1-4e1a-bafb-f7b1ba6e33f3</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>afb18bd5-bdd7-4cc3-a69b-bcb6997b5a6c</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>242</Id>
    <UniqueId>4cca5526-da89-4fb2-baa0-c9616936113e</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Environmental Litigation</PracticeName>
    <Text>With our strong sector knowledge, we combine environmental and litigation expertise to advise our clients in complex civil, criminal and administrative disputes and proceedings, expert determinations and arbitrations. In addition, our lawyers advise on public international environmental laws. 
We regularly advise on environmental indemnity and warranty disputes, third party civil actions and managing relationships with Governmental authorities.
Our environmental and litigation specialists also advise on administrative law matters, including judicial review (and equivalent) and have been successful in challenging environmental regulators on inappropriate use of, or interpretation of, their powers.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>86d0eab9-d805-4998-91c9-5a661d76bdca</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>7a7028a8-8ba1-4a5f-a0dc-95c1b4785668</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>243</Id>
    <UniqueId>5310643c-b93f-45a1-9dbf-2c6f3e0f1b6b</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Equity Capital Markets</PracticeName>
    <Text>Clients looking to raise capital in the financial market turn to us to provide sophisticated structuring solutions.  Our experience and knowledge means we are able to offer insightful and tailored legal advice coupled with efficient project management.
Our advice covers the full range of equity financing structures including initial public offerings, rights issues, secondary offerings, equity bridge financing, private placements and reverse takeovers. The majority of our transactions are cross-border in nature and require a co-ordinated approach across two or more of our offices.
Deeply embedded within our ECM practice, is a fully integrated U.S. offering. Our U.S. corporate finance lawyers advise on all aspects of U.S. securities law including SEC-registered offerings, Rule 144A and Regulation S offerings, American and Global Depositary receipts offerings, high-yield offerings, convertible bonds and equity warrants.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>9e7ae068-cdd5-4df1-98c6-3141ebf24e32</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>dddbe240-d29a-43f7-922f-1dc914fc0e53</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>244</Id>
    <UniqueId>1d61b39c-202c-48c9-8436-09681491f7ac</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Financial Services Regulation</PracticeName>
    <Text>Our Financial Services Regulatory team has over 80 lawyers across our office network, covering all of the world's principal financial markets. We are able to offer our clients expertise in the key regions, from our U.S. regulatory practice led from our New York and Washington D.C. offices and with U.S. regulatory lawyers based across our network, to a full-service coverage of the key European jurisdictions. We also have well established offices in the Middle East and Asia Pacific region that have been involved in setting up many of the regulatory systems that exist in those regions today. 
Our lawyers offer clients extensive regulatory experience and they lead thinking on regulatory developments, helping clients in lobbying on, planning for and implementing changes as they occur. Areas we advise on include bank regulation, capital and liquidity requirements, marketing and selling restrictions, clearing and settlement, custody and prime brokerage and recovery and resolution planning. As an international team we are very experienced in providing comprehensive surveys and comparative advice on regulatory matters that helps our clients decide where best to conduct their business and gives them a competitive advantage.
Recognition for our work
&amp;quot;This magic circle powerhouse offers its global clientele a superb service coupled with an impressive network, maintaining its position as one of the strongest choices for financial services work.&amp;quot; Chambers &amp;amp; Partners, 2013
&amp;quot;Allen &amp;amp; Overy is increasing its ability to advise on the interactions between US and EU reform, with a closer integration between its international offices, leading clients to state:'It is one of the only firms I have encountered that comes close to having a handle on the difficulties of managing cross-border legal and compliance risk.'&amp;quot; Chambers &amp;amp; Partners, 2013
&amp;quot;This international giant's impressive global reach and outstanding resources make it a natural choice for the giants of the financial services world when they face business critical issues.&amp;quot; Chambers &amp;amp; Partners, 2012 
&amp;quot;The group provides regulatory advice to the US operations of some of the most recognized financial institutions in the world, including RBS, UBS and BNP Paribas. It also serves as one of the primary outside counsel for SIFMA in relation to the SEC's new pay-to-play rules.&amp;quot; Chambers &amp;amp; Partners, 2013 
&amp;quot;[The US team] is a really skilled group; the premier firm in the country on any placement agent regulation.&amp;quot; - Chambers &amp;amp; Partners, 2013</Text>
    <TermStoreId>d1cbc3da-687a-4e1e-ba20-b33e827edddf</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>72cde3c8-471c-4823-bc1f-9acacb60631c</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>245</Id>
    <UniqueId>e2e99757-1981-462c-8650-89756b9c6aeb</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Financial Services Regulation and Investigations</PracticeName>
    <Text>As regulators around the world sharpen their focus on the financial sector, never before has a deep understanding of regulatory change across the full spectrum of banking, insurance and securities markets been so important.
As the alphabet soup of regulations targeting the financial sector grows, from Dodd-Frank to MiFID to AIFMD to Solvency II, our integrated, cross-disciplinary approach is ideally suited to advising our financial services clients across the world to navigate through the regulatory maze not only to protect their businesses from regulatory risk, but to position them to take advantage of emerging opportunities.
 
Whether you are an asset manager, bank, insurer, fund or other alternative capital provider, our international regulatory team offers clients extensive regulatory experience and they lead thinking on regulatory developments, helping clients in lobbying on, planning for and implementing changes as they occur. Areas we advise on include bank regulation, insurance regulation, capital and liquidity requirements, marketing and selling restrictions, clearing and settlement, custody and prime brokerage and recovery and resolution planning. As an international team we are very experienced in providing comprehensive surveys and comparative advice on regulatory matters that helps our clients decide where best to conduct their business and gives them a competitive advantage.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>72cde3c8-471c-4823-bc1f-9acacb60631c</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId />
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>246</Id>
    <UniqueId>c85ba8cf-a2f1-4ed0-8c9a-757d6dbb7ede</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Fraud</PracticeName>
    <Text>Our international network of offices and lawyers have experience of litigating in the key offshore jurisdictions in which the proceeds from fraud are usually held and are able to act quickly to freeze assets.
We have been involved in some of the largest international fraud cases. These include Maxwell, Madoff, Michael Brown, Solo Industries and KazakhGold.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>f1896ff3-0123-4ada-9ddd-834067f2f1d5</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>7a7028a8-8ba1-4a5f-a0dc-95c1b4785668</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>247</Id>
    <UniqueId>97a920cc-80c6-4de8-8a19-770b92f31e8e</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Freedom of Information</PracticeName>
    <Text>We have expertise in drafting requests for disclosure of material held by public bodies and in pursuing such requests if necessary on appeal.
We have specific experience of dealing with complaints to the UK Information Commissioner and appeals to the Information Tribunal. 
Our expertise also covers rights of access to environmental information and we have advised clients on issues relating to the disclosure of such material.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>203644fd-e590-4851-b7e7-fa71961ac016</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>e5f42143-a550-4fe5-84a5-6b5ada4229fb</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>248</Id>
    <UniqueId>4515f95c-20e5-41ba-8846-8411e4a632a9</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>General Lending</PracticeName>
    <Text>International financial institutions and 'blue chip' corporates continue to turn to Allen &amp;amp; Overy's General Lending practice in ever increasing numbers for assistance in structuring and documenting the most talked-about deals in the market. 
Deals today demand a broad mix of finance capabilities. Our corporate finance solutions offering includes an interdisciplinary team of lawyers from our General Lending, Capital Markets, Corporate and Restructuring teams. As a result, our coverage spans the spectrum of debt products, including a number of hybrid finance options such as bank/bond structures, high yield, LBOs, margin loans, IPOs and amend-and-extend/forward-start/refinancing facilities. The team has also advised on a number of firsts in the emerging markets, including advising on several of the biggest financings in emerging market jurisdictions to date. 
The practice offers exceptional market knowledge, built from a broad client base and extensive experience on 'big-ticket', cross-border deals, and a sophisticated practice in this area in all the world's leading banking centres. Our reputation as the premiere firm in this area is based on our commercial understanding of what our clients are trying to achieve, the quality of our documentation and our ability to deliver a high-value service within tight timeframes. Our longstanding presence at the top of the legal league tables shows that we have sustained this level of performance over many years.
Recognition for our work
&amp;quot;Its relationships with international banks and financial institutions have been built over many decades, and the firm acts on prestigious mandates across the world …&amp;quot; Chambers Global: Banking &amp;amp; Finance: Band 1: 2011
&amp;quot;Global titan Allen &amp;amp; Overy maintains its position among the market leaders in the high-end banking and finance space. 'We were very impressed with the creative ideas the team came up with. They work together across the globe using their excellent knowledge of the market to ensure a smooth and seamless transaction'.&amp;quot; Chambers UK: Banking and Finance: Band 1: 2012
Clients commend the team’s ‘industry knowledge’, ‘quality of advice’ and ‘international capabilities’.&amp;quot; Legal 500, Asia Pacific, 2012, Banking and Finance, Band 1</Text>
    <TermStoreId>269839c1-e72e-4573-b9d8-1be8884da645</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>7891e92d-9a8b-4dfa-8b4f-f45d51f09808</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>249</Id>
    <UniqueId>5c7725c8-0752-47b5-b2fb-e923ffdf3fbc</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Government Owned Assets</PracticeName>
    <Text>These assets usually include land, moveable property and intellectual property rights, among others.
In continental Europe, for example, we advise our clients on the differences between public domain goods and other public property, on their use, temporary assignment and, in certain cases, their transfer.
A major issue we regularly advise on is expropriation procedures, ie providing insight into the ways public authorities can forcefully purchase private land for public use or in the social interest, in particular with regard to infrastructure projects, such as new toll roads, train lines, airports. 
We also advise on the assignment of land from public authorities to third parties, who receive the right to use the land or to operate a certain service on the land for a specific period of time, after which the right to use the land reverts to the public authorities.  
With regard to land-planning issues, we provide expert advice on different land-planning procedures and the ways in which temporary rights may be granted to private parties for specific activities relating, in particular, to the urbanisation of land.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>a7193725-f4e2-45c3-bf9c-07126ff46f6e</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>e5f42143-a550-4fe5-84a5-6b5ada4229fb</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>250</Id>
    <UniqueId>397d4100-df1d-4aea-bcad-8cb90103876a</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Green Real Estate</PracticeName>
    <Text />
    <TermStoreId>49907317-0c0b-4956-8721-2e7db711b6d5</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>afb18bd5-bdd7-4cc3-a69b-bcb6997b5a6c</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>251</Id>
    <UniqueId>8771a088-e3fb-4fde-b975-47d7ae95c795</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>High Yield</PracticeName>
    <Text>Our lawyers have led many of the deals that have shaped and continue to influence the direction of the European high yield market, including working on some of the biggest and most prestigious deals to come to the market since the beginning of 2000.
We combine our high yield practice with our market-leading practices in banking and leveraged finance and debt capital markets. Our High Yield team also works closely with our corporate, restructuring and private equity groups. We believe this makes us one of the very few law firms that has the ability to cover all aspects of complicated leveraged finance high yield transactions and crossover and emerging markets high yield transactions. 
Our combined bank/bond team can service all requirements in relation to high yield debt offerings, senior, second-lien, mezzanine and PIK debt, bridge-to-bond financings, bank/bond financings, securitisation take-outs, debt buy-backs and restructurings. 
Our high yield and European debt capital markets practices integrate to cover crossover and emerging market credits. These deals can be governed by New York law indentures or English law trust deeds and/or executed following the eurobond or U.S. style offering paradigms.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>fba7a8a5-d448-4265-b1cf-49fdbc59cccd</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>dddbe240-d29a-43f7-922f-1dc914fc0e53</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>252</Id>
    <UniqueId>a0b69f82-46c3-479c-806c-8316a121f871</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Human Rights</PracticeName>
    <Text>United Nations Secretary-General, Ban Ki-moon, Human Rights Day 2011
As an organization working everyday in interpreting and applying complex laws, we know the importance of enforceable laws. 
We are passionate about using our professional expertise to give resonance to human rights; to ensure that they are not 'just words'. 
Human Rights Working Group: firm-wide 
Now in its second year, our Human Rights Working Group co-ordinates and develops the human rights work undertaken by our lawyers in jurisdictions around the world. The Executive Committee, headed up by Andrew Denny, one of the firm's London Litigation Partners, formulates policy and strategy to guide our human rights work.
Members of the Human Rights Working Group deliver training for (and with) Allen &amp;amp; Overy's clients on human rights compliance. We advise commercial clients on their human rights policies, particularly in the light of the adoption by the UN Human Rights Council of the Guiding Principles on Business and Human Rights (known as the 'Ruggie Principles'), and the applicability to their business of instruments such as the European Convention on Human Rights and the Charter of Fundamental Rights. We are also proud to publish the &amp;quot;Business and Human Rights Review&amp;quot;, which provides a key forum for the exchange of ideas in relation to the challenges faced by businesses in seeking to prevent adverse human rights impacts arising from or connected with their activities. As a business, Allen &amp;amp; Overy also faces these same issues itself, and the Human Rights Working Group is currently engaged in the process of investigating what implementing the Ruggie Principles would involve for Allen &amp;amp; Overy worldwide. We also assist human rights charities and international non-governmental organisations pro bono in the delivery of their work, for example, by representing marginalised communities in court, submitting interventions and amicus curiae briefs and undertaking international comparative research projects to inform policy work. 
Allen &amp;amp; Overy is well placed to use its position as an international business with core expertise in Public Law to achieve high impact results for its clients and for charities and international non-governmental organisations. We believe that everyone should have access to justice and legal representation. Here are some examples of our pro bono human rights work:
Acting for segregated Roma children: Budapest office
For five years, lawyers in our Budapest office worked on an important test case brought by Hungarian NGO, the Chance for Children Foundation. Allen &amp;amp; Overy represented several Roma people (an ethnic minority) pro bono in their dispute with the city of Miskolc, in relation to the segregation of Roma children in schools. The Supreme Court recognised the unlawful segregation of the children represented in the case as well as its detrimental effects upon their education and in an unprecedented decision awarded damages to each child. The landmark ruling could benefit more than 150,000 Roma students in Hungary.
Defending the rights of Guantanamo Bay detainees:  New York office
Our New York litigation department represents a number of Yemeni citizens detained at Guantanamo Bay in federal habeas corpus proceedings. The team working on these cases have participated in the briefing of several appeals concerning the rights of non-citizens who are alleged “enemy combatants”. The team also represented the Human Rights Institute of the International Bar Association and filed amicus curiae briefs to the U.S. Supreme Court in the Guantanamo Bay detainee litigation.
Human rights support and strategic litigation: London office
Our lawyers regularly work with organisations such as Liberty, INTERIGHTS, Fair Trials International and Amicus. Lawyers in our London office undertake detailed intervention work for Bail for Immigration Detainees (BID), a charity challenging UK immigration detention, recently working with them to intervene in a case before the UK Supreme Court.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>da8799aa-c524-4795-854d-f740aba48d03</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>e5f42143-a550-4fe5-84a5-6b5ada4229fb</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>253</Id>
    <UniqueId>6011511f-f56a-44ac-a3e3-9aeb1da36644</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Incentives</PracticeName>
    <Text>Staying on top of frequent changes in legislation and market practice is a crucial part of any employer's business and fundamental in managing reputational risk, particularly for remuneration committees.
Our global team of over 115 incentives experts across 20 countries specialises in the key aspects of this area such as tax, company, securities and regulatory law, as well as monitoring market practice developments.
In the past 12 months, we have advised on the operation of share plans in over 75 jurisdictions ranging from Azerbaijan to Australia. Our global offices and our network of relationship firms enables us to offer our clients outstanding global coverage. We work seamlessly in collaboration with our employment, corporate and banking colleagues to ensure our clients receive the highest quality advice.
Experienced in share plan design, we regularly advise clients on the impact of corporate transactions on share plans. Our proactive analysis of market practice and data means, which enables us to provide our clients with practical and commercial expert advice.
We are constantly seeking ways to be innovative and develop online tools to assist our clients to work as efficiently as possible. This includes our leading product Global Shareweb and also our more recently launched GlobalView online tool.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>c4efe77b-b32b-406e-82a3-74eb5fd0a53a</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>112e5e15-9144-48fb-8dd0-5c09eb1e53a3</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>254</Id>
    <UniqueId>f3bb5b28-ed7c-4e71-807a-441dde799cc9</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Insurance</PracticeName>
    <Text>Expertise covers restructuring of regulatory capital, strategic reinsurance, longevity transactions, M&amp;amp;A and regulatory matters. 
Fully integrated with the firm's global Financial Institutions Group, the team advise financial institution clients on all insurance aspects of property, project and real estate financings and transactions. The team also advise our financial institution clients in respect of their own trade credit and political risk insurance policies. 
The group advise a number of investment banks in respect of trading longevity risks with banks, insurers and investment schemes, as well as advising insurers and investment banks on regulatory capital and liquidity transactions.  We advise in the companies market and at Lloyd's. In addition to advising financial institutions, local and multinational companies and government bodies, a number of our team have spent time in industry, with insurance regulators or as underwriters. The team has the specialist product knowledge you would expect of a market leading insurance team, coupled with a well-rounded view of the sector to provide our clients with commercially relevant advice in the most efficient manner.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>8895b5c5-b35f-42e6-883d-9017b5d154b6</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId />
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>255</Id>
    <UniqueId>fec3c447-fd86-487b-bd2c-ff327d55424d</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Insurance Capital Markets and Derivatives</PracticeName>
    <Text>There is a current focus on concerns around liquidity and systemic risk arising from connections between insurers and banks and also insurer’s preparations for Solvency II.  It is essential for lawyers to combine an understanding of regulatory policy objectives, with the ability to provide rapid and effective execution. We have taken a leading role in developing transaction structures with insurers and banks and negotiating appropriate regulatory treatment with regulators. 
Our Insurance Capital Markets Group  advise on all aspects of insurance-related financings, regulatory capital trades, longevity risk transactions, transformer and reverse transformer structures, catastrophe bonds and CDO/securitisation structures. 
This team of leading insurance and derivatives and structured finance specialists regularly advises on complex transactions in conjunction with tax, banking regulatory, IP and pensions lawyers across our global network. We are adept at providing solutions to complex issues through our understanding of the cultural differences between insurers and investment banks; the way they view and manage risk, the commercial issues they face and the regulatory environments in which they operate. 
We advise on structuring and negotiating a range of tailored insurance products and solutions which are sensitive to credit, operational and reputational risks. Many of our clients’ transactions involve complex and multi-jurisdictional security and other collateral arrangements.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>800e7eb8-500a-4364-85f9-376b59d5aa42</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>8895b5c5-b35f-42e6-883d-9017b5d154b6</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>256</Id>
    <UniqueId>1007a86d-571e-4926-8c99-f6f0f410a936</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Insurance Disputes</PracticeName>
    <Text>Sadly, but possibly inevitably, insurance policies can lead to coverage disputes. We specialise in advising on the resolution of large and difficult claims from the London and international insurance market, and in the defence of claims against companies and their directors which are insured under all types of liability insurance policies.
There is no better place for insurance buyers to come for help with their serious problem claims: we understand the market well; we give good, practical advice; and we have a terrific track record. As insurance policies increasingly require arbitration of disputes, especially in London, our top-tier arbitration expertise plays to our strengths in this area, as does our international reach in dealing with cross-jurisdictional problems that often arise with globally placed insurance programmes. Our recent and current casework in this area includes representing:
A major bank in recovering under its policy of civil liability insurance for settlements of U.S. investor claim actions seeking billions of dollars in damages and associated defence costs. The claim gave rise to complex issues as to the scope of coverage, public policy and choice of law.
A major UK Plc on its Financial Risk Insurance Programme (FRIP) relating to a significant part of its business. The case was one of the most high profile and complex insurance arbitrations in the market. The case was settled to our client's satisfaction, after claims as to the invalidity of the policy and certain of its key terms were defeated. It was described by the tribunal as among the most testing it had ever encountered.
Three banks in seeking recovery under political risk insurance policies following default on substantial loans made to an Indian infrastructure product.
 
Recognition for our work
Ranked 1st tier in the Insurance Litigation: Policyholder category. &amp;quot;At Allen &amp;amp; Overy, Joanna Page heads the Insurance Litigation practice, and Judith Gill QC and Richard Smith are ‘professional and knowledgeable’ in exercising ‘judgement and case leadership’. The team is ‘first choice in acting for insureds’ against Bermudan insurance companies.&amp;quot; The Legal 500 UK 2010/11 
&amp;quot;This firm fields a powerful cross-border litigation team, with strong capacity across its many European offices. The London and Amsterdam teams are particularly highly regarded among peers and clients. Sources say: 'They are very good in just about everything they do; I get up an hour earlier if I have a dispute against them'.&amp;quot; Chambers &amp;amp; Partners Global 2011</Text>
    <TermStoreId>95660b06-b016-438d-b666-4ec2cad22345</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>7a7028a8-8ba1-4a5f-a0dc-95c1b4785668</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>257</Id>
    <UniqueId>3ed064fd-574b-4233-bd6f-c36b3389e26c</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Insurance M＆A</PracticeName>
    <Text>Financial institutions, including insurers, are at the heart of our practice.  We routinely advise leading insurance and reinsurance clients on their strategic M&amp;amp;A transactions as well as structural reorganisations; including the divestment and purchase of life operations and policy portfolio transfers via schemes of arrangement. 
We are regularly involved in arrangements for the purchase of large books of life policies in run-off, including the regulatory and asset management aspects. The group has also advised on precedent-setting pension scheme liability transfer transactions.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>9d43404c-73cb-43e4-aa8c-e9e9e8b220c6</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>8895b5c5-b35f-42e6-883d-9017b5d154b6</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>258</Id>
    <UniqueId>6d1d3e5b-6de3-4b41-a4ab-c219d86daae4</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Insurance Regulatory and Compliance</PracticeName>
    <Text>We regularly advise regulators and governments, as well as insurers and reinsurers in relation to regulatory issues.  We cover the full range of regulatory matters from authorisation, governance and solvency to engagement with supervisors. In a transactional context, our regulatory experts help manage execution risk associated with complex deals, often involving multiple regulated sectors and jurisdictions. 
Our team is heavily engaged in advising in relation to Solvency II and work closely with clients, trade associations and regulators to help shape the regulatory agenda.  Our Regulatory Investigations group advises companies and individuals involved in FSA investigations and enforcement proceedings.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>32988162-1287-43ab-bcf5-51837cce4cd5</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>8895b5c5-b35f-42e6-883d-9017b5d154b6</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>259</Id>
    <UniqueId>721b406e-88c1-45e0-bb50-8b288f5d461b</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Intellectual Property</PracticeName>
    <Text>With nearly 100 specialist IP partners and associates in all, we offer an integrated, cross-border service to meet our clients' global needs as well as specialist advice and representation in individual countries.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>ead974a2-95a8-4128-afb5-b493481bf45d</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId />
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>260</Id>
    <UniqueId>8654696f-b84c-4b6f-b19d-d5cf5f3d5b91</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Intellectual Property Disputes</PracticeName>
    <Text>Our IP teams understand how to exploit the procedural and tactical possibilities these forums offer in terms, for example, of securing evidence or obtaining fast interim relief or a speedy hearing. This enables us to co-ordinate litigation and settlement strategies to achieve the right business outcome for our clients.
Frequently, a firm technical understanding is crucial to securing success. Many of us have technical backgrounds and industry experience and can advise with confidence in cases involving the most complex technology.  
Antitrust issues are also increasingly important in IP litigation: we work together with our top-tier antitrust practice which includes leading practitioners with specific IP experience.
Our litigation experience spans all areas of intellectual property. For example, we frequently act in:
Major multi-jurisdictional patent litigation both in the life sciences and technology areas.
Trade mark litigation at the highest levels, including before the Court of Justice of the European Union.
Disputes relating to trade secrets, particularly in the financial and telecoms fields.
Copyright disputes, often with an emphasis on digital rights, jurisdictional and antitrust issues.
Disputes relating to transit trade, anti-counterfeiting campaigns and action to prevent parallel imports.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>b995bb69-63d3-42cd-852f-0f9e9a74d488</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>ead974a2-95a8-4128-afb5-b493481bf45d</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>261</Id>
    <UniqueId>475c0010-5a6e-4b30-8359-c383fbe7b739</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>International Arbitration</PracticeName>
    <Text>We act as advocates, sit as arbitrators, and are able to act in arbitrations arising anywhere in the world, under any national legal system as well as public international law. Our experience includes litigation in support of arbitration.   
Through our research, publications, conference papers, and contributions to working groups, we contribute to the development of international arbitration.
Recent examples of our work
Recent examples of our work include representing:
A major multinational in a series of arbitrations against its insurers for reimbursement of various U.S. product liability claims arising from the use of a pharmaceutical product. The coverage claims arise under the Bermuda Form policy, with which Allen &amp;amp; Overy has extensive expertise. The arbitrations involve complex issues of pharmaceutical regulation (including by the FDA), new drug applications, pre-clinical and clinical studies, epidemiological studies, adverse event reporting, post-market surveillance, product labelling and warnings, pharmaceutical marketing, and mass tort pharmaceutical litigation in the U.S.  The underlying product liability claims exceed USD1 billion.
Four different Asia based banks in separate LCIA arbitrations arising under ISDA master agreements against counterparties, including obtaining anti-suit injunctive relief from the English courts. We are at the forefront of resolving derivatives disputes through international arbitration.
A Middle Eastern company in connection with a series of gas price adjustments under a long-term energy supply contract governed by New York law under ICC arbitration rules with a Geneva seat. 
Recognition for our work
“Its expertise in oil and gas disputes is remarked upon, as is its long-standing involvement in the banking and finance sphere. The 37-partner team continues to attract some eye-catching mandates under the ICSID, LCIA, and ICC systems as well as under the Energy Charter Treaty.” - International arbitration, Chambers Global 2013</Text>
    <TermStoreId>d63bf062-4850-44f2-ae22-28a28e00c6b7</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>7a7028a8-8ba1-4a5f-a0dc-95c1b4785668</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>262</Id>
    <UniqueId>c56187a6-f814-4d50-a2ba-4140c90f7a42</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Investment Treaty Arbitration</PracticeName>
    <Text>Our experience includes bringing the very first arbitration under the Energy Charter Treaty. We have excellent experience in handling arbitration proceedings under both the ICSID Convention and the UNCITRAL Arbitration Rules. We act for both investors and states. 
Recent examples of our work
A group of funds v. Kingdom of Spain, in claims under the Energy Charter Treaty relating to multiple investments in the concentrated solar power and wind sectors, made on the basis of a regime designed to encourage investments in the Spanish renewable energy sector. The claim arises out of Spain’s legislative and regulatory measures affecting renewable energy projects. 
Baggerwerken Decloedt En Zoon NV, a subsidiary of one of the world’s largest dredging companies, in a dispute with the Republic of the Philippines concerning the wrongful cancellation of a contract to dredge the Laguna Lake, outside of Manila. 
Recognition for our work “ Investment treaty work is held to be its forte” - Public international law, Chambers UK 2014</Text>
    <TermStoreId>42ce43f5-4325-4c18-92f9-47770ed48af5</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>7a7028a8-8ba1-4a5f-a0dc-95c1b4785668</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>263</Id>
    <UniqueId>311677fe-1354-4fcf-8d4a-9a2ecb5658f3</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Islamic Finance</PracticeName>
    <Text>Islamic Capital Markets
The sukuk practice forms part of Allen &amp;amp; Overy's award-winning International Capital Markets practice which has enjoyed a long established reputation for its global reach and top tier position across the full range of financial products. 
Sukuk are Shari'a-compliant certificates which are issued in order to raise finance in a Shari'a-compliant manner and, like conventional bonds, can be listed on international exchanges and, if structured properly, will be tradable instruments in the international markets.  However, there are also significant differences between sukuk and conventional bonds, including the fact that sukuk, as trust certificates, are not debt instruments and instead convey a beneficial ownership interest in one or more underlying assets. 
In addition, the periodic payments on sukuk are not interest but instead represent a return earned through the underlying assets, for example on an ijara (lease) based sukuk the periodic return represents the rental payments made on the underlying lease.
“ ...sukuk, for which the firm is often rated 'the best in the world'. ”  - Chambers UK 2009, Islamic Finance 
“ Allen &amp;amp; Overy LLP is superb for sukuk, and 'demonstrates excellent legal knowledge and extremely strong industry knowledge. ”  - The Legal 500, United Kingdom 2011 
Key Islamic Capital Markets contacts


 

Market-first transactions
Our specialist global Islamic capital markets team consists of lawyers who are considered by independent directories and publications as the leading lawyers in the world for advising on sukuk transactions. The team has advised issuers (whether corporates, banks, governments or supranationals), managers and delegates on the most high profile and innovative transactions, many of which are market-firsts.

Global sukuk experience

Islamic Project Finance
We advise all parties in projects including sponsors, financiers and ECAs.We advise all sectors on some of the largest and most complicated project finance transactions.We advise on all elements of project transactions - project structures, conducting legal due diligence, risk allocation and reviewing the 'bankability' of project agreements.
“With strong Islamic finance capabilities in Dubai, Riyadh, Doha and London, A &amp;amp; O covers a multitude of Shari'a-complaint products and can advise MENA-based and overseas clients on all of their needs in this arena. ”  - Chambers Global 2011
Key Islamic Project Finance contacts


 
Deal highlights
Sipchem Hanwha Polymers Project, Saudi Arabia
We advised the financiers on the project financing of an ethylene vinyl acetate and low density polyethylene plant in Jubail Industrial City, Saudi Arabia. The project was sponsored by Saudi International Petrochemical Company and Hanwha Chemical Corporation. The transaction included an istisn’a facility from commercial banks as well as financing from Saudi Industrial Development Fund of Saudi Arabia and Public Investment Fund of the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia.
SAMAPCO Petrochemical Project, Saudi Arabia
We advised Sahara and Ma’aden Petrochemicals Company, a joint venture company formed by Sahara Petrochemical Company and Saudi Arabian Mining Company Ltd (Ma’aden), in connection with the SAMAPCO Petrochemical Project in Jubail, Saudi Arabia, involving SIDF, PIF and Islamic bank funding. 
Quarayyah IPP, Saudi ArabiaWe advised the lenders (including EDC and US EX-IM) to a consortium of bidders led by AES on the Al Qurayyah IPP in Saudi Arabia, the third in the SEC IPP programme. 
Al Sufouh Transit System, UAE We advised the mandated lead arrangers in respect of an export credit agency (COFACE and ONDD) supported loan package and two Islamic facilities (AED and USD denominated) utilising an ijara structure for the Department of Finance, acting on behalf of the Government of Dubai, in an aggregate amount of approximately USD674m. 
Jubail Refinery Petrochemicals Project, Saudi Arabia The Jubail Refinery USD8.5bn project financing was particurarly notable for the complexity raised by having many different facilities in a single financing, including USD and SAR facilities provided under two Islamic structures (an istisna-ijara and a wakala-ijara) and a sukuk issue.
Saudi Kayan Petrochemical Project, Saudi ArabiaWe advised in relation to the USD10bn Saudi Kayan petrochemicals complex at Jubail including PIF, 4 ECAs (ECGD, KEIC, K-EXIM and SACE), Islamic (including a murahaba facility provided by Al Rajhi Bank) and commercial bank financing. 
Emirates Steel Industries Expansion Project, UAEWe advised the lead arrangers in the Islamic and conventional co-financing of Emirates Steel Industries expansion project in Abu Dhabi. 
Shuqaiq Water and Electricity Company, Saudi Arabia We advised on the USD1.8bn financing of the Shuqaiq power generation and water desalination plant in Saudi Arabia. The transaction included a USD142m Islamic tranche. 
Sipchem, Saudi ArabiaWe advised on the Islamic refinancing of the International Methanol Company project in Jubail.
Saudi Polyolefins Company, Saudi ArabiaWe advised on the USD175m murahaba facility USD400m ijara facilities.
Al Qatrana IPP, Jordan We advised the successful bidder (a consortium comprising Xenel and Kepco) on the Al Qatrana IPP in Jordan. The financing involved direct conventional facilities from KEXIM and Proparco, a facility covered by KEXIM and provided by BNP Paribas and KfW and an Islamic tranche from Islamic Development Bank. 
Target Line O&amp;amp;G Project, LibyaWe advised Kuwait Finance House in relation to its financing on a murahaba basis of an acquisition of an oil rig for use in Libya.
Zayed University PPP Project, UAE We advised on the USD1bn PPP project entailing the development of the Zayed University on a 28-year concession, located in New Capital District, near Abu Dhabi International Airport. The financing involved an AED520m senior Islamic tranche provided by Al Hilal Bank.
Taweelah, UAE We advised the Islamic banks on the USD150m Islamic finance tranche of the USD500m refinancing of the Taweelah A2 power generation and desalination plant in Abu Dhabi. 
Islamic Banking
Our team offers clients advice on a broad spectrum of banking transactions with a particular focus on large-scale Islamic financings. 
The breadth of our expertise in banking-related fields is demonstrated by the calibre of transactions on which we have advised. Some of the major Shari’a-compliant transactions on which we have recently advised can be found below. “ This firm offers the best of both worlds for clients seeking a keen understanding of local law coupled with a highly regarded international transactions practice. ”  - Chambers Global 2011 UAE
Key Islamic Banking contacts


Deal highlights
Dubai Aerospace Enterprise, UAEWe advised the borrower on the refinancing of its facilities. 
Derindere Turizm Otomotiv San Tic A.Ş. , TurkeyWe advised Citi as arranger on the USD60m murabaha facility for Derindere Turizm Otomotiv San Tic A.Ş. 
Arabian Petroleum Investments Corporation, Saudi ArabiaWe advised Riyad Bank, Banque Saudi Fransi, The Saudi British Bank and Al-Rajhi Bank, as mandated lead arrangers on the SAR2.5bn murabaha facility for Arabian Petroleum Investments Corporation (APICORP). 
Etihad Etisalat (Mobily), Saudi ArabiaWe advised Al Rajhi Banking &amp;amp; Investment Corporation, Banque Saudi Fransi, Riyad Bank, Samba Financial Group, Saudi Hollandi Bank, The National Commercial and The Saudi British Bank, as mandated lead arrangers on the SAR10bn financing for Etihad Etisalat (Mobily), one of the largest general syndicated Islamic financing deals to date. 
Marafiq, Qatar We advised Bank Saudi Fransi, Samba Financial Group, The National Commercial Bank, The Saudi British Bank and Al-Rajhi Bank, as mandated lead arrangers on the SAR4.5bn murabaha facility for Marafiq. 
 
GEMS MENASA, UAEWe advised GEMS MENASA in its capacity as borrower in respect of a AED2bn financing. The financing consisted of conventional facilities, musharaka facilities and murabaha facilities which were all governed by a Common Terms Agreement.
 
Emaar Malls, UAEWe advised Standard Chartered Bank, Dubai Islamic Bank and National Bank of Abu Dhabi as arrangers of the AED3.6 billion dual tranche conventional and Islamic sherkat-ul-melk facility for Emaar Malls LLC (Islamic Finance News' Corporate Finance Deal of the Year 2011).&amp;quot;
 
Al Noor Group, UAEWe advised Standard Chartered Bank, HSBC and Mashreqbank as lead arrangers on a dual USD and AED currency murabaha facility for the Al Noor Group.
 
Al Raya for Foodstuff Company Ltd., Saudi ArabiaWe advised Al Raya for Foodstuff Company Ltd and the sponsors Levant Capital and CVCI on the dual tranche USD13 million and SAR75 million Islamic murabaha facility made available by UBS and National Commercial Bank.
 
Saudi Oger, Saudi ArabiaWe advised Alinma Bank on a SAR2.6 billion bai al-ajal facility and SAR993 million performance bond facility for Saudi Oger Limited both for the purposes of the MoI KAP2 project in the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia.
Emirates, UAEWe advised Emirates on an AED1 billion Islamic ijara facility made available by Dubai Islamic Bank.
  Mubadala Pramerica Real Estate Investors, UAE
We advised Mubadala Pramerica Real Estate Investors (MPREI) on the AED240m ijara financing entered into with ADCB to acquire three properties on Saadiyat Island, Abu Dhabi.Aldar Etihad Investment Properties LLC, UAE We advised Aldar Etihad Investment Properties LLC on the AED785m financing of its acquisition of the Abraj Towers residential real estate project in Abu Dhabi. The financing involved a conventional term loan facility and a commodity murabaha facility. 
Sorouh, UAEWe advised Sorouh on the AED2.7bn conventional and Islamic term loan and revolving facility secured by mortgages over certain of Sououh’s real estate assets. 
ENOC, UAE We advised the banks as the mandated lead arrangers on a dual currency USD500m syndicated Islamic financing for ENOC Supply &amp;amp; Trading LLC. 
Limitless, UAE We advised Emirates Islamic Bank and Emirates Bank International on a USD1.2bn dual currency mudaraba facility for Limitless LLC, a subsidiary of Dubai World, the proceeds of which will be used to fund landmark real estate projects being developed in Dubai and Riyadh. 
Aldar, UAE We advised Aldar Properties PJSC, the Abu Dhabi-based property developer, on an AED2.203bn (USD600m) ijara facility. 
Al Raha Beach Development, UAE We advised Dubai Islamic Bank and others as arrangers in relation to a USD2.1bn ijara and conventional co-financing for the Al Raha Beach development in Abu Dhabi.
Islamic Derivatives and Structured Finance
Our Islamic derivatives and structured finance practice is a market leader and is made up of lawyers from a number of jurisdictions who are both derivatives and structured finance experts and Islamic finance experts. It also benefits from the support and broad expertise of our wider top tier global derivatives and structured finance practice.
Our team has advised on some of the most innovate Shari'a-compliant OTC derivatives transactions as well as Shari'a-compliant transactions as well as Shari'a-compliant structured products and has extensive experience in structuring such products.
Whilst most of the deals in this area are of a private nature, examples of types of Shari'a-compliant transactions on which we have advised can be found below. Key Islamic Derivatives and Structured Finance contacts


Deal highlights
EquityWe have advised on a wide range of Shari'a-compliant equity derivatives products, including puts, calls, collars and total return swaps on shares, share baskets and indices both on a standalone basis and as part of wider financing transactions. We have also advised on Shari'a-compliant equity-linked and index-linked certificates.
Template DocumentationWe have drafted template Shari'a-compliant derivatives and collateral documentation for a number of institutions, including local and international banks and corporates.
Rates and FXWe have advised a number of financial institutions on profit rate swaps and Shari'a-compliant FX transactions on a standalone basis and as part of wider financing transactions (including Shari'a-compliant securitisations). We have also advised on rates and FX products under Shari'a-compliant structured products platforms.
Structured Products PlatformsWe have advised a number of banks, including Deusche Bank, Standard Chartered and HSBC on setting up their Shari'a-compliant structured products platforms which cater for the full range of structured products payoffs in a Shari'a-compliant format.
CommoditiesWe have advised on a variety of Shari'a-compliant commodity derivatives products including commodity based indices.
CreditWe have advised on variety of Shari'a-compliant credit-linked notes, including swapsm credit-linked notes and credit-linked repos. 
Repo TransactionsWe have advised on a number of Shari'a-compliant repo transactions based on the collaterised murabaha structure. 
Our news 
The 6 March 2010 edition of International Financing Review includes an article on the ISDA/IIFM Tahawwut Master Agreement in which associate Yusuf Battiwala is quoted commenting on the development of the market. 
The 1 March 2010 edition of Risk Magazine includes an article on the ISDA/IIFM Tahawwut Master Agreement in which Allen &amp;amp; Overy is quoted commenting on the close-out mechanism. 
The 29 June 2009 edition of Financial News includes an article on the development of the Islamic Finance market in which partner Anzal Mohammed and associate Yusuf Battiwala are quoted. 
The 17 January 2009 edition of International Financing Review includes an article on the Al Miyar programme, a Shari'a-compliant structured products programme developed by Deutsche Bank, in which associate Yusuf Battiwala and partner Andrew Sulston are quoted. 
The 14 November 2009 edition of International Financing Review includes an article on Shari'a-compliant derivatives in which partner Richard Tredgett and associate Yusuf Battiwala are quoted commenting on the Master Agreement for Shari'a-compliant derivatives. Access by subscription only. 
Profit rate swap - The market for Shari'a-compliant derivatives products is at a fascinating juncture and we are witnessing the embryonic stages of an OTC derivatives market. 
Case study published in Derivatives Week.
Islamic Funds
Our investment funds team regularly advises on the establishment and on-going operation of a wide range of Shari'a-compliant investment funds.Our investment funds team has developed a range of Shari'a-compliant fund structures across a range of sector including advising on Shari'a-compliant real estate, hedge, fixed income, private equity and SME funds. We also advise on acquisitions and disposals for, and investments into, Shari'a-compliant funds.
“ ...a superb profile in the investment funds environment...”  - Legal 500 UAE 2009
Key Islamic Funds contacts


 Deal highlights
Abraaj Capital We advised Abraaj Capital on the establishment of ASAS, a pan-MENA real estate fund, structured by way of Cayman Islands exempted limited partnership, with Shari’a-compliant investment projects across the MENA region, which had its first closing in 2010. National Bank of Abu Dhabi (NBAD) We advised NBAD on certain of the NBAD Growth Funds. A US hedge fund managerWe advised on the structuring of its Shari’a-compliant hedge fund. A Dubai real estate companyWe advised on its investment in shares in a DFSA regulated Shari’a-compliant real estate investment trust. A joint venture between a UAE sovereign wealth fund and US real estate asset managerWe advised on the structuring and establishment of a Shari’a-compliant real estate platform for investment in the GCC, including advising on the first acquisition on behalf of the platform in the UAE. Gazeley (a subsidiary of Economic Zones World) We advised Gazeley on its Shari’a-compliant development pre-let of 63,000 square meters of warehouse space to be constructed in the Jebel Ali Free Zone to CEVA, a major international distribution company, and subsequent sale of the property to a Middle Eastern private equity fund. 
Islamic Taxation
Our Islamic finance taxation specialists have experience of providing a wide range of taxation advice, both on domestic and multi-jurisdictional transactions. We provide a high level of service, whether on a stand-alone basis or as an integral part of the full legal service offered by Allen &amp;amp; Overy's Global Islamic Finance Group. 
Drawing from over 100 tax specialists across our international tax practice, our Islamic Finance Taxation team includes lawyers in London, Luxembourg, New York, Paris, Rome and Sydney.
Advising on the tax aspects of Islamic finance transactions requires an appreciation, not only of the Shari'a constraints that are likely to apply, but also of general principles of domestic tax law. Members of our Islamic finance taxation team are also familiar with any relevant legislation or guidelines which have been implemented to ensure that Islamic finance transactions operate in as tax neutral a way as possible.
We advise on a wide range of Islamic finance transactions, with both domestic and multi-jurisdictional dimensions, including ijara, istisna'a and murabaha financing transactions, sukuk issuances and securitisation transactions. We have also advised banks such as HSBC and Standard Chartered on the tax implications of their own products.
Our Islamic Finance Taxation team has also been involved in consultations and discussions with revenue authorities and governments in various jurisdictions in connection with the development of tax legislation and practice aimed at facilitating Islamic finance transactions.
Deal highlights
Providing advice on Islamic finance real estate transactions in France, including a murabaha financing in connection with the purchase of commercial real estate in Paris 
Advising on various murabaha financing transactions, including a portfolio refinancing 
Advising on a murabaha facility structured through a securitisation company 
Establishment of a shari'a-compliant regulated investment fund 
Advising on the UK and US tax implications of sukuk issuances.
Our news
Islamic Finance Taxation - Where are we now?
Key Islamic Taxation contacts
London, UK
Christopher Harrison
David Hughes
Mark Middleditch
Vimal Tilakapala
Luxembourg, Luxembourg
Patrick Mischo
New York, USA
Jack Heinberg
Paris, France
Jean-Yves Charriau
Rome, Italy
Francesco Bonichi
Sydney, Australia
Andrew Stals
 
 
 
 
 
 
 

The Global Islamic Finance Group consists of Islamic finance experts across Europe, including in London, Paris and Luxembourg; the Middle East, including in Abu Dhabi, Dubai, Qatar and Saudi Arabia; and Asia, including in Singapore and Hong Kong, who have a detailed understanding of the religious and legal background to Islamic finance, the evolving principal financing techniques and range of services offered by Islamic banks, and the issues affecting the development of Islamic finance. Allen &amp;amp; Overy is a supporting member of the Accounting and Auditing Organisation for Islamic Financial Institutions (AAOIFI) and an observer member of the International Islamic Finance Market (IIFM).
Recognition for our work
Band 1 - Banking and Finance (Islamic Finance): Global wide - Chambers Global 2013
Band 1 - Islamic Finance (Middle East) - Chambers Global 2013
Band 1 - Islamic Finance (Asia-Pacific Region) - Chambers Asia-Pacific 2013
Band 1 - Islamic Finance (London) - Chambers UK 2013
Band 1 - Islamic Finance (United Kingdom) - The Legal 500 United Kingdom 2012Allen &amp;amp; Overy is the only law firm in the world to be ranked in the top band across each region.
 
International Financial Law Review (2010) and Islamic Finance News (2012) recognised 12 Allen &amp;amp; Overy lawyers respectively in their surveys on 'the world's leading Islamic finance lawyers', more than any other law firm. This demonstrates the reputation and the strength in depth of Allen &amp;amp; Overy's global Islamic finance practice and our ability to offer a truly integrated global service regardless of where our clients are based or the nature of the specialist advice that they require.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>fd1a02e5-bac7-45fb-9e23-3719afba4c8f</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>7891e92d-9a8b-4dfa-8b4f-f45d51f09808</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>264</Id>
    <UniqueId>56fdda54-2090-4afb-9968-8549af694d0c</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>ITC Litigation / Section 337</PracticeName>
    <Text />
    <TermStoreId>69c48f5a-d3cf-4f05-aacb-758728cb1b73</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>ead974a2-95a8-4128-afb5-b493481bf45d</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>265</Id>
    <UniqueId>668b7005-5c29-4b6e-95e0-e0c1c4668c01</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Joint Ventures</PracticeName>
    <Text>We support corporates, investors and entrepreneurs on structuring, drafting and negotiating their joint venture agreements.
Because we work collaboratively across all our practice groups, we also offer a broad range of supporting advice in areas such as intellectual property rights and exploitation, regulation and licensing, commercial agreements, real estate, tax and employment and benefits.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>5ae29fb7-507c-487c-90cc-dfb1faf26e42</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>7e0fa517-f886-49c1-8d30-6474dd585171</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>266</Id>
    <UniqueId>656facb9-975d-4a59-a2b3-3dacb5479126</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Leveraged Finance</PracticeName>
    <Text>Thanks to our network, we can combine a multi-jurisdictional leveraged debt team with an extensive capital markets practice. 
This enables us to provide our clients with a full service for senior, second-lien, mezzanine and PIK debt, bridge-to-bond financings, bank/bond financings, high-yield debt offerings, securitisation take-outs and debt buy-backs and restructurings.
Our sector knowledge and understanding of our clients’ business objectives enables us to provide legal advice that truly meets those aims within the context of the overall rationale for the debt package. Lenders and borrowers alike need to be able to structure deals in ways that suit market conditions. Our lawyers can advise on any form of leveraged financing that our clients choose to undertake.
The leveraged finance market has changed. Deals these days are different and structuring them demands a broad mix of finance capabilities. We combine our market-leading practices in banking and leveraged finance with a pre-eminent high yield practice. This makes us one of the very few law firms that has the ability to cover all aspects of complicated leveraged finance and high yield transactions and crossover and emerging markets high yield transactions.
Recognition for our work
&amp;quot;Clients highlight the firm's technical excellence, as well as the consistently impressive quality of the team and its ability to &amp;quot;bridge the gap between legalese and commercial reality.&amp;quot;
Chambers UK 2013: Banking and Finance, Band 1 
&amp;quot;With ‘incredible depth, knowledge and expertise’, Allen &amp;amp; Overy provides a ‘superb service and sets the gold standard in every way'&amp;quot; 
Legal 500 2012, United Kingdom, Banking and Finance: Acquisition Finance, Band 1</Text>
    <TermStoreId>0015365e-a87a-4e2d-ae34-27bb2bb3b07b</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>7891e92d-9a8b-4dfa-8b4f-f45d51f09808</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>267</Id>
    <UniqueId>186079f3-7cec-4b31-90b9-64b0e408bebe</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Litigation, Arbitration and Dispute Resolution</PracticeName>
    <Text>We also have broad experience in corporate risk management and conflict management, advising senior level board members and executives of substantial corporates and banks. 
We provide a comprehensive service in most of the world’s major countries and have dealt with many of the problems generated by changes in the financial marketplace. Our global network includes many experienced former prosecutors, enabling us to represent clients effectively in the most difficult and sophisticated government investigations.
We actively pursue all avenues of dispute resolution available and advise clients on choosing the method most appropriate to them. Our main priority is to resolve disputes quickly and effectively with as little disruption to business as possible – recognition of this is central to how we approach any matter. 
Recognition for our work
&amp;quot;This firm has a truly global presence in litigation, with particular strengths in Europe and the Middle East, as well as a considerable presence in China and the USA. Its international stature is illustrated by the key financial crisis-related cases that it features on. Sources say: 'Very good in just about everything they do. Disputes work really matters to them. I sharpen my pencil and get up an hour earlier when I've got a dispute on with them'.&amp;quot; Chambers Global 2011 (Tier 1 - Dispute Resolution)
&amp;quot;Its expertise in oil and gas disputes is remarked upon, as is its long-standing involvement in the banking and finance sphere. The 37-partner team continues to attract some eye-catching mandates under the ICSID, LCIA, and ICC systems as well as under the Energy Charter Treaty.&amp;quot; - Chambers Global 2013 (Arbitration (International): Global-wide)</Text>
    <TermStoreId>7a7028a8-8ba1-4a5f-a0dc-95c1b4785668</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId />
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>268</Id>
    <UniqueId>ab42eedb-b311-453b-9b16-1d8d25c0ebed</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Lloyd's of London</PracticeName>
    <Text>We advise Lloyd's market participants, including managing agents and brokers as well as counterparties such as investment banks, reinsurers and insurers in respect of all aspects of the Lloyd's market.
Recently, particular areas of focus have included derivatives and other risk transfer instruments, reinsurance and general regulatory issues around Lloyd's trust funds and the Lloyd's chain of security.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>eb70e375-ebd5-4b44-94ba-190e6ed855c2</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>8895b5c5-b35f-42e6-883d-9017b5d154b6</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>269</Id>
    <UniqueId>11398d2b-9f9f-41d9-a6be-12486a061344</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>M＆A</PracticeName>
    <Text>We support buyers and sellers at all stages of transactions – from bid preparation and submission to negotiation, sign-off and close. We advise on the full range of deal structures from public takeovers/tender offers through to divestments, auctions, take privates and demergers. Our track record in M&amp;amp;A, expertise and local knowledge ensure that we deliver cost-effective, high quality legal advice. Our close-knit team of lawyers across the world employs a common approach, which means we can handle cross-border deals effectively.
Our sector teams work closely across our network of offices to provide clients with an unrivalled, seamless service. Strong sector knowledge built up from years of working with clients across all sectors, allows us to bring a strategic approach to our work, a deep understanding of industry issues and ensures we provide an efficient approach to due diligence.
&amp;quot;This international powerhouse has significant corporate capacity across the globe, handling a steady flow of impressive M&amp;amp;A mandates.” 
Chambers Global 2013 (Corporate/M&amp;amp;A)</Text>
    <TermStoreId>3fd850e7-2e03-4246-b920-db1a61524efa</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>7e0fa517-f886-49c1-8d30-6474dd585171</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>270</Id>
    <UniqueId>698d8274-7701-407d-ba2c-8747a6ca453e</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Merger Control</PracticeName>
    <Text>We are regularly involved in some of the most difficult and sensitive mergers and are regularly involved in detailed/Phase II merger control investigations at both EU and national level. 
Our involvement in some of the most high-profile cases has been recognised by the international antitrust community:
 In 2012 we won the Merger Control Matter of the Year at the GCR Awards for our role advising SABMiller on its AUD11.2 billion acquisition of Foster’s Group Limited. This was one of the most high-profile global acquisitions of the year.
We also won Matter of the Year for our role advising Seagate Technology on the EU, China and global (ex-U.S.) merger control aspects of its USD1.4bn acquisition of the hard disk drive business of Samsung Electronics. The review by the European Commission of Seagate/Samsung was one of the most high-profile and controversial of the year.
We also have a strong track record of securing U.S. antitrust clearances for domestic and cross-border mergers, acquisitions and disposals and we play an active role in advising on the antitrust aspects of multiple M&amp;amp;A transactions every year. 
Global strategies 
Merger control is a crucial element in any major merger process. When anticipating a transaction, reliable legal advice on the expected outcome and timing of merger clearance procedures is essential. Obtaining merger clearance often involves complex, time-consuming and multi-jurisdictional notification processes. 
In complex mergers, remedies may need to be offered to obtain clearance and there is always a risk that the merger will be prohibited or, in some cases, unwound. Effective and efficient preparation and completion of the notification processes may well affect the success of the entire transaction. We have advised on some of the most complex and cutting-edge remedies packages imposed in merger proceedings.
Many, if not most, of our clients' mergers require clearance in multiple jurisdictions. A global strategy is essential for a coherent and efficient merger filing process. Drawing on local contacts and the expertise in our international network, we develop global strategies to obtain clearance of mergers and joint ventures in all relevant jurisdictions as soon as possible.
To give our clients consistency and cost efficiency, we also develop universal antitrust submissions that can be adapted for use in national filings. 
Our international merger teams advise on: 
the likelihood of opposition from merger control authorities
the preparation of submissions and briefing papers
the negotiation of settlements when needed to secure clearance
Practical assistance includes:access to our extensive database of precedents, merger regime overviews and competition lawyers in virtually every jurisdiction
he option of setting up a bespoke global merger filing database to store previous merger filings and authority decisions, facilitating and expediting future cases
performing complex jurisdictional and substantive analysis to explain procedures, rules and timelines and help prepare notifications and other documents for submission to competition authorities
challenging prohibition or merger approval authorisation before the courts
Recognition for our work
Winner – Merger Control Matter of the Year GCR 2012
Winner – Matter of the Year GCR 2012
&amp;quot;This firm maintains its position as a market leader in competition work, with its lawyers receiving particularly high praise from peers. The group has been active on several of the most high-profile merger control cases over the past year&amp;quot; Chambers and Partners Netherlands 2012
&amp;quot;The firm's broader reach has significant advantages in international transactions&amp;quot; Chambers and Partners Australia 2012 
&amp;quot;Its international footprint allows it to co-ordinate multi-jurisdictional merger filings (and) complex cartel investigations&amp;quot; Chambers and Partners Europe 2012
&amp;quot;The breadth of this practice encompasses both inbound and outbound international matters, and it has further deepened its foothold in the region this year&amp;quot; Chambers and Partners China 2012
&amp;quot;Its ability to draw upon the expertise of the firm's global network of European and American antitrust practitioners is also considered a real competitive edge&amp;quot; Chambers and Partners China 2012</Text>
    <TermStoreId>00530078-e038-4253-a92d-0cc1ee084520</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>97290c58-1db1-45aa-89a2-48d7d0f765a0</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>271</Id>
    <UniqueId>d50f6dbe-f803-4e53-b7dd-7b3df85716a4</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Microfinance and Social Investment</PracticeName>
    <Text>Our Microfinance and Social Investment practice encompasses more than 300 lawyers located in over 25 offices across the Americas, Europe and Asia Pacific, and includes many of the leading practitioners in our key practice groups including banking, capital markets, corporate and dispute resolution.
The team has advised on a number of microfinance-related transactions and prides itself on being able to provide real and much-needed solutions helping to transform businesses in developing economies. Our clients include microfinance institutions (MFIs), banks, private investors and institutional investors. Whether on a pro bono or fee-paying basis, we aim to handle every case in exactly the same way – with professionalism and care. 
More recently, Allen &amp;amp; Overy has been involved in advising Social Finance Limited (Social Finance) on their Social Impact Bonds (SIBs), which are a unique investment product, structured as a fund, that directs private-sector money to fund public sector projects. In this case, the investment proceeds fund prisoner rehabilitation programmes, creating a financial return to the investors that is dependent on levels of recidivism in the prisoner group. Legal fees for negotiating and setting up the Social Finance prisoner programmes could have run into hundreds of thousands of pounds, a particularly significant amount when measured against a fundraising target of £5 million. To solve the puzzle, Allen &amp;amp; Overy stepped in to provide over 1,500 hours of legal advice on a pro bono basis, to help Social Finance craft and negotiate the SIB, an investment product enthusiastically accepted by investors, the Ministry of Justice and HM Treasury and used in many jurisdictions around the world as an example of groundbreaking social finance funding.
Recognition for our work
&amp;quot;Business in the Community Big Tick Award&amp;quot; in the Coffey International Awards category for the past three years (2011/2010/2009)
&amp;quot;Excellence in Community Investment&amp;quot; awarded by The Law Society 2010&amp;quot;
Allen &amp;amp; Overy lawyers have provided 41,500 hours of pro bono legal advice in 2012/2013. This is in addition to the significant volunteering contribution of our professional support staff. 
Key contacts</Text>
    <TermStoreId>ae95aa1e-29f4-4316-9c2f-993d0ef10ead</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>7891e92d-9a8b-4dfa-8b4f-f45d51f09808</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>272</Id>
    <UniqueId>01807dee-a5b1-48a0-98c8-18a82723c201</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Nature Protection</PracticeName>
    <Text>It also represents a potential opportunity, with growing policy and market moves towards methods of valuing the economic capital of biodiversity.
Projects in or near the EU-wide Natura 2000 network of protected areas may be subject to specific permitting regimes or restrictive conditions. Even existing businesses may be impacted by the presence of protected species. At the same time, forward looking companies may also be interested in taking advantage of market measures to monetise the natural capital of land and ecosystems within their control.
Members of the Global Environmental and Regulatory Law Group in Allen &amp;amp; Overy's international network of offices are well-placed to assist with what is often considered one of the most complex and detailed areas of environmental law, advising on both the international framework and the national implementing legislation for nature protection. Recent experiences include advice to, and risk assessments for, power and infrastructure projects, both nationally and in cross- and near-border contexts.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>4f2642d4-ef5d-4558-800b-d5e29349d4b6</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>afb18bd5-bdd7-4cc3-a69b-bcb6997b5a6c</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>273</Id>
    <UniqueId>585c328f-e5ba-439b-bbf9-fcb4edd76523</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Outsourcing</PracticeName>
    <Text>Acting for both leading suppliers and corporate customers from a wide range of jurisdictions and business sectors enhances our understanding of the commercial requirements and priorities of both parties, as well as our ability to identify and anticipate the latest trends in outsourcing. We have significant experience of advising clients on how to structure a procurement process to take best advantage of the various procurement models, as well as on how best to approach a response to a tender in order to win the business.
The breadth of our practice is demonstrated by the range of commercial transactions that we have advised on, including those involving IT and communications services, business process outsourcing (including procurement, asset and cash management, finance and accounting, facilities and logistics management, clinical trial services, call centre and security services), and human resources outsourcing.
With an integrated global team combining expertise in employment and benefits, tax, antitrust, corporate finance and regulation to harness insights and best practice, creating innovative outsourcing solutions. We also have a first class team of litigators with extensive experience in outsourcing disputes across all the major industry sectors.
We work closely with both clients and industry experts to develop market-leading training materials and strategies that address key concerns in the outsourcing process, including in relation to service levels, benchmarking, human resources, relationship management, liability, business continuity planning and exit management.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>889edac6-4736-44f7-8a49-4a91af10fd78</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>7e0fa517-f886-49c1-8d30-6474dd585171</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>274</Id>
    <UniqueId>ad5428ce-7855-4149-a910-029b8e51a8cf</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Pensions</PracticeName>
    <Text>Our global team of over 65 Pensions lawyers across 14 countries is made up of local experts. We work together to cover the cross-border dimension as well.
Whether your need is for a creative solution to a technical pension benefit problem, day to day practical advice on the operation of your retirement benefit plans, commercial advice on the pensions risks in a transaction or help navigating the increasingly regulated pensions environment, we can meet your needs.
We advise on retirement benefit provision for the workplace, including plan changes, fiduciary responsibilities, governance, dispute resolution, financial support negotiations and conventional or alternative liability management.  We also offer investment funds specialists.
We advise on retirement benefit plans of every size, from GBP1 billion plus funds to single member arrangements. Whether you are an employer sponsor, a plan trustee or manager, or an investor, we have the experience to help.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>7c4d4ba2-f1a0-4225-8015-a33caa38371f</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>112e5e15-9144-48fb-8dd0-5c09eb1e53a3</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>275</Id>
    <UniqueId>eafc4c0b-65d7-41f4-ba57-0b884ae77d2d</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Pensions Disputes</PracticeName>
    <Text>We have a strong pensions dispute resolution practice and advise all types of parties, including trustees of pension schemes, scheme sponsors, insolvency practitioners, investment managers, and parties to corporate transactions. Matters range from individual ombudsman claims through to rectification matters and claims relating to systemic errors of administration affecting scheme benefits.
Increased intervention by supervisory authorities usually means more risk, but the level of exposure is often not clear. Our pensions lawyers have good relationships with their local pensions regulators, social security and tax authorities to confirm requirements and test analysis.
We often advise on the scope of powers and benefit entitlements. Our technical knowledge and commercial experience is tried and tested. For example, in the UK we advised Prudential in a dispute over pension increases. Our client's approach was approved in a high profile application for directions to the High Court.
When managing employee and plan member complaints for our clients, we advise on tactics as well as the legal merits. In an ideal world though, prevention is better than cure. We also advise on reducing the risk of successful complaints, including offering training in the areas of common difficulty, such as exercises of discretion and eligibility criteria for early retirement and death benefits. Discrimination issues remain a hot topic too.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>440d711c-6b24-4c9b-b1e6-fd0d623f70cf</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>112e5e15-9144-48fb-8dd0-5c09eb1e53a3</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>276</Id>
    <UniqueId>ed9094aa-d9d4-46c3-bd7a-06e58771f6f6</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Permits and Authorisations</PracticeName>
    <Text>Our particular areas of expertise include: 
advising on complex permit procedures relating to the planning, construction and operation of infrastructures in transport (road, rail and air), energy, mining, telecommunications, and industrial sectors
providing advice on permit and notification requirements under European and national law regarding foreign trade and export control
representing our clients in negotiations with public bodies and in administrative or court proceedings</Text>
    <TermStoreId>a012a72c-c5c9-4b57-8a8f-b38df0d1166e</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>e5f42143-a550-4fe5-84a5-6b5ada4229fb</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>277</Id>
    <UniqueId>206e1549-3607-428f-b9da-1190efd7380c</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Policy Advice</PracticeName>
    <Text>Our Insurance Group advises insurers and reinsurers, but also corporate buyers of insurance, including financial institutions, local and multinational companies, government bodies and insurers in relation to policy wording and operational insurance issues, as well as the use of insurance to address risks that arise in corporate transactions. 
We also regularly advise financial institutions on the use of tailored insurance products as security for financing arrangements, and other financial instruments, such as derivatives, which utilise legal technology developed in the insurance and reinsurance markets.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>25f9b12a-1a4b-42d6-803c-0d9b194061b0</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>8895b5c5-b35f-42e6-883d-9017b5d154b6</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>278</Id>
    <UniqueId>a3cfcc2d-0c51-4f87-ab63-4fc9b01a3ffc</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Private Equity</PracticeName>
    <Text>Our dedicated Private Equity M&amp;amp;A lawyers are an integral part of our global Private Equity sector group; a single sector group combining M&amp;amp;A and equity expertise with leveraged finance and high yield expertise. We tap into the firm's knowledge and experience built up across all sectors.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>7e95672d-9ed3-4219-8d76-dd1bbaef290e</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>7e0fa517-f886-49c1-8d30-6474dd585171</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>279</Id>
    <UniqueId>9261a380-7e27-4812-ba83-dee95116f751</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Product Stewardship</PracticeName>
    <Text>Legislators around the world are increasingly taking a product-centred approach to environmental protection, imposing obligations on manufacturers, distributors, importers, users and disposers to reduce the environmental impacts of products, from the sourcing of raw materials to the management at their end-of life stage. Members of our Global Environmental and Regulatory Law Group are well-placed to advise on all aspects of this cycle. 
Our product liability practice provides strategic advice and practical assistance to all operators in the supply chain, covering a wide range of products, including industrial equipment, automotives, medical devices, electronic equipment and other consumer goods. 
We are involved at all stages of the production and marketing chain, from regulatory compliance at the strategic planning stage, to product labelling issues (including CE marking) and product liability risk assessments. We also assist clients with the regulatory impact of product misuse and product health and safety issues such as exposure to asbestos or other hazardous content. 
We support clients on the practical impacts of regulatory enforcement action, including product investigations, recall, litigation, toxic torts and the associated reputational issues. 
We have established global product teams dealing specifically with producer responsibility and product liability issues, who help our clients ensure compliance with all relevant legislation and managing product risks - enabling them to do business across the globe.
We also focus on trade and export controls enabling our clients to understand and comply with the complex challenges of operating within the ever expanding international trade sanctions.
Topics on which we routinely advise include: 
product safety and recall
managing supply chains, sales channels, logistics and customer disputes
RoHS and WEEE directives, including the chemical content of products
China RoHS
Batteries Directive
U.S. and European sanctions, exemptions and approvals
dual-use product restrictions
medical devices
U.S .conflict minerals legislation
scoping and implementing due diligence on supply chains
drafting and negotiating product supply terms and associated compliance certifications and warranties
U.S. rules on e-waste and substance restrictions
EMC requirements
EuP Directive and implementing measures
waste shipment regulations
carriage of dangerous goods and substances
packaging requirements
developing compliance plans and strategies
carrying out product registrations and certifications
market surveillance initiatives
product liability</Text>
    <TermStoreId>246c24db-f8e0-416a-a982-6dc14a08ed7a</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>afb18bd5-bdd7-4cc3-a69b-bcb6997b5a6c</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>280</Id>
    <UniqueId>409f4722-1030-49dc-b626-a7afd742b76c</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Projects</PracticeName>
    <Text>The Group advises sponsors, governments, construction companies and lenders on projects and project financings across energy, infrastructure, mining and telecoms throughout the world.
We provide our clients with a totally integrated service on all aspects of project work, drawing on and marshalling Allen &amp;amp; Overy’s specialist skills in all relevant areas of law.
Our lawyers win praise for their technical ability as well as their commercial approach and can provide a comprehensive service, including advising on joint ventures, project structures (BOT, BOOT, DBFO, DBFM, PPP, 3P, PFI and others), conducting legal due diligence, risk allocation and reviewing the &amp;quot;bankability&amp;quot; of project agreements, financing arrangements (Bank and bond) and relevant security packages and considerations across the Globe.
Allen &amp;amp; Overy has consistently closed more project finance deals globally than any other law firm since 2000 and is recognised as ‘top-tier’ in all the major legal directories. 
Recognition for our work
&amp;quot;For the first time in a long time, IJ League Tables have an outright winner in the Global Legal Adviser table by both value and volume of transactions.&amp;quot;  Infrastructure Journal</Text>
    <TermStoreId>9f06ba67-0792-49a7-aae5-b50ac5896363</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId />
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>281</Id>
    <UniqueId>1bf40e69-c68f-4ade-9f61-22ad05c7956d</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Public and Mixed Entities/Structures</PracticeName>
    <Text>Indeed, by using a corporate entity – rather than relying on traditional statutory bodies – public authorities are able to speed up the relevant administrative process and to achieve their market goals, while at the same time respecting the related public interest needs.
In addition, as a result of privatisations started in several countries, the public-private mixed company has become one of the main forms of public-private partnership (PPP). This is particularly the case in the following market sectors: public infrastructure, assets and services (mainly water, gas, electricity, transportation, waste management as well as zoning development).
With this form of structure, the private partner not only provides the financing but also the technical capability required to ensure that a project reaches a successful conclusion.
In this respect, European laws and national implementing provisions govern the set up and operation of mixed companies, operating public assets and providing public services, to ensure that fair competition and transparency principles are complied with. 
The Allen &amp;amp; Overy Public Law group has a proven record of providing high-level assistance on projects involving both these forms of public and mixed companies. We advise both public bodies and private companies on the set-up phase, operation phase and the contractual relationship between the public and private parties, covering all issues including employment issues and public accountability. We can also assist on all the phases regarding the tender process to select the private partner and as we are a full-service law firm, can advise the client on all the legal issues involved in the matter.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>5725f7c0-2bc1-453d-84eb-3337a78418fe</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>e5f42143-a550-4fe5-84a5-6b5ada4229fb</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>282</Id>
    <UniqueId>e5efbc21-f556-42cd-ae2e-958ee1fdc7fc</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Public International Law</PracticeName>
    <Text>Public international law is of increasing relevance to our clients, both in contentious and non-contentious matters. Examples of our work in this field are set out below. 
Public international law (Advisory)
Negotiating, drafting and acceding to treaties
Negotiating and drafting inter-governmental and host government agreements concerning cross-border trade, investment and cooperation
Cross-border project finance and infrastructure projects
Structuring cross-border investments
International investment law protection for investments abroad
Rights and obligations under international trade law agreements, international intellectual property law agreements, international environmental law agreements, and international human rights law agreements 
International anti-corruption laws
Boundary disputes and rights to resources straddling borders 
International sanctions
The immunity of sovereigns and state entities
Sovereign debt and restructurings
Public international law (Disputes) 
International arbitration under bilateral investment treaties and the Energy Charter Treaty before International Centre for Settlement of Investment Disputes and other international arbitral tribunals
Disputes before World Trade Organisation panels and the WTO Appellate Body 
Disputes before World Intellectual Property Organisation tribunals
Recognition for our work
&amp;quot;A very strong practice.&amp;quot; (Public international law, Chambers UK 2014)
“Allen &amp;amp; Overy LLP has a team of ‘very experienced and talented lawyers’.” (Public international law, Legal 500 UK 2013)</Text>
    <TermStoreId>09f176e5-1aec-4999-a86f-02006f78b595</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId />
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>283</Id>
    <UniqueId>f63e1ff8-905b-44d2-a264-f18277cf36e1</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Public Law</PracticeName>
    <Text>Understanding how dealing with public law entities may be different from dealing with private entities and the impact of regulation have always been an important aspect of business life. It is even more important with governments cutting costs, privatising and selling assets, turning to or away from public-private partnerships as well as increasing public sector spending in some areas. 
Advising on both transactions and litigation, our Public Law team has proven its world class expertise covering all aspects of public economic law including:
administrative contracts
freedom of information
government-owned assets
human rights
permits and authorisations
public and mixed entities/structures
public law litigation
public-private partnerships
regulatory 
Our global Public Law practice brings together more than 40 lawyers with a client base that includes public authorities, regulatory bodies, utilities, sponsors, financial institutions, and corporates. Our people advise these diverse players on global, cross-border and local public sector transactions.
We assist a large number of public authorities and regulatory bodies on the implementation of their powers as well as with drafting and interpreting legislation. As a result, we fully understand the complexities and challenges of this area of law. Conversely, we can offer our clients in the public sphere assistance that takes into account the perspective of private sector players.
Our clients value our straightforward and pragmatic advice. We work in an integrated way with our Banking, Corporate and Real Estate departments, and approach issues from a variety of perspectives, taking into account the wider economic and legal context. 
We advise major players in all sectors, including:  
infrastructure
transport
financial markets
utilities, including energy and water
telecommunications
mail services
life science
defence
Recognition for our work
&amp;quot;Allen &amp;amp; Overy LLP delivers an extremely high-quality service, and has strength in the regulated sectors, particularly finance and telecoms.&amp;quot; - Legal 500 2011 (UK)
&amp;quot;Effective and results-driven is how market sources describe the public law team of this magic circle firm.&amp;quot; - Chambers Europe 2011 (Belgium) 
Recognised as a top tier practice by Chambers Europe 2011 (France), clients praise &amp;quot;the exemplary and distinguished team [...] for its in-depth knowledge of public law.&amp;quot;</Text>
    <TermStoreId>e5f42143-a550-4fe5-84a5-6b5ada4229fb</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId />
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>284</Id>
    <UniqueId>c5a49d07-4759-4c03-b4db-b39dbf932641</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Public Law Litigation</PracticeName>
    <Text>This is all the more probable in the current environment of austerity and government cost-cutting, which has in many situations resulted in the removal of rights and the frustration of expectations. At such times it is essential that clients have the best advice from a team of lawyers well-versed in public law litigation.
Allen &amp;amp; Overy can provide that team. Our public law practitioners have a wealth of experience in public law litigation across a number of different jurisdictions. We act both for public sector bodies seeking to defend their acts and decisions and also for private sector parties bringing public law challenges, which gives us a unique perspective and enables us to bring a different approach to representing a client, whether public sector or commercial.  
We understand the different procedures, approaches and strategies required to deal with public law issues. We handle many large-scale disputes and have considerable experience with proceedings in the administrative and civil courts, as well as in the European Court of Justice. Our lawyers often represent foreign companies in proceedings related to the decisions of national bodies. Our global reach and the fact that so many of our cases have an international element means that we are also used to working with lawyers and witnesses from different jurisdictions.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>0313fc64-9fdf-45cd-829c-c84d99bd7cba</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>e5f42143-a550-4fe5-84a5-6b5ada4229fb</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>285</Id>
    <UniqueId>90371298-e129-4fcc-96a5-585be5faf2ec</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Public Private Partnerships (PPP)</PracticeName>
    <Text>We are market leaders in providing assistance on large scale PPPs in a wide variety of jurisdictions. We advise on a range of sectors including roads and bridges, airports, prisons, ports, stadia, rail infrastructure, schools and social housing.
We act for sponsors, banks, authorities and contractors. Thanks to the diversity of our client base, we are able to anticipate and understand issues and provide innovative and robust solutions for complex deals. 
Our clients value our straightforward and pragmatic advice. We work in an integrated way with our Banking, Corporate and Real Estate departments and approach issues from a variety of perspectives, taking into account the wider economic and legal context.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>d4fb52d7-dc60-4b0d-9be2-ea5c3175cfbe</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>e5f42143-a550-4fe5-84a5-6b5ada4229fb</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>286</Id>
    <UniqueId>76cb0f09-6dc9-424e-9a13-da679f6bb2b7</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Public Procurement and Competitive Tendering</PracticeName>
    <Text>Private companies themselves may also award contracts through a tender process. Non-compliance with these rules can have very serious commercial consequences. 
Arrangements with public authorities that do not fall within the scope of these rules may still be subject to the general principles of the Treaty on the Functioning of the EU and therefore require some degree of transparency and competitive tendering. 
Our international team has the experience to address public procurement issues from the perspective of all those involved in the procurement process. Our expertise stretches out to Europe and beyond, and among our procurement lawyers is a former director of criminal enforcement at the Antitrust Division of the U.S. Department of Justice, who was responsible for developing the training programme provided by the DOJ to senior officials on contracting with the U.S. government (MAPS). 
Our international public procurement team advises on:
how to anticipate potential issues and prepare suitable strategies for dealing with the rules 
preparing a clear, structured approach from the initial commercial assessment to the final award and performance of the contract 
procurement disputes 
guidance for contracting authorities and utilities operators whose tendering processes have come under attack 
disappointed tenderers seeking to challenge the award of a public contract 
Recognition for our work
&amp;quot;The procurement team at Allen &amp;amp; Overy advises large public and private sector entities on a wide range of matters, and is further bolstered by its international platform and ability to handle the most sophisticated, multi-jurisdictional projects&amp;quot; Chambers and Partners UK 2012 
&amp;quot;The effective procurement group at Allen &amp;amp; Overy has a deep-rooted presence throughout Europe, and provides a range of procurement advice to public and private sector clients&amp;quot; Chambers and Partners 2011 
“Procurement Law firm of the Year” The International Who’s Who of Public Procurement Lawyers 2011</Text>
    <TermStoreId>30b22769-4939-4c16-98bb-ae9de642e2e1</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>97290c58-1db1-45aa-89a2-48d7d0f765a0</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>287</Id>
    <UniqueId>793fdac9-ec90-479d-8c9b-0dbb1052027b</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Real Estate</PracticeName>
    <Text>Our clients choose us because they know we understand their objectives and offer them the innovation, experience, technical expertise, clarity of advice and commitment to get their deals done efficiently and effectively. We regularly handle transactions for the world's leading investment banks, private equity funds, hedge funds, pension funds, REITs and sovereign wealth funds.
Real estate deals are becoming ever more complex. Increasingly they are cross border, highly structured and involve sophisticated financing arrangements. Allen &amp;amp; Overy is ideally placed to advise on these sorts of transactions with our specialist real estate capability across all product lines, unparalleled reputation in finance and well resourced global network. 
We advise on development and planning, projects and construction, large loan, mezzanine, A/B and preferred equity origination, loan workouts, NPL pool acquisitions, distressed debt acquisition (including loan-to-own strategies), investment, corporate occupation, tax, finance, securitisation, real estate investment fund formation, structuring and joint ventures, and complex real estate mergers and acquisitions.
We support our clients in their most important real estate projects on an international basis. With more than 90 partners and over 300 associates across our global network, we have both significant geographical reach and a wealth of real estate experience in the UK, Europe, Asia Pacific, Africa, the Americas and the Middle East.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>2cd9e1b8-bcd7-4f4d-b63b-1f28018625b1</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId />
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>288</Id>
    <UniqueId>18a0dcfc-2e5a-47eb-bd4f-4e84ce2e791b</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Real Estate and Planning Disputes</PracticeName>
    <Text>We are recognised as a leading real estate litigation practice with an outstanding reputation for handling complex ad hoc and high-profile commercial property and planning disputes, acting on pivotal cases for a wide range of clients – from government bodies and international financial institutions to major corporate concerns.  
Examples of the kinds of cases that our London office can advise on include:
Landlord and tenant matters – break notice disputes, service charge claims, possession and forfeiture actions, dilapidations, lease renewal or business tenancy claims under the Landlord and Tenant Act 1954 and rent review.
Insolvency-related disputes – advising insolvency practitioners, advising on a landlord's remedies in the face of an insolvent tenant.
Neighbour disputes – rights to light claims, nuisance, boundary issues, restrictive covenants, rights of access.
Professional negligence actions – for example in relation to advice given by solicitors, valuers' negligence cases concerning surveyors, and claims against management companies.
Major property transaction disputes – construction disputes between contractor and developer, failures to complete, warranty claims, joint venture disputes and limited partner disputes.
Enfranchisement - in respect of prime and super prime residential premises, advising landlords and tenants in respect of lease extension and collective enfranchisement (freehold purchase) claims.
Recent examples of work by other offices include representing:
A major German real estate fund in connection with the late delivery of an important real estate development in Luxembourg
A Hong Kong company on the commencement of legal proceedings against a company for recovery of possession of the property together with the arrears of rent, management charges and other moneys due under a lease
Our emphasis is on providing pragmatic advice tailored to specific situations, which makes us the natural choice for the 'big ticket' work relating to a wide variety of property types, including large development sites, shopping centres and office blocks. We take time to fully understand our clients’ businesses and the wider property market.
Clients also benefit from our pre-emptive commercial advice, which flags up potential future problems. As a first step, we try to avoid disputes and to contain our clients’ costs. When unavoidable, we use court proceedings or other dispute resolution procedures to achieve their goals. 
With wide experience of the property market and all types of dispute resolution procedure, we are used to managing many of the largest and most complex multi-party disputes. Working closely with our real estate, insolvency, corporate, projects and finance teams, we provide clients with creative legal solutions to their business problems, right up to conclusion of a project or dispute.
Recognition for our work
&amp;quot;Allen &amp;amp; Overy rises in the rankings this year due to its work on recession-related disputes...It earns praise for its commitment to the development of more junior members, with commentators noting that 'the team produces very good assistants – they bring on the young recruits very well there.'….'A totally reliable team; the lawyers show dedication and will make themselves available to you whenever you need them.'... 'They give considered, tactical advice, and are very pragmatic'.&amp;quot; Chambers &amp;amp; Partners UK 2011
&amp;quot;Allen &amp;amp; Overy is noted for its effective, commercially savvy settlements.&amp;quot; The Legal 500 UK 2011</Text>
    <TermStoreId>76d8b584-6d53-4b08-9f3d-33922ccd1af7</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>7a7028a8-8ba1-4a5f-a0dc-95c1b4785668</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>289</Id>
    <UniqueId>0858b06a-404c-4271-958f-99f28e33c1a2</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Real Estate Construction</PracticeName>
    <Text>Whether we are acting on relatively simple construction schemes or highly technical projects, our clients appreciate our pragmatic and commercial approach. 
We specialise in complex domestic construction and engineering projects such as commercial offices, corporate and bank headquarters, shopping centres, major international energy and infrastructure projects, PFI/PPP work, finance, insolvencies, insurance contracts, claims analysis and contentious work. 
This experience gives us an excellent understanding of the wide spectrum of issues that arise across various sectors. We work closely with procurement and project delivery teams from the very start of each project, making sure all solutions meet our clients’ requirements at every step of the way. 
Because our lawyers regularly draft and amend building contracts, consultancy agreements, warranties and performance securities – such as bonds and guarantees – to ensure adequate rights of recourse, we are well versed in the construction-related legal issues that organisations are likely to encounter.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>fc7edb0d-4569-435d-ad2b-5456de4494e4</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>2cd9e1b8-bcd7-4f4d-b63b-1f28018625b1</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>290</Id>
    <UniqueId>28946d7f-c3e9-42dc-8716-2e951dbcea6c</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Real Estate Development and Planning</PracticeName>
    <Text>We advise leading developers, funders and occupiers on all types of projects providing them with advice spanning real estate, planning, construction, environment, energy and infrastructure related projects and PFI/PPP. 
A significant part of the practice's work involves innovative funding and structuring techniques. Much of our work involves the use of joint ventures allowing our clients to share the knowledge of their commercial partners, share risk and increase tax efficiency.
We also have wide experience in dealing with all types of planning work in the office, retail, industrial, hotel and residential sectors as well as substantial infrastructure and energy projects such as power stations, gas storage facilities, offshore windfarms and  transport schemes.  Within these overall sectors we regularly advise on all aspects of planning law and its practically related specialisms, including built heritage and listed buildings, compulsory purchase orders, highways, judicial review and local authority practice and procedure.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>5b9e9ac8-9c5e-4cea-9bd7-bbda1f162a8e</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>2cd9e1b8-bcd7-4f4d-b63b-1f28018625b1</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>291</Id>
    <UniqueId>fb6fc185-b88d-471a-99a5-4a33d0444122</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Real Estate Finance and Workouts</PracticeName>
    <Text>We advise the world’s most advanced investment banks, specialist real estate lenders, borrowers, funds and investors on their most critical and pioneering transactions. No other practice can match our depth of experience and unique understanding of every aspect of real estate finance in both domestic and international markets. 
As financing techniques have evolved, we have evolved with them, cementing our reputation for leading developments in the market and structuring the most complex deals. Our practice includes advising on large loan, mezzanine, A/B and preferred equity origination, loan workouts, securitisation, the formation of real estate investment funds, secondary market debt acquisitions, NPL pool acquisitions, real estate mergers and acquisitions, joint venture structuring and complex real estate acquisitions.
Our international footprint and depth of resource is backed up by our experience. Allen &amp;amp; Overy has been involved in the real estate finance market since its inception and boasts uniquely strong practices in Europe, the U.S. and Asia Pacific. With over 90 partners in our global office network specialising in real estate finance we offer our clients a truly integrated service.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>15becb7c-1cc8-4690-a92f-a8e11dc848e1</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>7891e92d-9a8b-4dfa-8b4f-f45d51f09808</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>292</Id>
    <UniqueId>ebd3cc48-fc95-4542-9727-e90b0a8e9b5f</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Real Estate Funds</PracticeName>
    <Text>In recent years, as real estate has become a fully-fledged alternative asset class for funds alongside private equity funds and hedge funds, we have advised on some of the largest and most complex fund structures, delivering to clients imaginative and intelligent solutions that meet their commercial needs. 
Our real estate fund clients include some of the world's largest asset managers and private equity real estate fund managers. We provide advice in relation to various commercial real estate funding and joint venture structures using onshore and offshore partnerships and corporates, eg Luxembourg FCPs, SICAVs, SICAFs, and Jersey and Guernsey corporates.  
We act in all the areas that you would encounter during the life-cycle of a real estate fund, from fund formation to real estate, regulatory, tax and corporate advice through to exit strategies.
Our international network of lawyers in the real estate funds group allows us quickly to solve cross-border issues - with offices in the majority of the world's major financial centres, we can provide you with a choice of location as to where you would like your work to be managed.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>662cf9c0-14e3-4708-aa31-4cc04c6a85b8</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>2cd9e1b8-bcd7-4f4d-b63b-1f28018625b1</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>293</Id>
    <UniqueId>750fa7a9-dbe5-4142-bbcc-e11efca6fb86</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Real Estate Investments, Joint Ventures and Structures</PracticeName>
    <Text>Described by clients as “indisputably brilliant on the very big transactions&amp;quot;, we represent real estate owners, investors, investment banks, private equity houses, sovereign wealth funds and REITs. 
Our in-depth knowledge of the real estate sector and close working relationships across our global network allow us to add value to our clients’ transactions with high-quality, practical and tax-effective legal advice. Our partners and associates are not just skilled in real estate matters. They also have wide experience of indirect real estate acquisitions, negotiating corporate-style documentation and providing advice on joint ventures and structuring that is drafted within a real estate context.
A key part of our advice involves looking at the associated corporate, financing and tax aspects in any transaction. Many of the real estate acquisitions we handle are actually corporate acquisitions (both onshore and offshore) to maximise tax efficiency. Our team is well versed in negotiating these share or unit sale and purchase agreements. 
These agreements are often structured offshore in jurisdictions such as Luxembourg, where we have an office, or Jersey, Guernsey, the Cayman Islands or the British Virgin Islands, where we have strong relationships with leading local law firms.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>8fc5a9af-52af-407d-8d44-1a96e5ccca3a</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>2cd9e1b8-bcd7-4f4d-b63b-1f28018625b1</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>294</Id>
    <UniqueId>4dbef051-0f89-4dc2-8611-1bbd74273cdf</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Real Estate Securitisation</PracticeName>
    <Text>Although new issuance of CMBS and RMBS remains low by historical standards, particularly in Europe, sponsors, financials institutions and investors need to be able to access the best advice when looking at CMBS and RMBS structures and other structured capital markets lending (such as whole business securitisation for property companies and REITs). 
Allen &amp;amp; Overy has a market-leading real estate securitisation practice, advising on transactions ranging from single trophy-assets structures through to loan portfolios, conduit lending, and, now more important than ever, working on deal restructurings. Our team leads on industry associations and remains committed to guiding our clients through the new regulatory landscape.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>912b7e23-64c6-4d3e-be09-0f4ca9e2971e</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>2cd9e1b8-bcd7-4f4d-b63b-1f28018625b1</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>295</Id>
    <UniqueId>dead578a-b907-444f-ad8b-3f4bf80576c7</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Real Estate Tax</PracticeName>
    <Text>We field an experienced and commercial team who advise on structuring both domestic and cross-border real estate transactions.
We act for a variety of market participants on real estate investments, securitisations, joint ventures, limited partnerships, fund establishment (both cross-border and domestic), IPOs of real estate companies, leasing structures and mergers and acquisitions in the real estate sector.
In addition to domestic matters in the major jurisdictions, we are particularly adept at advising on cross-border matters, drawing on the resources of our 100 strong global tax group.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>a5347499-eb0b-4274-90ac-ebc04b34cf67</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>2cd9e1b8-bcd7-4f4d-b63b-1f28018625b1</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>296</Id>
    <UniqueId>bf1e04dd-c888-4789-830e-da6fc5d3fb0f</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Regulatory</PracticeName>
    <Text />
    <TermStoreId>a2146f3e-4a74-45ea-a51d-57b135f8551e</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>e5f42143-a550-4fe5-84a5-6b5ada4229fb</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>297</Id>
    <UniqueId>c57b17fe-ed07-4286-84ef-30fffb7ac19e</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Regulatory Investigations and White Collar Defence</PracticeName>
    <Text>Successfully managing the risks arising from this increased focus requires a deep understanding of both the technical legal requirements of multiple jurisdictions and the practical concerns and investigative methods used by government regulators and criminal prosecutors. Most importantly, early identification of potential criminal and civil liability risks will provide the best opportunity for effectively crafting a response that protects the long-term interests of the client in all relevant jurisdictions.
Even the decision to conduct an internal investigation into possible employee wrongdoing can later present difficult issues if the investigation is not tailored to the risks, the jurisdictions, and the regulators involved in the matter. Our global team of lawyers responsible for representing clients in regulatory and white collar criminal investigations bring a powerful combination of breadth of experience and local expertise to the task of helping clients solve potential problems that arise in the context of cross-border and domestic regulatory and criminal investigations.
Our practice includes both conducting internal investigations on behalf of clients and defending clients subject to government investigations. We cover a number of areas of specialty, notably the following:
antitrust 
anti-bribery and corruption 
securities
Recent examples of our work 
Examples of our recent work includes representing: 
A major bank on issues arising from sales worth over GBP1bn of structured notes issued by Lehman Brothers to retail customers, following the bank’s collapse in 2008. This has involved advice on dealing with regulators, criminal and civil court cases and customer claims and complaints in various EMEA countries, as well as investigating and advising on the documents and processes used in the distribution and sale of the notes.
A global financial services firm in the DOJ antitrust investigation of the credit derivatives clearing, trading and information services industries.
An investment bank in responding to worldwide government investigations into manipulation and collusion regarding LIBOR submissions.  
BAE Systems Plc in the defence of the public investigation by the UK SFO of the company’s involvement with the Al Yamamah defence contract with Saudi Arabia and its procurement of contracts in multiple jurisdictions around the world; culminating in final settlement at the end of 2010.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>2886e359-7e38-44e3-a292-0ac4330f21a0</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>7a7028a8-8ba1-4a5f-a0dc-95c1b4785668</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>298</Id>
    <UniqueId>1de50f23-b3e7-4454-ae59-5559aef7bf66</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Reinsurance</PracticeName>
    <Text>Our Insurance Group advises the world's leading insurers and reinsurers on reinsurance transactions and related matters, including collateral and security structures and asset/liability management.
We advise in respect of both general business and long term business, and in relation to reinsurance transformer structures.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>3953af05-d883-48bf-bfca-089a583d292d</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>8895b5c5-b35f-42e6-883d-9017b5d154b6</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>299</Id>
    <UniqueId>8b10c6fe-f16b-40ef-b80f-6b6aa6275c10</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Restructuring</PracticeName>
    <Text>With such an extensive and dedicated team, we advise on the largest and most complex restructurings, and pride ourselves on providing pioneering solutions as well as real commercial results. We specialise in cross-border restructurings and insolvencies, utilising the full range of international options including U.S. Chapter 11 reorganisations, UK schemes of arrangement, pre-packaged sales and debt for equity swaps. 
Our expertise covers advice on contingency planning, insolvency filing requirements, debt restructuring, distressed financing and reschedulings, distressed acquisitions/sales, credit bidding, formal insolvency proceedings, out-of-court restructurings and refinancings and distressed debt trading. We advise lenders and investors at all levels of the capital structure as well as corporates/directors, central banks, insolvency officeholders/trustees and government institutions. 
We work closely with specialists in related practice areas including finance, corporate, real estate, employment, pensions, tax, environment, regulatory, capital markets and litigation to provide a seamless and integrated service.
Recognition for our work 
&amp;quot;Recognised as one of the premier players in the UK market, and earns praise for 'its superior knowledge of UK insolvency law'&amp;quot;UK Chambers, Restructuring and Insolvency, 2013
&amp;quot;Allen &amp;amp; Overy have simply been involved in nearly all of the largest bank related restructurings to have taken place since the financial crisis.&amp;quot;IFLR 2012, Restructuring and Insolvency 2012
&amp;quot;Allen &amp;amp; Overy LLP’s 29 partner restructuring team is ‘a machine’, with a ‘very strong resource base’, and is ‘a cut above the rest’.&amp;quot; Legal 500, Corporate Restructuring and Insolvency 2011</Text>
    <TermStoreId>acec88f6-f1f0-4c94-ab08-6ced08483ceb</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId />
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>300</Id>
    <UniqueId>c4d843e7-be58-46e0-a84e-d167f2a6fea3</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Restructuring and Insolvency Disputes</PracticeName>
    <Text>We act for clients from all parts of the capital structure and our advice spans all aspects of contentious insolvency work, including, for example, retention of title claims, enforcing security, representing officeholders in numerous and diverse applications for directions, risk assessing restructuring proposals and defending corporate restructuring and reorganisations. 
Our team is able to seamlessly combine all the elements involved in complex restructurings, both contentious and non-contentious. We work closely with our top-ranking restructuring and insolvency group and other practice areas such as corporate, employment, pensions, tax, environmental, regulatory and capital markets. 
Recent examples of our work
Recent examples of our work include representing:
ISDA in an application made by the administrators of LBIE seeking directions as to the meaning and effect of Section 2(a)(iii) of the ISDA Master Agreement, and its compatibility with the anti-deprivation principle of English insolvency law. This matter raised important issues relating to parties’ rights and obligations under the standard form ISDA Master Agreement which had not previously been considered by the English courts. 
As well as advising over 150 counterparties in relation to the failure of Lehman Brothers through our restructuring group, we advised two of the parties to the application brought by the administrators of Lehman Brothers International (Europe) (in administration) (LBIE) for directions in relation to some USD2bn of ‘client money’ held by LBIE. Later this year, this matter will proceed to the Supreme Court.
HSBC as security trustee in relation to a 'leapfrog' appeal to the Supreme Court by a bond trustee against a decision of the chancellor regarding whether a clause in a finance document excluded the rule in Cherry v Boultbee.
Richard S. Fuld, Jr., the former chairman and Chief Executive Officer of Lehman Brothers Holding, Inc. (LBHI) on an array of intersecting proceedings arising out of Lehman's well-publicized bankruptcy.  We are representing Mr. Fuld in connection with his Congressional testimony, governmental and regulatory inquiries, and multiple securities and ERISA class actions.
Recognition for our work
Ranked 1st tier in the Dispute Resolution category. “Sources say: ‘Very good in just about everything they do. Disputes work really matters to them. I sharpen my pencil and get up an hour earlier when I've got a dispute on with them!’” Chambers &amp;amp; Partners Global 2011</Text>
    <TermStoreId>12f74df2-9cde-4c73-a192-c85c9132f297</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>7a7028a8-8ba1-4a5f-a0dc-95c1b4785668</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>301</Id>
    <UniqueId>030c928c-cca6-4413-8743-54b49597f042</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Securitisation</PracticeName>
    <Text>International transactions are the norm and we have securitisation specialists across our global network of offices. In addition to working in jurisdictions where our specialists are located, our lawyers also regularly advise on work outside of the Allen &amp;amp; Overy network. We are adept at securitising in new markets, examples of which includes working on Greece’s first private sector securitisation, advising on the first auto loan securitisation in the Middle East, developing the first UK master trust structures (and the subsequent master issuer and delinked structures) and the first whole business securitisations in Germany and the UK.
Our securitisation team regularly advises arrangers, originators and trustees on transactions involving a wide variety of asset classes and structures, including 'true sale' and synthetic securitisations, CLOs, CDOs and the establishment of securitisation programmes. Our experience includes advising on precedent-setting residential and commercial mortgage-backed securitisations, whole business and public sector securitisations, as well as securitisations of auto loans, consumer loans and trade receivables.
Our securitisation team works alongside structured finance, derivatives and banking lawyers to ensure clients’ transaction needs are met and complex structures can be successfully completed. The team is also able to call upon the resources of specialists in their particular field of expertise such as tax, real estate finance, project finance and corporate trustee as and when required.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>13a621c9-77dc-4658-a5cb-0053cc41f85d</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>dddbe240-d29a-43f7-922f-1dc914fc0e53</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>302</Id>
    <UniqueId>1ab407ec-ef7e-4d34-a492-e315472aee10</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>State Aid</PracticeName>
    <Text>The law governing the aid that governments in the 27 EU Member States provide to the private sector is an increasingly important specialist area within EU competition law. Few can match our breadth and depth of experience. In fact, we helped to set the legal framework for state aid in the EU. 
The recent spate of bank mergers and rescues has highlighted the importance of this area of law and has raised challenging issues around the interaction of state aid, merger control and government action to protect financial stability. Our international antitrust team has been at the heart of these issues. 
Our understanding of the Commission's position in this area is reflected in our selection to update the Directorate General for Competition's report on the Application of the EC state aid law by the Member State courts, having drafted the original report in 1999. 
The text book, EU State Aids, widely regarded as the leading authority in this area, is co-edited by two of our antitrust specialists, Tom Ottervanger and Leigh Hancher, and has now gone into its fourth Edition. 
We advise clients throughout the complaint or approval process, and where required provide representation before the national and European courts. 
We have wide experience of acting for governments and other public sector bodies, as well for aid beneficiaries and lenders on a variety of complex financial transactions giving rise to state aid issues. 
Recognition for our work&amp;quot;This firm is widely regarded as an important player for domestic Belgian matters, and is also well versed in EU and international competition work&amp;quot; Chambers and Partners Belgium 2012
&amp;quot;This firm has a highly regarded pan-European practice&amp;quot; Chambers and Partners Europe 2012
&amp;quot;…recommended for its ‘excellent knowledge and response times’ &amp;quot; Legal 500 Poland 2012</Text>
    <TermStoreId>4a10ff8a-db81-44a1-9a9b-3df205c3afb8</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>97290c58-1db1-45aa-89a2-48d7d0f765a0</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>303</Id>
    <UniqueId>8ac21e53-ef47-465f-93e9-d7845fc502c4</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Tax</PracticeName>
    <Text>That's why, with over 100 tax specialists across our international network, we are able to offer both domestic and cross-border advice wherever our clients need it, whether they are financial institutions, corporate entities, or funds.
The depth and breadth of our knowledge ensures that we are able to support our clients' business needs successfully and provide high quality, innovative tax solutions in the increasingly complex area of tax legislation and practice.
Our tax offering
Asset finance
We have experience in all areas of tax based asset finance, including aviation, shipping, rail and commercial property.
 
We advise many of the world’s leading financial institutions and corporations on domestic and crossborder transactions.
Banking &amp;amp; Finance
Many of the world’s leading banks and financial institutions turn to Allen &amp;amp; Overy for help with their most important and innovative deals. Our international Tax group has a great deal of expertise and advises on a range of products from bilateral and syndicated loans, to leveraged acquisition and project finance.
Corporate
We advise on corporate reorganisations and restructurings as well as commercial transactions, including domestic and cross-border mergers and acquisitions, demergers, capital raising, joint ventures, tax efficient holding company and financing structures and permanent establishment issues.
Our client base includes corporations involved in banking and finance, energy, insurance, manufacturing, retail, technology, media, public utility, construction, shipping, aircraft, transport, property and engineering.
Indirect tax
We have indirect tax expertise, in particular value added taxes, across sectors – from the ever-changing financial sector, through asset finance and corporate, to not for profit and private client areas.
International Capital Markets
Allen &amp;amp; Overy is one of the world’s leading International Capital Markets practices and tax plays a key role in this work. Our international Tax team is involved in the full range of transactions including debt capital markets, derivatives, equity capital markets, Islamic finance, securitisations, structured finance and structured retail products.
Investment funds
We offer cross-border expertise on regulated funds, hedge funds, infrastructure funds, private equity funds, real estate funds and structured funds. Our work covers the structuring of new funds and reviewing fund structures for prospective investors. We also advise managers about ongoing tax issues.
Real Estate
Tax considerations are important in real estate transactions, particularly those that are complex and innovative. We work with our real estate colleagues, providing expert tax advice on every type of real estate transaction.
Restructurings and insolvencies
Our restructuring practice operates at the forefront of a changing market. We provide tax advice to distressed companies, insolvency practitioners, banks and funds.
Structured finance
Frequent changes of law make this a very innovative and challenging area and we are one of the few tax departments that are trusted by clients to advise on and implement their ideas.
Tax investigations
All of our major offices have experience advising clients on tax audits and their relationship with local tax authorities, national courts or European legislative bodies. We regularly deal with domestic and cross-border investigations. 
Recognition for our work
&amp;quot;Ranked across numerous jurisdictions in Europe, Allen &amp;amp; Overy boasts one of the foremost tax practices on the continent. Recognised for its strengths in M&amp;amp;A, capital markets, tax structured finance, asset finance and restructuring work, the team of over 110 tax specialists has a substantial share of the European market.&amp;quot;  Chambers Europe, Tax 2012
&amp;quot;The firm is increasingly active in cross-border tax mandates thanks to its integrated global team, and attracts clients from across Europe as well as Asia and the USA.&amp;quot; Chambers Europe, Tax 2012
&amp;quot;This firm has a stellar European tax practice and is widely acclaimed for its cross-border expertise and in-depth international experience.&amp;quot; Chambers Global, Tax 2012
&amp;quot;It certainly has a very strong banking and finance-related tax practice and has excellent individuals in its team.&amp;quot; Chambers Europe, Tax 2012</Text>
    <TermStoreId>13bd2318-5344-4aac-903e-9c51955a51ca</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId />
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>304</Id>
    <UniqueId>39ba7711-7d34-4556-88d5-4a3c4fa8a86a</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Tax Disputes</PracticeName>
    <Text>Our experience in all aspects of corporate, commercial, VAT and finance tax is designed to avoid disputes arising, however, we are often called upon to advise when, or even after, various schemes or transactions have completed and issues with the revenue authorities have arisen.
One area which distinguishes us from our competitors is the handling of cross-border transactions. The proliferation of tax disputes, which often involve one or more jurisdictions, is where we can bring clarity of focus. It is the strength of our tax teams in international offices and their relationships with local revenue authorities which has allowed clarity and transparency to solve disputes to the benefit of all parties. This same strength also allows us to build structures to take advantage of benign tax treatment in certain countries to produce innovative solutions for clients.
Recognition for our work
Chambers Global directory 2011, states of our tax practice: “This firm’s network of offices - and superb reputation - stretches across Europe, the Middle East and Asia”.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>4a94f11a-25be-44a7-90a9-5bf846d2c48f</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>13bd2318-5344-4aac-903e-9c51955a51ca</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>305</Id>
    <UniqueId>4ca9a9ca-b81a-4944-ace4-08821b1271c5</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Transactional Support</PracticeName>
    <Text>A major part of the global environmental group’s work is concerned with providing advice to multinational corporations, global financial institutions, public sector institutions and other organizations on the management of environmental and regulatory risks and liabilities in mergers, acquisitions, disposals, financings, projects, joint ventures and similar transactions.
Our transactional advice on a particular matter may include, for example, the following:
due diligence on environmental, health and safety matters
lender liability 
piercing the corporate veil 
transaction structure issues 
environmental indemnities and warranties
property transfer requirements and permit transfer issues
environmental investigations (phase I and phase II environmental site assessments)
environmental insurance
risk mitigation</Text>
    <TermStoreId>6e8877c0-166f-4f33-9238-dee7527772b0</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>afb18bd5-bdd7-4cc3-a69b-bcb6997b5a6c</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>306</Id>
    <UniqueId>7e09298c-6257-4712-b1c3-e3de018167fa</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Waste</PracticeName>
    <Text>Allen &amp;amp; Overy advises on all aspects of the regulation of waste and waste management activities, including the definition and classification of waste, permitting requirements, the transfrontier shipment of waste, licensing and national and local regulatory issues.
Our experience also includes advising on waste projects utilising a variety of technologies including energy from waste and anaerobic digestion plants. We also have extensive experience of advising on the acquisition and disposal of businesses in the waste management industry and in waste related litigation.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>7ce49072-6ff1-4ede-abb7-c6ad1455bb59</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>afb18bd5-bdd7-4cc3-a69b-bcb6997b5a6c</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>307</Id>
    <UniqueId>a3083fa3-5e73-4792-a0e0-46a00f4e684d</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Airports</PracticeName>
    <Text>The regulatory systems to which they are subject are also different and the economic downturn affects different airports differently (hubs have broadly suffered less than point-to-point airports). 
This lack of uniformity in a single sector presents a number of opportunities to the market (governments designing regulatory systems as a prelude to sale, private sector vendors and potential purchasers such as airport operators and infrastructure funds).   
We believe that it is critical for legal advisers to have not just detailed knowledge of how a particular airport in a particular country works, but also to maintain a global view of the airport market and have a clear understanding of the potential options (for regulators, buyers and sellers) that are available. Allen &amp;amp; Overy has positioned itself so that it can offer applied knowledge from its significant experience advising on matters involving airports including project financing, development and construction, mergers and acquisitions (both public and private), funding (equity and debt), litigation, competition matters and funds.
We work with every kind of market participant in the airport sector, including buyers, consortia, builders, financiers, governments and regulators on many of the largest airport transactions around the world. 
Our experience is truly global. In recent years we have acted on matters involving international airports in the UK, U.S., Hong Kong, The Netherlands, Italy, Belgium, Germany, Denmark, Slovakia, Spain, Australia, India, United Arab Emirates, Greece, Columbia, Ecuador, Tunisia, Dominican Republic, Russia and Poland.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>9fe3a103-26ee-4f38-bf81-f3fc88d8d9bc</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>dbb7d095-dede-44cf-871a-a0780e70e08d</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>308</Id>
    <UniqueId>64302230-2065-47be-ab9a-557824c062c2</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Aviation</PracticeName>
    <Text>Increased competition, overcapacity, security concerns, climate-related pressures and rising fuel costs coupled with the increasing consolidation of airlines have had a profound impact on the industry. ​
Allen &amp;amp; Overy’s Aviation practice has built a world-class reputation advising on many of the industry’s most significant and pivotal transactions. The team comprises leading lawyers who have a thorough understanding of the latest developments in the sector and what this means for clients domestically and internationally.
We provide global coverage to the aviation industry advising across all legal disciplines including workouts and restructurings, mergers and acquisitions (public and private), funding (equity and debt), aircraft portfolio sales and purchases, engine financings, operating leases, privatisations, sales and leasebacks, major fleet purchases, EIB backed financings, export credit backed financings, mergers and acquisitions, U.S. EXIM backed financings, cross-border tax and leveraged leases, receivables, funds and maintenance contracts. We also have aviation specialists in ancillary areas such as real estate, employment and tax who offer commercial advice tailored to the sector.
Our clients include banks, financiers, lessors, lessees, export credit agencies, airlines and manufacturers on the full range of aviation matters.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>c16d8f8c-e397-42fd-a92b-a9488e910a68</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>dbb7d095-dede-44cf-871a-a0780e70e08d</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>309</Id>
    <UniqueId>385ed596-82c2-465d-8fab-8742ac66a8c7</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Banks</PracticeName>
    <Text>A significant portion of our Corporate, Banking, International Capital Markets and Litigation practices are dedicated to serving the legal needs of our international bank client base. 
Banks of all shapes and sizes, from domestic retail to international commercial and investment banking conglomerates, have relied on Allen &amp;amp; Overy’s FIG team to advise them through the financial crisis through to the current sovereign debt crisis. For example, we have helped banks: undertake capital raisings and liability management exercises to shore up finances and comply with new regulatory capital standards; restructure their operations to focus on core businesses; embark on major multi-jurisdictional outsourcings; acquire assets and businesses being offloaded by distressed institutions; defend themselves and key individuals from actions and proceedings resulting from cases brought as a result of the financial crisis; restructuring and insolvency proceedings, including on issues relating to custody and title to assets; and navigate the myriad of regulatory initiatives and proposals emanating from global, European and national bodies, including Dodd Frank, the various Recovery and Resolution Plan proposals in the UK, U.S. and Europe, the Independent Commission on Banking’s report in the UK, and Basel III and CRD IV to name a select few. 
In relation to the business that banks provide their customers, a significant share of our Finance and regulatory work is devoted to advising our bank clients on the full range of products and services they offer. This includes: asset finance; debt and equity capital markets; derivatives and structured finance; general lending; leveraged finance and high yield; projects, energy and infrastructure, real estate finance; and securitisation. These are described in greater detail in the Finance section of our website.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>1caad6bc-8ee4-42d6-b313-20aef6d0bfa0</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>1930da2e-adbd-451b-91f0-c56c8403829a</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>310</Id>
    <UniqueId>d87bd4aa-1fa1-43d8-87e8-3b3f9883dfc2</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Carbon Capture and Storage</PracticeName>
    <Text>Power developers and energy suppliers are now turning their attention to low carbon and renewable forms of energy, including wind, solar, tidal and nuclear. However, in many countries nuclear power is not an acceptable choice or a complete answer.  Accordingly, to ensure a 'green' base-load, some countries are investing in the development of Carbon Capture and Storage (CCS).
Allen &amp;amp; Overy is at the forefront of this exciting new area of climate change having advised a number of companies on CCS matters. In addition we are active members of the Carbon Capture and Storage Association (CCSA).</Text>
    <TermStoreId>87c947f9-e285-49dd-bd8a-075c18006a88</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>7ef89c9b-6439-445a-862d-cf428893e2d3</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>311</Id>
    <UniqueId>b055fe39-9648-4437-aef1-59095d26d128</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Climate Change</PracticeName>
    <Text>Our worldwide climate change practice group has advised extensively on carbon related projects, initiatives to mitigate carbon impacts and the development of CSR policies and carbon management strategies for clients. For more on the work of the Climate Change Practice Group, please also see emissions trading.
Allen &amp;amp; Overy is also at the forefront of the renewable energy market, advising both companies and financiers across the renewable energy spectrum, including hydro, energy from waste, solar, wind, biomass, biofuels and co-firing. We assist clients on the regulatory aspects of a wide range of renewables projects, as well as the environmental economic instruments which are so essential in making such projects viable, such as the UK’s Renewables Obligation, green certificates and tariffs in Europe, and emissions credits under the Kyoto Protocol.
The geographic reach of Allen &amp;amp; Overy, including the transfer of knowledge between different offices and jurisdictions, means that we are able to keep abreast of the latest green initiatives and legislative developments occurring around the globe.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>3ea5eb92-b203-4664-a214-6056a1a1ed28</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>7ef89c9b-6439-445a-862d-cf428893e2d3</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>312</Id>
    <UniqueId>89017de9-2700-4d91-90d5-91212e40beb0</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Downstream</PracticeName>
    <Text>Many of the traditional downstream players are divesting their assets in developed markets, whilst new projects are beginning to be developed in the higher growth markets of Asia. Developments in the Middle East, particularly in petrochemicals (including ethylene, propylene, aromatics, acetyls and fertilizers), continue to generate significant opportunities.  All these factors make this an exciting industry to work in, and one that requires its advisers to have sector–specific knowledge backed up by a global resource capability. 
Allen &amp;amp; Overy has been at the forefront of this market, advising IOCs, NOCs and host governments, sponsors, funders (equity and debt), and contractors on market leading transactions globally.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>3a77d67e-928a-44b4-956c-0fc90af1a75b</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>7ef89c9b-6439-445a-862d-cf428893e2d3</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>313</Id>
    <UniqueId>3f7fafd4-8bdb-4aba-b7a7-85551917ba46</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Emissions and Carbon Trading</PracticeName>
    <Text />
    <TermStoreId>2a55116c-d2cc-463c-9ead-99d9ac872d45</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>7ef89c9b-6439-445a-862d-cf428893e2d3</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>314</Id>
    <UniqueId>192f7e75-a651-461f-b9da-4e7a4fa279be</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Energy</PracticeName>
    <Text>The need to reduce greenhouse gas emissions, growing global demand, security of supply and ageing energy assets mean that governments and energy companies globally are faced with some of the most complex and challenging decisions that will have an impact not only on economic prosperity, but also on the long-term health of the environment. 
All these factors make this an exciting industry to work in, and one that requires its advisers to have sector–specific knowledge backed up by a global resource capability.
Allen &amp;amp; Overy's global Energy team is at the forefront of this sector, providing clients with advice on matters relating to power and utilities (including IWPPs), transmission and distribution, carbon capture and storage, oil &amp;amp; gas (up, mid and downstream and LNG) and climate change.
Allen &amp;amp; Overy provides pioneering advice on the entire lifecycle of these assets, from the consenting and planning process, through to the construction, financing, operation, maintenance and ultimately their refinancing or sale. We advise sellers and acquirers (on M&amp;amp;A transactions), project sponsors, corporates, financial/passive investors, suppliers, manufacturers, governments and debt funders (including banks, bond arrangers, ECAs, DFIs and multilaterals) on energy transactions globally.  These transactions are supported by our specialists in areas such as environmental, regulatory, antitrust, tax, employment and planning law.
The energy market is global, with many deals crossing borders. Allen &amp;amp; Overy is one of the few firms that can leverage a truly global network and deliver an absolutely seamless service across the UK, Europe, CIS, the Middle East, Africa, Asia Pacific, Australia, the United States and Latin America. Our global exposure and experience is highly valued by our clients.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>7ef89c9b-6439-445a-862d-cf428893e2d3</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId />
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>315</Id>
    <UniqueId>f532bd5b-d3b3-4d40-b7fd-f954e29aba15</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Energy Networks</PracticeName>
    <Text>forecast growth in the demand for energy globally; the need to support new low-carbon generation capacity; the need to replace dated infrastructure to improve demand management (smartgrids &amp;amp; smartmeters); regulatory pressure in some jurisdictions to separate transmission, generation, supply and distribution businesses and increasing investor appetite for a stable regulated income stream. 
Allen &amp;amp; Overy provides pioneering advice on the entire lifecycle of these assets, from the consenting and planning process, through to the construction, financing, operation, maintenance and ultimately their sale or refinancing. We are at the forefront of the energy networks market, advising debt funders (including banks, bond arrangers, ECAs, DFIs and multilaterals), sellers and acquirers (on M&amp;amp;A transactions), sponsors, corporates (including large vertically integrated utilities), suppliers, manufacturers and governments on market leading projects and transactions globally. These transactions are supported by our specialists in areas such as environmental law, regulatory, tax and planning.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>47cb49e7-c096-4979-9f5f-2d54941f1f49</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>7ef89c9b-6439-445a-862d-cf428893e2d3</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>316</Id>
    <UniqueId>38a41856-783c-4dc4-ad50-0bd8baf853b0</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Energy Retail</PracticeName>
    <Text />
    <TermStoreId>a9f8d559-0617-4cf2-8b4e-47c1a1e3c49c</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>7ef89c9b-6439-445a-862d-cf428893e2d3</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>317</Id>
    <UniqueId>bc50c317-869f-49e5-b654-990b8e12007b</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Energy Trading</PracticeName>
    <Text>The volatility in energy markets makes energy products a valuable commodities to trade, and almost every power project or M&amp;amp;A deal in the sector will require a significant amount of advice in relation to trading and hedging. 
Allen &amp;amp; Overy has capitalised on its energy sector knowledge and market leading trading and derivatives practice to provide its clients with the most sophisticated advice on this highly specialised subject in all jurisdictions of the world. These clients include NOCs (National Oil Companies), IOCs (International Oil Companies), Independent Oil &amp;amp; Gas Companies, and funders (debt and equity), power project developers, integrated power utilities, energy traders and governments.
Allen &amp;amp; Overy advises clients on issues such as physical commodity trading (short-term and long term); financial commodity trading contracts specifically relating to energy and emissions allowance markets (including hedging energy price risk and related counterparty credit risk); shipping and trading disputes. Allen &amp;amp; Overy also builds on its strong experience in trading and derivatives to advise clients on the set up of physical commodity trading platforms. Significantly we drafted the original form of Grid Trade Master Agreement which forms the basis of all bilateral electricity trades in the UK. We have subsequently advised several large and active market participants on contractual and regulatory issues in relation to gas and power trading.
We also have a market-leading financial regulatory practice, with lawyers who specialise in advising energy derivatives players on compliance, market abuse issues, and latest developments under EU Directives such as MIFID.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>95cafbaf-badf-4de9-8875-77454c264e0e</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>7ef89c9b-6439-445a-862d-cf428893e2d3</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>318</Id>
    <UniqueId>112c5e02-e1e3-447a-875b-434b04655928</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Financial Institutions</PracticeName>
    <Text>With partners who focus exclusively on financial institutions transactions in offices across the world, we are well placed to advise on complex deals that often involve more than one jurisdiction.
Buffeted by a vast and growing regulatory reform agenda, particularly in the U.S. and Europe, volatile financial markets and adverse economic environment, financial institutions face considerable strategic challenges as they seek to navigate a path to achieving the returns expected by their shareholders. Our FIG team is working with our financial institution clients across the world to help them anticipate and prepare for change across the full scope of their businesses, both in terms of their own organisations and in terms of the products they offer their customers. 
Recovery and resolution planning, remuneration rules, the impact of the Basel Committee’s responses to the financial crisis including regulatory capital requirements and liquidity issues, the development of new trading systems and other market infrastructure regulation, preparing for Solvency II, derivatives reform, developments in clearing OTC derivatives and regulatory investigations are just some of the areas in which our lawyers are applying their full intellectual nous and well-known skills to developing practical solutions for our clients. 
We developed a regulatory tracker, GlobalView, to help our clients navigate through the key regulatory themes affecting the financial services sector. 
Designed for financial institutions, it is the first of its kind to pull together developments at a global level, the EU, the UK and the U.S. in a graphical, intuitive and easy-to-use online service.  
Dedicated groups focus on key issues for banks, mutuals and building societies, insurers, asset managers and stock exchanges, supported by specialists regularly working with hedge funds, global investment bodies and brokerage houses.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>1930da2e-adbd-451b-91f0-c56c8403829a</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId />
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>319</Id>
    <UniqueId>d725b24a-df95-498a-b04d-4f5c78c3cf4d</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Food, Agriculture and Cosmetics</PracticeName>
    <Text>We operate on a cross-border basis and cover the full spectrum of legal support.
Our Life Sciences team has experience of advising many cosmetic and food companies including Cargill, LVMH Perfumes and Cosmetics, United Biscuits, McDonalds, Heineken, Kraft Foods Inc, Somerfield Ltd, Nestlé and British Sugar, among others. This has included advice on acquisitions, takeovers, intellectual property, copyright infringements and joint ventures.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>a89e894f-f19d-498d-9496-8ccc8045b0c2</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>a219d2ec-2a80-4aa9-9ad8-b8ca824edca0</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>320</Id>
    <UniqueId>fb4f392a-4196-4f5d-a79d-c7cf91054b50</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Government and Public Institutions</PracticeName>
    <Text />
    <TermStoreId>2791e4f0-7754-4e0d-aa6a-8f337e867c93</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId />
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>321</Id>
    <UniqueId>d3564105-8e7e-4f08-9a7c-47204b4bef2c</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Healthcare Services</PracticeName>
    <Text>Development and provision of specialised healthcare infrastructure is one of the key themes in modern times and requires specialist advice. The unique issues raised by the public service nature of hospitals, nursing homes, rehabilitation centres, clinics, academic and commercial R&amp;amp;D facilities always challenge investors, sponsors and lenders. 
As a global firm, we can successfully guide you through all stages of the lifecycle of healthcare infrastructure projects. In the healthcare infrastructure sector, we regularly advise on lettings and leasings, development, planning and construction, environmental issues and implications, private/public partnerships, including public procurement, transitional employment issues, commercial agreements with stakeholders, outsourcing, data protection and privacy, strategic licensing and collaboration agreements, global joint ventures, M&amp;amp;A and restructuring.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>51ff6db9-0568-4670-8447-8964856ff395</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>a219d2ec-2a80-4aa9-9ad8-b8ca824edca0</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>322</Id>
    <UniqueId>2e40b497-1350-4252-9f23-30add2f43f84</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Hotels and Leisure</PracticeName>
    <Text>We first became involved in the sector at the beginning of the 1980s and have continuously developed our practice since then. We advise some of the world's largest and most prestigious hotel chains and investors on the full range of legal services including acquisitions, disposals, developments and construction, equity capital market fundraisings, bond issues, whole business securitisations, litigation and M&amp;amp;A. 
Allied to this is the sector insight that we have built up over the previous 30 years. Our unmatched international footprint among elite global law firms means we have advised on matters in over 40 jurisdictions mirroring the development of the hotels and leisure sector as it has grown internationally.
Our investor client base includes corporate owners, private equity funds and high net worth individuals among others. Given the real estate-backed nature of the asset class, transactions in the sector regularly involve advanced financing solutions enabling us to combine our structuring and tax advice with project management expertise.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>20889288-5ad9-4345-93ff-173369d53f7c</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId />
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>323</Id>
    <UniqueId>b1242e03-7597-4f20-b0ec-7c8ea1b7ac6f</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Industrial and Manufacturing</PracticeName>
    <Text>Unless offset by price and surcharge rises, margins have been squeezed by the rising costs of oil, natural gas and steel. At the same time, customers are reluctant to invest in new equipment and the demand for after sales services has grown.
To strengthen core product lines or expand their presence geographically, some players are looking to acquire, while others are keen to divest their underperforming businesses. This comes at a time when local and national taxes, often managed across many territories, are more and more complex and under constant review.
We have a global understanding of the sector and so are ideally placed to share and apply the market intelligence and legal know-how we’ve gained from working in key markets and multiple jurisdictions. Consequently, our advice is realistic, practical and commercially viable.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>d87aeb65-0730-4a7b-9999-b002280913f3</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId />
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>324</Id>
    <UniqueId>c247cb66-10a6-4f96-b2e5-59b330decaa9</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Infrastructure and Transport</PracticeName>
    <Text>Over the next 20 years there is a pressing need for infrastructure to be replaced, upgraded or built in both developed and emerging markets as the rapid pace of globalisation continues. Some estimates put the total investment needed in existing and new infrastructure at tens of trillions of U.S. dollars. 
Allen &amp;amp; Overy provides clients in the infrastructure and transport sector with both industry insight and imaginative legal advice that will help meet these challenges. The group comprises over 220 sector specialists on six continents working in partnership with clients to help them achieve their goals. 
We view infrastructure and transport assets in the same way as our clients. Our approach combines disciplines and provides legal solutions for all advice needed on any infrastructure investment or activity across a variety of sub-sectors. We cover the full asset life cycle from creation to acquisition, the raising of sponsor or debt capital to restructuring and portfolio management and asset sales. Specifically, we work on major infrastructure project financings, mergers and acquisitions (both public and private) relating to brownfield infrastructure assets, securitisations, asset financings, refinancings, regulatory matters, infrastructure fund formation, arbitration and litigation and construction projects.
Our perceptive advice and work on critical transactions means we are recognised as the leading global provider of legal services to the infrastructure and transport sector. In recent years we have been named 'Global Infrastructure Firm of the Year' by Infrastructure Investor and 'Global Legal Adviser of the Year' by Infrastructure Journal.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>dbb7d095-dede-44cf-871a-a0780e70e08d</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId />
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>325</Id>
    <UniqueId>60ac8466-cb24-4786-8fa0-834166771ebf</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Life Sciences</PracticeName>
    <Text>We act for companies and their investors across the industry, including in the pharmaceuticals, biotech, medtech, diagnostics and healthcare sectors.The practice operates on a cross-border basis and covers the full spectrum of legal support. We advise on mergers and acquisitions, commercial transactions (including licensing and collaborations), IP (both contentious and non-contentious), capital markets and finance, regulatory and dispute resolution. Our international network ensures that we have a ready resource of expertise in a number of jurisdictions, including those in emerging markets, and that we are well positioned to advise on cross-border work.
Recognition for our work
Allen &amp;amp; Overy is known for its work on high-value life sciences transactions and it counts a number of significant market leaders amongst its clients.Chambers &amp;amp; Partners UK 2012 (Life Sciences)
“This team has impressive transactional capabilities. These lawyers are completely committed to their clients and have an outstanding work ethic,” say sources. Chambers &amp;amp; Partners UK 2011 (Life Sciences)
Competition and IP – particularly patent litigation – are the outstanding strengths of this magic circle practice. It is also able to advise on a wide range of other matters in the pharma and life sciences field, including M&amp;amp;A, regulatory, public law and employment, drawing upon the firm’s multidisciplinary capacity. Chambers &amp;amp; Partners Europe 2011 (France: Life Sciences)</Text>
    <TermStoreId>a219d2ec-2a80-4aa9-9ad8-b8ca824edca0</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId />
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>326</Id>
    <UniqueId>0ad535e3-1e3e-4f65-a35a-92f92c3bab4d</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Liquefied Natural Gas (LNG)</PracticeName>
    <Text />
    <TermStoreId>57897d3d-bb9e-470f-939c-6d09f2a85833</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>7ef89c9b-6439-445a-862d-cf428893e2d3</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>327</Id>
    <UniqueId>4054e209-ac8a-4efa-8b40-f40a55078bd9</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Media</PracticeName>
    <Text>And, because our clients operate across the spectrum of media operations from advertising and content production (including publishing, TV and filmed entertainment, games, music and other audiovisual products) to network distribution (including TV and radio broadcasting, online, fixed and wireless communications) and technology, our knowledge of media law is wide-ranging.
This means we provide relevant media-focused advice, delivered quickly to ensure that we add value from day one. So, irrespective of the location, the size, or the complexity of the matter, you can be confident that we have the right team in the right place.
We offer a complete range of services. As well as our renowned corporate finance practice, our media clients benefit from first-rate advice in areas such as intellectual property, antitrust and regulatory, commercial contracts, employment and benefits, litigation and dispute resolution, banking, capital markets and real estate. We are a one-stop solution for leading media companies.
Recognition for our work
“Allen &amp;amp; Overy LLP ‘is clearly ahead of the competition’…‘if you need visionary people who will not only give concrete advice but also direction for the future – call Allen &amp;amp; Overy.'” Legal 500 EMEA 2010 (Media and Entertainment: Belgium)</Text>
    <TermStoreId>081e0d6a-ec21-437b-99a7-eda169782c3f</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>492804b7-d6f0-4b03-b725-27e24de0908e</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>328</Id>
    <UniqueId>3c8f36f2-26fc-4577-bff9-a6395f680203</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Medical Devices and Technologies</PracticeName>
    <Text>Our lawyers have been advising clients in the sector for many years and have developed a deep understanding of the issues affecting businesses in the sector. This ensures we add high value to any matter and there is no learning curve. 
Our international network ensures that we have a ready resource of expertise in a wide range of jurisdictions and that we are well positioned to advise on cross-border work.
Our advice covers intellectual property, both contentious and non-contentious, mergers and acquisitions, commercial transactions (including licensing and collaborations), capital markets and finance and regulatory matters.
Our clients include Biomet, GE Healthcare, Alere (formerly Inverness Medical) and Chiron (now Novartis Vaccines and Diagnostics).</Text>
    <TermStoreId>06888ec5-83ff-4363-93f4-2ae2db6ead74</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>a219d2ec-2a80-4aa9-9ad8-b8ca824edca0</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>329</Id>
    <UniqueId>e6b2219b-1d12-4eb1-9405-1b17bc98fe21</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Midstream</PracticeName>
    <Text />
    <TermStoreId>d315abf0-d2aa-4e6f-8e21-e724f825d5cb</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>7ef89c9b-6439-445a-862d-cf428893e2d3</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>330</Id>
    <UniqueId>b3580c78-c465-44ea-ba74-c52a46ff7a2e</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Mining and Metals</PracticeName>
    <Text>Their market leading experience includes advising on a number of industry 'firsts' and major innovative transactions.
Our global team's expertise extends to advising clients in a range of businesses from mining (non-ferrous and precious metals, coal and other minerals) to smelting, refining, trading and semi-manufacturing.
The combination of our experience across the full life cycle of a mine – from acquisition and financing to expansion and disposal – means we can provide a comprehensive understanding of the mining sector and the likely issues and solutions that arise in a wide variety of transactions.
Our aim is to find commercial solutions for investors in complex legal and regulatory regimes. In addition to M&amp;amp;A and financing expertise, this also requires a solid understanding of the tax and regulatory rules across many jurisdictions. 
We are ideally placed to help our clients, advising from our own offices in Europe, the U.S., Latin America, the Middle East, Asia and Australia.
In late July 2011, we were the first global elite law firm to establish a presence in Africa, with the opening of an office in Casablanca, Morocco.
Recognition for our work
Chambers UK 2010 (Energy and Natural Resources) Band 1
&amp;quot;Allen &amp;amp; Overy is noted for its ‘commercial and professional approach’ and broad corporate offering.&amp;quot; Legal 500 2009 (Mining and Minerals)
&amp;quot;A&amp;amp;O is at the forefront of almost every area of the energy and natural resources sector and is a first port of call for major clients seeking advice on project development, finance, M&amp;amp;A, commercial and capital markets work.&amp;quot; Chambers UK 2010 (Energy and Natural Resources)</Text>
    <TermStoreId>95f623ba-5925-4284-a378-878913dae0fe</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId />
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>331</Id>
    <UniqueId>413b85d2-a44a-47e9-bbf4-5a760589849b</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Mutuals and Building Societies</PracticeName>
    <Text>This experience enables us to take an informed and commercial view of situations and give advice to clients which combines legal accuracy and practical experience.
The practice has advised on a number of market firsts, including the creation of the UK’s first ‘super-mutual’ under the Butterfill Act, the first acquisition under the Banking Act 2009, the first covered bond by a building society and the use by building societies of self-issued covered bonds to access central bank funding. 
We have advised societies and other mutuals, and entities dealing with them, for many years and have considerable experience and expertise in advising on constitutional issues, directors’ duties and corporate governance, regulatory matters (including regulatory investigations), defence issues and strategic transactions (including mergers and acquisitions). 
In addition, we have advised on numerous building society covered bonds and securitisations. Other areas on which we regularly advise societies and finance arrangers include public senior and subordinated debt issues, medium term note (MTN) and commercial paper (CP) programmes, transfers of mortgage portfolios, commercial lending, project financing, housing association financing and other types of treasury transactions. We also advise societies on regulatory capital, liquidity, mortgage regulation, consumer credit, unfair contract terms, employment, pensions and incentives matters, tax, data protection, intellectual property, outsourcing, electronic communications and insurance.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>0c285d03-2c9d-4545-beb1-c90b8d4eeada</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>1930da2e-adbd-451b-91f0-c56c8403829a</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>332</Id>
    <UniqueId>a110e43e-2745-4f9d-b3ed-78f25d21b401</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Nuclear</PracticeName>
    <Text />
    <TermStoreId>f175c315-f1a4-4954-a253-753e403914da</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>7ef89c9b-6439-445a-862d-cf428893e2d3</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>333</Id>
    <UniqueId>e80d9663-aa27-4aac-84dd-1fd341b7e453</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Oil and Gas</PracticeName>
    <Text>The ongoing growing demand for oil and gas in developing countries has ensured that prices, particularly oil, have generally remained high. These high prices ensure continual activity and investment in this sector, across the entire supply chain. All these factors make this an exciting industry to work in, and one that requires its advisers to have sector–specific knowledge backed up by a global resource capability.
Allen &amp;amp; Overy's market leading Oil &amp;amp; Gas practice advises governments and NOCs (National Oil Companies), IOCs (International Oil Companies), Independent Oil and Gas Companies, and funders (debt and equity) on all aspects of the oil and gas supply chain, including upstream (exploration and production), midstream (storage and transportation), downstream (fuels and lubricants, marketing and refining, retail and chemicals) and LNG.
Our integrated practice advises clients on transactions relating to project development, M&amp;amp;A (both public and private), funding (equity, debt and Islamic financing), energy and emissions trading and litigation and arbitration. All of these transactions are supported by our market leading experts in areas such as taxation, antitrust, regulatory, environment and employment, to name but a few.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>09252f4d-d8dc-4e52-863a-922630e88bf8</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>7ef89c9b-6439-445a-862d-cf428893e2d3</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>334</Id>
    <UniqueId>83b9d8b3-4714-40ed-8115-dd27d1942f50</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Pharmaceutical and Biotechnology</PracticeName>
    <Text>We draw on the advice of these specialists to provide tailored advice. Our expertise covers antitrust and parallel imports, high-profile patent litigation, regulatory matters, mergers and acquisitions, licence and other intellectual property/commercial agreements, IPOs, private placements and employment law. 
Our unique experience of working with leading pharmaceutical and biotech companies has enhanced our ability to identify and anticipate the latest trends in the life sciences sector. We advise many well known pharma companies in this field including Pfizer, Novartis, UCB, Sepracore, AstraZeneca, Sanofi-Aventis, Bristol-Myers Squibb and Bayer among many others.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>8ddb772e-2c81-463a-9fcd-50a7e8d787d8</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>a219d2ec-2a80-4aa9-9ad8-b8ca824edca0</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>335</Id>
    <UniqueId>f30e34ab-a33e-46a7-9da2-343184ea1ce8</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Ports</PracticeName>
    <Text>The rise of emerging markets and pace of globalisation means that ports are investing large sums to expand facilities to cope with increasing demand for imports and exports. This is at the same time as dealing with issues that have buffeted the wider shipping sector such as rising charter and fuel costs.
Allen &amp;amp; Overy has an impressive track record advising on projects and transactions in the ports sector spanning a range of legal disciplines including acting on a number of high profile mergers and acquisitions and financing transactions. We advise leading sponsors, banks and governments and port operators and regularly top the league tables for the number and value of deals completed in the ports sector. 
Our experience of working in this sector allows us to provide our clients with rich and intelligent advice that demonstrates our understanding of all corporate, finance, construction, operational, permitting, zoning, environmental and regulatory issues which are likely to arise during a variety of transactions involving ports.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>a7f99260-ea21-4508-aa9f-6ab58e80207e</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>dbb7d095-dede-44cf-871a-a0780e70e08d</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>336</Id>
    <UniqueId>9d3a4ac3-b2ef-499e-a3d1-60bf3b5fb6c3</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Power</PracticeName>
    <Text>Thermal power, including coal, oil and gas fired generation, may also see its future share of the energy mix increase as carbon abatement and sequestration technologies move from demonstration projects to full commercial viability. All these factors make this an exciting industry to work in, and one that requires its advisers to have sector–specific knowledge backed up by a global resource capability.
Allen &amp;amp; Overy provides pioneering advice on the entire lifecycle of these assets, from the consenting and planning process, through to the construction, financing, operation, maintenance and ultimately their refinancing or sale. We are at the forefront of the traditional power generation market, advising debt funders (including banks, bond arrangers, ECAs, DFIs and multilaterals), sellers and acquirers (on M&amp;amp;A transactions), sponsors, corporates, suppliers, manufactuers and governments on market leading projects and transactions globally.  These transactions are supported by our specialists in areas such as environmental, regulatory, antitrust, tax, employment and planning law.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>532bd272-43df-4a39-816c-7d918e2ffe24</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>7ef89c9b-6439-445a-862d-cf428893e2d3</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>337</Id>
    <UniqueId>522df4f8-783d-4c7e-92e4-00613057322b</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Private Equity</PracticeName>
    <Text>With the increasing sophistication and complexity of private equity transactions, the role of specialist advisers has become increasingly important in this field.
Allen &amp;amp; Overy is a market leader in the private equity sector, with extensive experience advising private equity investors, arranging banks, management teams and investee companies on the full cycle of private equity matters. We regularly advise a number of the leading private equity houses in the world.
Our comprehensive approach to private equity has seen us work on everything from structured acquisitions and financings and some of the largest cross-border buy-outs seen in the market, to the provision of venture capital to start-up businesses. The combination of our multi-jurisdictional corporate, leveraged finance, high yield, securitisation and investment funds expertise and full range of complimentary practices such as tax, employment and benefits and real estate makes us stand out in the market. 
This offering is truly global. Our spread of offices covers each of the key financial markets across the world, enabling us to work on private equity transactions and give specialist advice to clients wherever and whenever it is required. As such, our Private Equity group exhibits the market knowledge, timeliness and efficiency we as a firm take pride in.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>5fdb1d66-afbc-41e5-bd46-c6e49d66b2a6</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId />
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>338</Id>
    <UniqueId>ce9e46c4-b76c-428c-9a7c-76c7334f60fa</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Rail</PracticeName>
    <Text>This includes the liberalisation and reorganisation of the rail industry in a number of key jurisdictions, the development of high speed rail links, the need for new rolling stock and the growth of light rail projects. 
Allen &amp;amp; Overy has a first rate Rail practice, which has extensive experience advising on pioneering and complex rail transactions globally. With a thorough knowledge of trends and developments in the market, our team of rail experts are continuously involved in every aspect of this changing industry. 
Acting for rolling stock companies, lessors, project sponsors, financiers, train operating companies, regulatory bodies, manufacturers, investors and government authorities, the practice covers rail from every perspective and brings a measured and commercial approach to the sector. 
We are one of the few firms capable of advising our clients across the whole range of rail transaction types and are unique in being able to advise in each of these product areas with the same depth of expertise. This breadth of expertise, when coupled with the commercial approach we take to transactions, ensures we are able to provide our clients with one of the most experienced rail teams operating in the market.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>d290ff04-b15c-4eb2-869d-ca3cd5d88348</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>dbb7d095-dede-44cf-871a-a0780e70e08d</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>339</Id>
    <UniqueId>ecb5c354-369f-4c5c-8983-6e4b96182af8</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Real Estate</PracticeName>
    <Text>We are at the heart of the global real estate sector offering advanced and intelligent advice that complements the way our clients work.
Our Real Estate sector group brings together lawyers from across Allen &amp;amp; Overy's network and practice groups with particular involvement from our real estate, real estate finance, corporate, tax, securitisation, capital markets, litigation, investment funds and restructuring groups. Their expertise and strong team working enables us to advise on both domestic and cross-border deals involving real estate as an asset class.
Our client base reflects the diversity and vibrancy of our practice. We act for public and private companies, pension funds, investment banks and other financial institutions, private equity funds, sovereign wealth funds, hedge funds, real estate funds, hotel owners and operators, retailers, public sector bodies, developers and unit trusts.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>b5d1d3cc-7bd6-4b89-9d61-f0695e9eebe7</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId />
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>340</Id>
    <UniqueId>0c0b03bf-d7a1-4c86-906a-9b4c4d585e9c</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Renewables and Clean Technology</PracticeName>
    <Text>With the reduction of carbon emissions and the assurance of energy security so high on the agenda for governments and energy companies, renewable energy (on and off shore wind, solar, hydro and marine power) is as an essential part of the solution for slowing the pace of climate change and improving energy security. 
With ambitious carbon reduction targets being set globally and regionally, many governments incentivise the development of renewables through support programmes, such as feed-in tariffs, which are having a positive impact on the pace of development of renewables. All these factors make this an exciting industry to work in, and one that requires its advisers to have sector–specific knowledge backed up by a global resource capability.
Allen &amp;amp; Overy provides pioneering advice on the entire lifecycle of these assets, from the consenting and planning process, through to the construction, financing, operation, maintenance and ultimately their refinancing or sale. We are at the forefront of the renewable energy market, advising debt funders (including banks, bond arrangers, ECAs, DFIs and multilaterals), sellers and acquirers (on M&amp;amp;A transactions), sponsors, corporates (including large vertically integrated utilities), suppliers, manufacturers and governments on market leading projects and transactions globally. These transactions are supported by our specialists in areas such as environmental law, regulatory, tax and planning.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>38c9d0ea-dea3-4137-85f9-1070c7098d64</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>7ef89c9b-6439-445a-862d-cf428893e2d3</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>341</Id>
    <UniqueId>c8ed7cf3-79dc-4cca-ac8e-4a4720ae3838</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Retail and Consumer Goods</PracticeName>
    <Text>According to Mergermarket, since 2005 we have advised on more M&amp;amp;A deals globally in the consumer sector than any other law firm. Therefore we offer a team that understands the particular needs of consumer products clients and the pragmatic and commercial advice that they need. 
Allen &amp;amp; Overy, or members of our legal teams, have amongst current or past clients in the food sector the following large-scale companies: Nestlé, Danone, Kraft, Bahlsen, Diamond Foods, Arla Foods, Unilever, United Biscuits, Associated British Foods, Barilla Holding and Masterfoods. We advised the underwriters in respect of the IPO of Rank Hovis McDougall (RHM). We also advise many smaller regional or national manufacturers of food and drink products. We therefore have a good understanding of the business drivers and challenges that are at play in this dynamic sector, and can help you meet them.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>5e582f38-64b7-4aa3-ba0a-dbf4dba53ecc</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId />
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>342</Id>
    <UniqueId>6c79a811-0f48-421c-b2d7-1f6a0b70096c</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Roads</PracticeName>
    <Text>With the year-on-year increases in traffic, the drive for low carbonisation and declining government revenues, many countries are wrestling with the issue of road pricing. Ironically, as increases in traffic have outpaced road construction in the world's developing economies, we expect significant global growth in the road market over the next two decades. Developing economies often have preferences for toll roads for different reasons.
As the ownership of roads has become broader (states, construction companies and infrastructure funds all have significant portfolios), their sales have become more common, whether it is construction companies exiting due to construction having been completed and capital needing to be recycled, or financial constraints making disposals necessary. Whether the roads are toll roads, shadow toll roads or have availability based payment models, the key to efficient legal advice is a deep understanding of the market.  
Allen &amp;amp; Overy has considerable experience advising on toll roads, bridges, tunnels and ring roads. We advise sponsors, banks and governments and other parties involved in the sector on project financings (public-private partnerships/private finance initiatives), construction, mergers and acquisitions, funding (equity and debt) and litigation. 
We have experience of advising on numerous road projects globally including market-defining transactions in the UK, U.S., Europe and Central and Latin America.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>3c0d80fa-f68f-4c8e-bdd4-a7dc9e8a7bc2</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>dbb7d095-dede-44cf-871a-a0780e70e08d</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>343</Id>
    <UniqueId>f3328a70-2349-4fc7-91b0-887083e2df4a</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Satellites</PracticeName>
    <Text>Our international training and integrated know-how ensures the effective management of international advice for satellite projects. 
Specifically, we advise on: 
satellite financings and insurance arrangements
satellite construction and launch service contracts
transponder leases and commercial service agreements
corporate reorganisations, IPOs, acquisitions and disposals in the satellite industry
national and international regulation, including broadcast regulation
research and development projects, including those involving the European Space Agency
We also have a thorough understanding of the International Telecommunication Union (ITU) regulatory framework, and the Outer Space Treaties.
Recognition for our work
Allen &amp;amp; Overy has status as “the go-to firm for big-ticket corporations” with recent highlights including advising “on the competitive procurement of all aspects of the Yahsat satellite system”. Legal 500 EMEA 2010 (TMT:UAE)</Text>
    <TermStoreId>22326c0f-0516-41ec-8b1a-bfeb10c6ea06</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>492804b7-d6f0-4b03-b725-27e24de0908e</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>344</Id>
    <UniqueId>1a2487d9-aaea-4697-85bd-0958bf170ad4</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Shipping</PracticeName>
    <Text>Survival was the watchword, but now activity has begun to rise with growth fuelled by emerging markets.
Our international Shipping group holds a premier position in the market. Through its experience advising a wide-ranging client base, it brings a rounded approach to transactions. Comprising enterprising lawyers with a track record in shipping from areas such as project finance, asset finance and leasing, capital markets, restructuring, tax, and mergers and acquisitions, we offer clients in the shipping sector a complete legal service.
We are the preferred counsel for a broad range of clients including lenders, banks, lessors, lessees, export credit agencies and shipowners. The range of vessels on which we advise include FPSOs, LNG carriers, drillships, container vessels, chemical tankers, VLCCs and luxury cruise ships.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>38ca512d-7926-465b-9094-90bdba601382</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>dbb7d095-dede-44cf-871a-a0780e70e08d</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>345</Id>
    <UniqueId>a8e531de-f8bf-4681-879a-cc15fc8e37a0</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Social Infrastructure</PracticeName>
    <Text>Whether we are working on transactions in the West, the East, the developed world or the developing world, whether acting for governments or sponsors, it is absolutely clear that value for money is critical.  
Allen &amp;amp; Overy has a long history of advising on projects in the social infrastructure sector, particularly schools, universities, hospitals, social accommodation, prisons, stadia and sporting facilities. We are pioneers of the public-private partnerships/private finance initiatives market in these sectors in the UK and Europe and are at the forefront of rolling out this model in other jurisdictions.
We have received numerous awards for project finance transactions in the social infrastructure sector working on numerous 'market firsts'.
Our leading Social Infrastructure group's expertise extends to the acquisitions of social infrastructure assets and companies, privatisations, structuring and establishing funds to invest in social infrastructure, advising on partnership models, ownership arrangements and unit trusts, negotiating appropriate contractual provisions for required agreements (whether agreements with the government or supply chain members).</Text>
    <TermStoreId>cc6a7d76-500b-4dc4-892a-c6c8027d48c0</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>dbb7d095-dede-44cf-871a-a0780e70e08d</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>346</Id>
    <UniqueId>e642ea21-a5a6-4f3d-85ee-d09ff4577b61</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Stock Exchanges</PracticeName>
    <Text>We advise leading stock exchanges, clearing and settlement houses, related technology suppliers, and national and cross-border regulators on the full range of corporate, financing, regulatory, tax and other matters. 
We act for many of the major international exchanges, covering a wide range of trading activities, as well as advising investors in the sector and regulators on how best they can develop their financial markets. We have been involved in a significant number of the recent consolidation attempts among the larger exchanges, including through mergers and joint ventures into new business areas across borders.
The past few years have seen the most significant changes to the architecture of the credit derivatives market since its inception as a result of the deluge of regulations emanating from both sides of the Atlantic. We have been at the forefront of initiatives to reduce risk in the over-the-counter (OTC) derivatives space by facilitating further use of central counterparties (CCPs), client-clearing services developed by CCPs and CCP inter-operability, acting both for major market participants and CCPs. Our Global Clearing Group has advised both clearing houses and groups of leading credit derivatives dealers in Europe, the U.S. and Japan on rules for clearing OTC credit derivatives (CDS) and interest swaps. The breadth of our experience is demonstrated by the fact that we have advised either dealers or central counterparties on the rules for every clearing house currently offering CDS clearing.
In addition, we have established a Default Management Working Group to discuss the development of industry standards for managing the default of a clearing member. Allen &amp;amp; Overy has developed a position paper on behalf of the group and discussed this issue extensively with central clearing houses around the globe and across the full range of derivatives asset classes (including CME, LCH.Clearnet, ICE Trust, ICE Clear, Eurex, JSCC and SGX).</Text>
    <TermStoreId>3725b41f-1021-42be-a9b4-9254a3a524e4</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>1930da2e-adbd-451b-91f0-c56c8403829a</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>347</Id>
    <UniqueId>1953e750-8d41-44d0-95eb-62c251641629</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Technology</PracticeName>
    <Text>We also advise international corporate customers on a wide range of major technology projects and technology-related issues such as procurement, licensing and outsourcing. 
We offer a complete range of legal services tailored to the technology industry. This includes mergers and acquisitions, private equity, commercial contracts, outsourcing, licensing arrangements, hardware, software and services procurement, intellectual property, antitrust, finance, privacy and data protection, regulatory, dispute resolution, employment and tax.
We have an in-depth knowledge of the technology sector, built up over decades of closing deals for technology organisations and their customers.
Recognition for our work
“Multinational companies value the strength and scope of this group’s transactional abilities, which facilitate its skilled handling of large-scale cross-border deals.” Chambers Global 2011 (Technology and Communications: Global)</Text>
    <TermStoreId>a2128e72-7dc4-433d-b62d-7ecd09278310</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>492804b7-d6f0-4b03-b725-27e24de0908e</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>348</Id>
    <UniqueId>d00133c8-c455-44c3-8726-003e195d6ba8</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Telecommunications</PracticeName>
    <Text>Among our clients in the sector are some of the world’s largest telecoms companies, government bodies, regulators, industry participants, financial institutions and major corporations (suppliers and customers). We take time to listen to our clients in order to gain an understanding of their needs, aspirations and goals. 
One reason these companies choose Allen &amp;amp; Overy is the complete range of services on offer. As well as the firm’s renowned M&amp;amp;A and corporate finance practice, we advise telecommunications sector clients on banking, regulatory, intellectual property, antitrust, tax, employment, litigation, commercial contract and outsourcing matters. 
The team has a broad range of experience, acquired not only in private practice but also in-house at leading telecoms companies and on secondments to corporates and regulatory bodies. This mix of expertise, dedicated knowledge and hands-on commercial experience enables us to provide you with legal services of the highest quality.
Recognition for our work
” Multinational companies value the strength and scope of this group’s transactional abilities, which facilitate its skilled handling of large-scale cross-border deals. The firm’s regulatory expertise is also commended by telecoms clients, which include a variety of major names operating in Europe, Latin America and Africa.”  Chambers Global 2011 (Technology and Communications: Global)</Text>
    <TermStoreId>71bd8c06-bb68-41f5-97b2-335d52e70aad</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>492804b7-d6f0-4b03-b725-27e24de0908e</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>349</Id>
    <UniqueId>24ff0b8f-d58c-44a6-902e-c75e642d2289</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Telecommunications, Media and Technology</PracticeName>
    <Text>Supporting the TMT sector is a key priority for Allen &amp;amp; Overy and we have a dedicated TMT sector group which allows us to foster and share industry knowledge and expertise across our offices and legal disciplines. As many of our TMT clients operate across borders, we support them by being able to combine our talents and resources to provide solutions in almost any country, at any time.
Few firms can deliver the combination of experience and resource that is needed to handle the most important matters. Our team benefits from experience acquired not only in private practice but also in-house at leading TMT companies and on secondments to corporates and regulatory bodies. 
This means we provide relevant industry-focused advice, delivered quickly to ensure that we add value from day one. So, irrespective of the location, the size, or the complexity of the matter, you can be confident that we have the right team in the right place.
Recognition for our work
“Allen &amp;amp; Overy are forward-thinking and innovative, and really try to get under the skin of what we’re doing.” “We value their ability to coordinate the multinational aspects of a deal.” Client feedback in Chambers Global 2011 (Technology and Communications: Global)</Text>
    <TermStoreId>492804b7-d6f0-4b03-b725-27e24de0908e</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId />
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>350</Id>
    <UniqueId>20df0178-5b00-4956-ac90-7d26d590b8fc</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Traditional</PracticeName>
    <Text />
    <TermStoreId>5f451e41-5aa7-4560-91ff-726b7e07d708</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>7ef89c9b-6439-445a-862d-cf428893e2d3</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>351</Id>
    <UniqueId>7592193a-c408-40a5-9f91-ec9e0ac98a82</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Upstream</PracticeName>
    <Text />
    <TermStoreId>4b88f7da-881c-4b16-b635-88ed63e82ce0</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>7ef89c9b-6439-445a-862d-cf428893e2d3</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>352</Id>
    <UniqueId>2eac93e5-afc2-407c-ae4c-0713e3ed5416</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Vaccines</PracticeName>
    <Text>Our advice covers intellectual property, both contentious and non-contentious, mergers and acquisitions, commercial transactions (including licensing and collaborations), capital markets and finance and regulatory matters. 
Vaccination efforts have been met with some controversy since their inception, on ethical, political, medical safety, religious, and other grounds. Early success and compulsion brought widespread acceptance and mass vaccination campaigns were undertaken which are credited with greatly reducing the incidence of many diseases in numerous geographic regions. The eradication of smallpox, which was last seen in a natural case in 1977, is considered the most evident success of vaccination.
Our clients include Novartis Vaccines and GlaxoSmithKline.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>70fbcc15-7b60-4dea-baca-c26e3892c4b0</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>a219d2ec-2a80-4aa9-9ad8-b8ca824edca0</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>353</Id>
    <UniqueId>d8d315ff-8ee7-4613-a355-45dedf357440</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Water and Waste</PracticeName>
    <Text>The number and variety of deals that we are involved in and the breadth and depth of our client base, geographical coverage and expertise distinguish our practice from other firms in the market.
We have wide experience of acting for sponsors, banks and governments and utilities operators on mergers and acquisitions (both public and private), funding (equity and debt), litigation, competition and regulatory matters. 
As well as offering sound commercial advice, we recognise the ethical dimensions critical to the water sector and the need to promote sustainability at all levels. We regularly advise on the commercial implications of environmental legislation worldwide, as well as advising governments on the development of protection frameworks to preserve aquatic environs and mitigate anthropogenic impact. 
We also have specific experience relating to multi-faceted and highly specialised waste transactions. Our extensive waste management and power experience enables us to provide a unique depth of specialist knowledge in all relevant areas, including waste supply, construction, operations and maintenance and electricity (including interconnection and market trading strategies), as well as procurement, planning and environmental law and alternative financing structures.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>3993eb21-51f4-4a0a-a6fe-27686b885637</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>dbb7d095-dede-44cf-871a-a0780e70e08d</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>354</Id>
    <UniqueId>0f22ec54-3043-42c4-87c6-15230cb57ad1</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Political Law</PracticeName>
    <Text />
    <TermStoreId>82c43943-0e05-4056-825b-95ccc3befef9</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>e5f42143-a550-4fe5-84a5-6b5ada4229fb</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>355</Id>
    <UniqueId>591f6840-4a68-4eed-98df-5893dddbcd03</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Political Law</PracticeName>
    <Text />
    <TermStoreId>a350277d-d3fd-402d-a9bd-ef58797657eb</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>72cde3c8-471c-4823-bc1f-9acacb60631c</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>356</Id>
    <UniqueId>496790f4-d379-45a2-a530-94e2c864677e</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Compliance and Counselling</PracticeName>
    <Text />
    <TermStoreId>796667e6-7b78-423d-aae6-57b5feb01f70</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>97290c58-1db1-45aa-89a2-48d7d0f765a0</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>357</Id>
    <UniqueId>81f490ec-dd22-40c6-9368-3929270a336c</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Antitrust Disputes</PracticeName>
    <Text />
    <TermStoreId>a922d025-18ec-405d-802c-fe4deb4bb85e</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>97290c58-1db1-45aa-89a2-48d7d0f765a0</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>358</Id>
    <UniqueId>030caf38-89be-4134-8565-9a8186b2e4ad</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Sector regulation, monopolisation and market investigations</PracticeName>
    <Text />
    <TermStoreId>402f34c6-e872-4047-bf65-1dba01c98ae0</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>97290c58-1db1-45aa-89a2-48d7d0f765a0</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>359</Id>
    <UniqueId>c0943a97-d8d3-4164-8260-09414e1401f8</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Public Procurement and Competitive Tendering</PracticeName>
    <Text />
    <TermStoreId>c897ccfe-23dc-47f5-974a-26a4e5654017</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>e5f42143-a550-4fe5-84a5-6b5ada4229fb</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>360</Id>
    <UniqueId>0ac821bc-216e-49e8-be68-98be8935acf5</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Trade, Commodities and Export Finance</PracticeName>
    <Text />
    <TermStoreId>2816ac72-f4bc-4569-b9fd-1b1783a38a70</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>7891e92d-9a8b-4dfa-8b4f-f45d51f09808</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>361</Id>
    <UniqueId>9bbf8311-8c37-4890-be44-093328270897</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Antitrust and Intellectual Property</PracticeName>
    <Text />
    <TermStoreId>06ac78cb-d37c-46a7-b869-a3582943e78e</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>97290c58-1db1-45aa-89a2-48d7d0f765a0</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>362</Id>
    <UniqueId>b3e3c53e-5679-4c86-bd41-b90be3361704</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>UK Corporate Governance</PracticeName>
    <Text />
    <TermStoreId>ac0b494b-cfaf-4cb9-b2b9-528b929588e6</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId />
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>363</Id>
    <UniqueId>04e34aa5-1002-4fe3-8d5f-6267a3547047</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Business Ethics and Human Rights</PracticeName>
    <Text>Investors, shareholders and customers are increasingly interested in how businesses conduct their operations over and above complying with law. This is being seen in areas such as human rights, which, in addition to more established areas such as environment and health and safety compliance, also require you to focus on supply chain issues, employment practices, usage policies, third party sourcing and wider business practices. This is being coupled with initiatives (and legal obligations) for greater transparency in areas such as material sources (e.g. conflict minerals) and payments to Governments and regulators. As a result, how you operate your business and the business practice standards you apply are becoming as important as ensuring basic legal compliance.
Our Group has strong expertise in the legal and practical aspects of this emerging area and can advise on the full range of issues including:
human rights and ethics diligence 
compliance with international human rights standards
development of corporate policies and procedures
litigation arising from alleged infringements of human rights
regulatory investigations in to business practices
supply chain diligence, certifications and disclosure requirements
managing business ethics risks in M&amp;amp;A transactions
Equator Principles and IFC Standards
risk analysis for business transactions and mitigants
disclosure obligations (e.g. conflict minerals)</Text>
    <TermStoreId>b70e80e6-2f2d-42d6-88a5-6cdb5e3213b1</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>afb18bd5-bdd7-4cc3-a69b-bcb6997b5a6c</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>364</Id>
    <UniqueId>df574074-1993-41c9-86c3-2589959e5063</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Crisis Management</PracticeName>
    <Text>Growing environmental, health and safety standards combined with intense media scrutiny and stakeholder concerns mean that you need to clearly identify major risks which may affect the business and plan for all eventualities.. Our integrated practice of regulatory experts and litigators is ideally suited to advise on developing, planning and implementing a crisis strategy. We advise on integrity testing plans, provide practical guidance on managing relationships with regulators and resolve disputes with as little disruption to our clients’ business.
In particular, we can advise on:
developing a management and organisational structure to respond to an incident or crisis
existing emergency response procedures
the preparation of key documents to manage the role of parties such as contractors or JV partners 
selecting, appointing and managing other external advisors such as PR or media consultants
training staff on crisis procedures
managing the relationship with regulators in the event of a crisis
bringing the business back into compliance
civil and criminal proceedings which follow an incident</Text>
    <TermStoreId>191415e1-a740-46b2-a16c-a29a776bbb24</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>afb18bd5-bdd7-4cc3-a69b-bcb6997b5a6c</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>365</Id>
    <UniqueId>9ac72f2a-70df-4e4f-9624-1ec7218f0f9f</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Export Controls</PracticeName>
    <Text>The Global Environmental and Regulatory Law Group has extensive experience in advising clients on the potential implications of these restrictions as well as on import and export requirements. 
We have particular experience in:
advising on the impact of EU, UK and U.S. trade sanctions
developing trade compliance policies and procedures
advising on dual-use restrictions
analysing and mitigating trade related risks in M&amp;amp;A transactions
undertaking voluntary investigations in compliance with trade restrictions
advising on contractual arrangements in relation to sanctions and export controls
carrying out due diligence in the supply chain
supporting applications for licences/exemptions</Text>
    <TermStoreId>d8675a29-bd3e-4028-9203-3f479b33b180</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>afb18bd5-bdd7-4cc3-a69b-bcb6997b5a6c</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>366</Id>
    <UniqueId>44dde370-799b-4dc5-8b59-8e8a01700870</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Product Liability</PracticeName>
    <Text>Wherever you are in the supply chain you may find yourself embroiled in regulatory investigations and customer litigation as a result of a product that you have manufactured, supplied or distributed. Managing these issues requires a broad international, legal and commercial approach with a strong focus on fast responses and practical solutions.
Our cross-disciplinary, global Product Liability group provides strategic advice and commercial assistance to all businesses in the supply chain, from designers to end users. We advise on these issues across a wide range of sectors covering products such as medical devices, tobacco, industrial equipment, food contact materials, electronic equipment and other consumer and business products.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>190ffdf0-e534-43c4-8dac-c2a43af9956e</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>afb18bd5-bdd7-4cc3-a69b-bcb6997b5a6c</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>367</Id>
    <UniqueId>fb6c4507-f2e0-4972-9206-0a14785c376b</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Shale Gas Projects</PracticeName>
    <Text>However, shale gas exploration is not without controversy. Our team of EHS regulatory lawyers, have specific and practical expertise in advising on the developing regulatory frameworks governing shale gas across Europe. We advise on issues such as the:
strategic planning and management of projects
requirements for EHS permits including mining waste permits, environmental permits and greenhouse gas permits
planning aspects of a project
need for environmental impact assessment (and its scope)
negotiating with regulatory authorities
management of NGO and security risks (including the potential for Judicial Reviews (in the English courts))
pre-application stage of a project
obtaining relevant permits and licences 
mitigating commercial risks arising from shale developments</Text>
    <TermStoreId>88340d58-5fc3-435e-9fa4-e36eaa8f6738</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>afb18bd5-bdd7-4cc3-a69b-bcb6997b5a6c</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
  <Practice>
    <Id>368</Id>
    <UniqueId>40dd2199-f854-4c69-b1a5-11160cb97095</UniqueId>
    <PracticeName>Strategic Oil Stock Holding Obligations</PracticeName>
    <Text>We have expertise in national oil stocks management, the creation of public entities designed to hold stock and the CSO including ticketing arrangements designed to provide obligated parties with stock availability. Our lawyers also have experience in advising governments on their stock holding compliance strategies.</Text>
    <TermStoreId>54ad4e3e-fdb2-4731-b29e-00f46dd2938c</TermStoreId>
    <ParentTermStoreId>afb18bd5-bdd7-4cc3-a69b-bcb6997b5a6c</ParentTermStoreId>
  </Practice>
</ArrayOfPractice>